Alright, awesome. You've just completed Lesson Seven, the heart had fun me.
非常好，你已经完成了 "Lesson 7: Hardhat Fund Me"
And now it's time to move on to lesson eight,
现在是时候移步到 Lesson 8 了
which is going to be our HTML slash JavaScript to fund me,
标题是 "HTML/JavaScript Fund Me"
you can find all the code for what we're about to go through, of course, on my GitHub repo.
你可以在我的 GitHub 仓库中找到所有代码
And for this section, we're now going to start to see some of the differences between Node js between that back end JavaScript,
在这一节中，我们会看到 Node.js 和后端 JavaScript
and JavaScript in the browser or front end JavaScript.
以及浏览器中的 JavaScript 或者说前端 JavaScript 之间的区别
And if you come to the GitHub repo associated with this lesson,
如果你来到与这节课关联的 GitHub 仓库
our main version we'll be using what's considered better front end JavaScript.
我们 main 版本使用的是通常被认为更好的 JavaScript 前端版本
But we'll also have a no JS addition, as well,
但我们同样会提供一个 Node.js 版本
if some of the front end JavaScript is really confusing,
如果某些 JavaScript 前端确实令人困惑的话
and you'll see what I mean with some of those differences very soon.
很快你就会看到我所说的区别是什么意思
Now, people can programmatically interact with our smart contracts at any time.
现在，人们可以随时通过编程的方式与智能合约进行交互
However, most of our users are not compete developers.
然而，大多数用户并不完全是开发者
So we need to create a website,
所以我们需要创建一个网站
we need to create a user interface
创建一个用户界面(User Interface)
for them to interact with our smart contracts and interact with our protocols.
让他们能使用我们的协议与我们的智能合约进行交互
And that's what this section is going to teach us,
这就是本节课要教授的内容
it's going to be an introduction to building these fullstack.
即构建全栈应用的介绍
building these front ends on top of our smart contracts.
在我们的智能合约之上构建这些前端应用
Now, I wanted to show you what this is actually going to look like when we finish it.
现在我要给你展示的是实际完成后的效果是什么样的
Because here, we're actually going to make our first front end our first website using the blockchain using web three.
我们要做的是使用区块链和 Web3 来创建我们的首个前端，首个网站
And it's going to be an incredibly minimalistic website.
这会是一个非常简约的网站
As you can see right here,
正如你现在所看到的
we're not going to have any styling,
我们不会做任何风格化处理
we're just going to show you how to get the functionality.
只向你展示如何获取这些功能
And additionally, we're going to do a couple of things that aren't really recommended and are definitely not best practices.
此外，我们要做几件既不推荐也非最优的事
The reason we're going to do it like this is the same reason that in math class,
我们之所以这么做，原因就和在数学课上一样
before you learn the tricks for derivatives,
在你学习关于求导数的各种技巧之前
you learn what a derivative actually is.
你得先了解导数是什么
We're teaching it like this first,
我们先这样教你
so that you can understand
这样你就能理解
what's going on on the websites when you interact with them. And when you work with them.
当你与网站进行交互和工作的时候它发生了些什么
We saw already with Foston, touching the link
我们之前来看过 "faucets.chain.link"
where we can connect our wallets and we can work with the faucets.
我们可以在这里连接到我们的钱包并使用水龙头
All decentralized applications have this website and have this setup where you connect your wallet
所有的去中心化应用都会有这样的网站和设置供你连接钱包
and then you interact by clicking buttons,
接着你可以通过这些按钮进行交互
which make these function calls to the blockchain.
以在区块链上调用这些函数
And here's going to be our minimalistic website that
does exactly that. So this section is just going to teach
you what's going on under the hood. So you can really
understand how to build these applications at a professional
level. So for this section, if you don't want to code along
with me, you definitely don't have to however, coding along
with me will definitely ingrain everything in your memory here.
So here's what an application is going to look like. We have our
website here, which is connected to our hard hat, our local
blockchain, but it's gonna run exactly the same as if it was on
a real test net, the first thing you'll notice is in our meta
mask, we are not connected. And we'll go ahead and hit Connect,
and meta masks will pop up asking us if we want to connect,
we'll go ahead and connect to it. And now we'll be able to
interact with our heart at Funmi. You'll notice two buttons
here are functions that we're familiar with, we have our
withdrawal function, which is going to be our withdrawal
function that we just created. And then of course, we also have
our fund function here where we push or we send Aetherium or
Matic or whatever, native blockchain token to our smart
contract. So we can do it through this user interface. So
once we're connected, if we want to see the balance, we can
actually right click, hit Inspect, come over to our
console. And we'll print out to the JavaScript console, the
current balance of our smart contract. So nobody has funded
this yet, we can come down, we can choose an amount we want to
fund. So for example, maybe 0.1, eath, we'll go ahead, we'll hit
fund, meta masks will pop up, we'll get a little council
saying funding with 0.1. And it'll give us all the
transaction details that we need to send 0.1 eath, to our smart
contract, we can go ahead and hit Confirm. And after it's been
confirmed after it's been mined on our local blockchain, we had
get balance, we now see that it's 0.1. We could call fund
again, we could have multiple funders, we could switch between
different accounts and fund with different amounts. And we can
see that funding amount increase, then we can call the
withdrawal function. As long as we're the owner, we can confirm
and we can pull out all the money out of our funding
contract. And we'll get balance. Now we'll see the balance is
reset to zero. So this is what we're going to be building. Are
you ready? I sure am.
Let's get into it. This is the introduction to building
websites with web three. All the information here is available in
our GitHub repo, so feel free to follow along there. Alright, so
if you're in your heart head Funmi dash Free Code Camp repo,
we're still going to want to have this open as well. But
we're also going to want to create a new Visual Studio code
for working with our new repo. So let's go ahead and CD down a
directory. We'll type MK dir, we'll call this HTML, Fund Me
Free Code Camp. We'll cd into that. And we'll open this up by
typing code period. You can also do File Open Folder, but we just
want to open this up in a new Visual Studio Code. New VS code
will pop up but before we flip over to that, we do want to CD
down CD back into hard hat fun we Free Code Camp because we are
still going to use everything in here. We're still going to
deploy In a smart contract using this folder and using this repo,
when you're building daps, or websites that are connected to
the blockchain, you'll usually have two repositories or repos.
One is going to be for the smart contracts, like what we see
here. This is our repo that has all the code for our smart
contracts. And then you'll also have one for the front end slash
website. And it's going to be the combination of these two
repos, which makes up the full stack. So when people are
talking about full stack, they're talking about the smart
contracts, which is going to be our back end, plus, plus our
HTML slash JavaScript slash website stuff, which is going to
be our front end. So smart contracts are the back end, HTML
slash JavaScript slash website stuff is going to be our front
end. So we have our back end already. And now we're going to
build our front end, we want to keep this up because we're going
to need it to test and interact with our front end. Awesome. So
we have this new folder now, HTML Funmi, Free Code Camp. Now
this course is not a how to learn front end course, we are
going to teach you a number of front end concepts. But if you
want to learn a full traditional front end course, once again,
you can check out Free Code Camp, they've got a ton of
fantastic tutorials, I'm teaching you front end, if you
go ahead and follow along with me, though, you'll definitely
get a basic understanding of front end as well as front ends
and how it relates to our smart contracts. Additionally, you
don't have to do the front end parts or the full stack parts.
If you only want to take this course, to learn back end and to
learn JavaScript, and to learn solidity and learn how to do
these smart contracts programmatically, then you can
absolutely skip these front end parts. However, if you want to
learn to build exciting websites, and you want to have
other people other than developers interact with your
protocols, you definitely want to watch this part. Now before
we actually jump in here and start writing our code. We need
to understand what exactly is going on when work with one of
these websites that use the blockchain. So I actually made a
video about this recently. So let's watch a segment from that
really quick, just so that we can get up to speed with with
exactly what's going on behind the scenes of these websites
that interact with the blockchain.