All right. So here we are, with a website or a front end
on top of some smart contracts that we've deployed,
doesn't really matter what it is
right now. This is typically the interface that you'll see boiled
down to a really, really minimalistic level. Typically,
you'll see something like connect function, right, and
Metamask, or some other wallet connector thing will pop up,
we'll hit Next we'll connect here might even say something
like connected. And we can also execute functions, we can
interact with our smart contracts, we can confirm, etc.
Right? This is something you might see something like Avi
right, I'll hit Connect on the application, it'll say, hey, how
would you like to connect? I'll choose Metamask. I'm going to
change my Metamask to main net, but you get the picture, right?
This is a simple example of what that would look like. So what is
actually going on in the browser when we connect what is actually
going on? And what do we actually need to do, we're going
to right click, hit Inspect. And on the right side, we're gonna
see our debugger here. Now if we go over to sources, on the top
of our browser, you'll see a few things. If you look down over
here, right, we'll see this URL, right, which right now is going
to be my localhost. And we'll also see meta mask and Phantom
and a whole bunch of other stuff. These other things that
we see here are going to be what's injected from our browser
extensions. The reason we see this meta mask thing here is
because I've meta mask installed, right? The reason I
see Phantom here is because I have the Phantom app installed.
Meta masks, of course, being an EVM, wallet and Phantom being a
Solana based wallet. Now what happens when we have these
extensions installed is they automatically get injected into
a window object in JavaScript, and in fact, we scroll down
to here in the console, again, you can find console, you can
click here and click anything up there. And we type in window.
We'll see we have this big window object with all this
stuff, right? This window object represents this our window
basically right? Now if we scroll all the way to the bottom
and we do window dot Aetherium. We also see an object here. Now
this window dot Aetherium object only exists if you have a meta
mask or meta mask like browser or if you want to look at some
other web three wallet you do window dot Solana. So Alana
right and we see this window dot Solana. Now let's look at a
browser that doesn't have Metamask or phantom installed.
What do you think is going to happen in the window now let's
go ahead and right click hit Inspect. We'll go to the
console. Now let's see what's going on in here. If we go to
sources, we first off we don't see that Metamask or that Solana
source here. And if we go to console, we still see window if
I let me zoom in a little bit. We still see window here. But if
I do window dot Aetherium If we get nothing, or if I do window
dot Solana, we also get nothing. So in order for our browsers to
know that there's a Metamask, or that there's a phantom, those
extensions automatically add these to our window objects, and
that's something that we can check for in our JavaScript. The
reason these wallets are so important is built into them
underneath the hood, they have a blockchain node connected to
them. And in order to interact with the blockchain, we always
need a note. And you might have seen URLs from alchemy, or in
FIRA because you need them to interact with the blockchain,
Alchemy, and infura are examples of third party blockchains that
you can interact with and basically rent, right. But you
need them to create a provider, or a node to send your
transactions to. So you could do it in JavaScript, like something
like this is the alchemy documentation where you take
that alchemy URL, you stick it into some object and use that to
send your transaction. This is a way that you could do it in the
back end. But on the front end, what you normally want to use is
you just want to use the user's Metamask, or their Solana or
their wallet as the main wallet. Now, there are a ton of other
different types of wallets to connect, like ledger, mu,
Coinbase, wallet, connect, etc. And there are different ways to
set those up. But they all do the same thing where they expose
some URL, they expose some node under the hood, they give us
that URL. They give us that provider. The way metamath Does
it is with window dot Aetherium. Boom, this is now our URL. This
is now our connection. In fact, if you go up to your Metamask,
hit the little three dots, expand view. hit Add Network,
and then just hit the X so we can get to networks. You can see
all of these blockchains that I have in here all have an RPC
URL, this the HTTP RPC URL connection of the blockchain No,
that's running. I happen to have one running locally right now.
All of these also have a node RPC URL and you can actually see
them right in your meta mask right. This is connected to in
Fira, these are all connected to in Fira. It's all the exact same
thing. Meta mask just has a really nice way of taking that
URL, sticking it in the browser for us in this window dot
Aetherium or window dot Solana you know or whatever. So this is
the main thing that we need to know we need. We always need a
connection with the blockchain. And these browser wallets are an
easy way to do that. Make sense? Great. Let's take this knowledge
now. And let's
apply it.