So in here, let's make a quick readme.md.
现在，让我们来快速创建一个 "README.md" 文件
Just so we can talk about what we're going to be making here.
这样我们就可以讨论一下接下来我们要处理的内容
So in this section, we're gonna be using raw HTML slash JavaScript
在这一节中，我们将先使用原始的 "HTML / JavaScript"
in conjunction with our smart contracts to build this website.
结合我们的智能合约来构建这个网站
Later on. We will use next Jas slash react,
接下来，我们要使用一种更加现代化的技术栈
which is a more modern stack to build our websites here.
"Nextjs / Reactjs" 来构建我们的网站
But learning understanding how to do everything with HTML and JavaScript first,
但首先来学习和理解如何使用 HTML 和 JavaScript 来完成所有的操作
is going to make our lives a lot easier come later on down the road.
会让我们之后的学习工作变得更轻松一些
But as we know, all websites use HTML as kind of their scaffolding for what they look like.
但正如我们所知的，所有网站都使用 HTML 作为它们的骨架来支撑外观
So let's go ahead and create our HTML for our website,
所以让我们继续，来为我们的网站创建一个 HTML 文件
we'll call it index dot HTML.
我们把它命名为 "index.html"
And this is going to be the basic scaffolding or the
basic bones of what our website is going to look like. Now, in
VS code, if you go ahead and just type exclamation mark index
dot HTML, and you click the first thing that pops up, it'll
automatically populate your code your file here with some basic
HTML setup. If it doesn't do this for you, feel free to copy
paste the basic setup from the GitHub repository associated
with this course, we have our doctype. HTML, we have some HTML
tags telling us that everything in between here is going to be
an HTML, which is great. However, for simplicity, we
don't need most of this. So we're going to make this a
little bit easier. We're going to delete this line, this line
and this line. And we're just going to change the title to
fund me app. And then inside of our body, we can do something
like or Hello. And now we have the bare bones to create a
website just with this. Now to show this on a website, we can
do one of two things. If you are using Visual Studio code, I'm
going to recommend you install the extension live server. And
it looks like this. And I'll have the extension ID for this
extension in the GitHub repository associated with this
course, this is going to allow us to easily spin up an HTML
website. So we'll go ahead and install this. And if you're not
using Visual Studio Code, I'll show you a different way in just
a second. Once this is installed, you should have this
little go live button at the bottom. And if you don't, you
can always open up your command palette, which again, you can
open up by hitting View command palette, and you can type in
live server and just say open with live server but we're going
to just click this go live button. And it's going to say
starting and it's actually going to open up your browser with our
index dot HTML. We can actually see our website is being called
Save on 120 7.0 point 0.1. This is known as the loopback, or
local host endpoint, we're on port 5501. If you're not
familiar with the ports, don't worry about that for now, we
have our index dot HTML here. And if we change this to
something like what's good, we hit save. If it doesn't
automatically refresh, we'd come over here and refresh. And we'd
see that being reflected here. If you've never created a
website before, you've essentially just done it,
congratulations, you might get this.vs code folder. a.vs code
folder allows you to make settings specifically for the
repo that you're working with, for your code editor for VS
code, but we're going to mostly ignore it for now. Now, if
you're not using Visual Studio Code, what you can do is you can
just run this in the browser. So one thing you could do is you
could right click it, and I'm using a Mac. So I'm going to hit
Reveal in Finder, aka reveal where it's located. And you can
just double click it, and boom, now it's running right in your
browser. Instead of pointing to your localhost, it's going to be
pointing directly to your local file path. Now one final version
that we could do that I'm going to highly recommend you don't
do. But it's another option, we're actually going to download
a package for you using no Jas, which allows us to serve up
HTTP. And we're gonna install it the exact same way we've
installed our other packages, we can do yarn, add dash dash dev
HTTP hyphen server. And you may still want to add it anyways.
But now, we'll get some node modules for this HTTP server
package, we'll get a package json, and of course, a yarn dot
lock as well. And what we can do is we can stop this down here,
stop that live server. And if we go back to our website, refresh,
it'll now be blank. And we can run yarn HTTP server. And this
will do the exact same thing. And we get, and if we come over,
and we refresh, we'll see what's good. Now this one is a little
bit more finicky. And after you make a change, like, Hey, what's
good, you might have to close it, and then reopen it and then
refresh. So I do recommend that if you're on Visual Studio code,
you definitely just use this little go live button, because
it'll reflect your changes a lot nicer.
So let's go ahead and hit the Go Live button. Hey, what's good
pops up. Okay, cool. Our HTML is working perfectly.