So the title, of course, is going to be the Funmi app,
标题当然就是 "Fund Me App"
which we see up here in the title section.
我们可以在这里的标题部分看到它
So let's update this HTML, so that it has those buttons,
让我们来更新一下这个 HTML，让它拥有那些按钮
and it can actually connect and work with our blockchain and work with any blockchain.
这样它才能连接和使用我们的区块链以及任何区块链
Something else that you can do in HTML is you can actually write JavaScript inside your HTML.
其实你可以直接在 HTML 里面写 JavaScript
And the way we can do that is by doing this script tag,
要想做到这一点，需要执行 ``
and then we'll do a closing script tag.
接着要闭合它 ``
And anything inside here inside of our script tags is going to be JavaScript.
在 "" 标签内部的所有内容都是 JavaScript
So I could do something like
所以我们可以这样做
console dot log, hi, with a bunch of exclamation marks, I'm going to save it.
`console.log("Hi!!")，写一些感叹号，接着保存它
We'll go back to our front end, we're going to right click, we'll hit Inspect,
我们回到前端，点击右键，选择“检查”("Inspect")
we'll go to the console. And we can see that Hi prints it out,
前往“控制台”("Console")，接着我们可以看到 "Hi" 被打印了出来
we refresh, we can see the hi consistently printed out
当我们刷新页面时，就可以看到 "Hi" 被持续打印出来
hi from script tag, we'll save it,
"Hi from script tag!"，保存一下
we'll move back, we see hi from script tag printed out.
回到前端，我们看到 "Hi from script tag!" 被打印了出来
I know it's a little bit small. So let me zoom in. Alright, great.
这里有点小，我来放大一下，很好
So we can type our JavaScript in here,
所以，我们可以在这里输入 JavaScript 代码
it's inside the script tag is where we're going to write our JavaScript to write the functions that
在 "" 标签内部编写 JavaScript 函数
our front end is going to interact with.
用它们来与前端进行交互
Now, as we saw before, in this little console, we can check for window dot Etherium,
就像我们之前见到过的，在这个小控制台中，我们可以使用 "window.ethereum" 进行检查
to see if Metamask or is installed.
来查看是否安装了 MetaMask
And again, a lot of what we're working with is actually right in the Metamask documentation.
再次重申，我们使用到的很多东西其实都在 MetaMask 的文档里有
If you go to their basic section,
如果你前往他们的基础部分
they talk a little bit about the provider,
他们会谈论一些关于 "Provider" 的内容
which is this window dot Aetherium,
正是这个 "window.ethereum"
you can read how to actually interact directly with meta mask in the meta mask documentation as well.
你也可以在 MetaMask 的文档中读到直接与 MetaMask 进行交互的方法
Now using window dot Aetherium is just one of the ways we're actually going to connect to the blockchain,
使用 "window.ethereum" 只是我们连接区块链的方式之一
there's actually multiple ways
实际上还有很多其它方式
because there's multiple different kinds of wallets out there.
因为还有很多其它种类的钱包存在
But for now, we're just going to pretend that window dot Aetherium and meta mask is the only extension out there.
但现在，我们只假设 "window.ethereum" 和 MetaMask 是唯一的扩展
So
what we want to do is we want to check to see if this wind of
that Aetherium exists. This is the first thing that we should
be doing. Because if this doesn't exist, this means that
they can't connect to the blockchain, one of the first
things that we're going to want to do is we're going to want to
check to see if that exists. So we can do something like if we
can say type of window that Aetherium does not equal,
undefined. Then we'll do console dot log, I see a meta mask. So
now if we save, we come back to our front end, we do see I see a
Metamask. I've got a Google Chrome up without Metamask that
if we look in the console, and we hit refresh it the same URL
where our live server is running. We don't see that I see
a meta mask because it doesn't see a meta mask. We can do else.
console dot log, no Metamask refresh, we still see ICD a meta
mask where we have a meta mask. You don't have to open up a
browser without one but we see no meta mask for Chrome because
it doesn't see a meta mask. Now what we could do is We can
automatically try to connect to meta mask if we see that there
is a meta mask, right? Remember how before, when we hit that
connect button meta mask popped up and said, Are you sure you
want to connect? So what we can do is, and you can, again, you
can find this in the meta mask docs, we can run this eath
request accounts method, which is basically going to be how we
connect our Metamask. Now, this is specified by a new EIP and an
older documentations. And in older tutorials, you might see
Aetherium dot enable, which essentially does the exact same
thing. So what we could do here is we could say, a cerium, or
excuse me, window dot Aetherium dot request. And we could put
method F request accounts. And we'll save that. Now if we go
back to our browser, we'll actually see, you'll actually
see Metamask, go ahead and pop up and say, let's connect so we
can choose an account. And we'll hit Connect, will automatically
connect our meta mask to our website. And now if we look at
our meta mask, we can see this little connected thing. It's
saying that our account one is now connected to our website.
This means that the website can now make API calls to our meta
mask, we still have to be the ones to approve them. But it can
go ahead and connect and try to run transactions, which is
awesome, which is what we want. If you want to disconnect, we
can go ahead and click that little button and hit disconnect
this account. Well that we have our code currently is anytime we
hit refresh, this is going to pop up which is going to be
really annoying. So what we're going to do instead is we're
going to wrap this up into an asynchronous function, the exact
same as we've been doing, we'll do we'll create an async
function called Connect. And we'll wrap it up these curly
braces here. And then we'll just format this a little bit to make
it look nicer. And now if we save, we go back to our website,
and we refresh. And we go ahead and disconnect.
If we refresh Metamask won't keep asking us Hey, do you want
to connect Hey, do you want to connect here do you want to
connect, because we need to call this connect function where we
can do that is we can add a little button here. So right
underneath our script tag, we're going to add a button tag. So
this is the opening button tag. And then here's the closing
button tag. And inside the opening button tag declaration,
we'll give it an ID, which will be Connect button. And we'll say
on click equals the Connect connects function. And we'll
call this button connect in between these little button
tags, we'll call it connect will say when we click it will call
the Connect function. So if we save, and we go back to our
front end, we can now see we have a little Connect button.
And now if we press Connect, Metamask is going to pop up,
we'll hit next and connect like that. And boom, now we are
connected. And we can even do a little await here so that we
wait for this to finish before moving on. And then after we
connect, we can say console dot log connected. So let's actually
go ahead and test this out, we'll go back to Metamask. we'll
disconnect here, try to never be on Main net if we don't have to
be. And let's go ahead run connect, we'll hit Next connect.
And now we see a little console dot log come out saying
connected. Okay, great. We can also update our website
accordingly. So that we can let users know that we're connected.
So we can grab the connect button element ID and say that
we're connected once we're connected. So after we await to
be connected, we can go ahead and do document dot get element
by ID Connect button. And then we'll say dot inner HTML equals
connected like that. And then instead of saying no minimize
down here, we'll do just the opposite. So we'll copy this
line. And instead of connected, we'll say please install meta
mask. And we'll save we'll go back to our front end, we'll hit
connect. And now if we're already connected, it'll just
automatically go to connected. If we're not connected, it'll
pop up, we'll get connected. And now we have this button that
says connected, which is great. So now we already know that
we're connected. So we've connected our Metamask to our
front end. Now we want to actually go ahead and do some
functions here. And this is where we want to create some
more functions and some more buttons that are going to use
ethers that package that we become so familiar with. Now, as
we code, our script section is going to get bigger and bigger
and bigger. So oftentimes, we actually want to put our code in
a JavaScript file itself. So we're gonna go ahead, come over
here, we're going to create a new file, and we'll call it
index dot j s. And instead of putting our JavaScript in these
script tags, we're going to put it in this index and then import
this index file into our HTML. And the way that we're going to
do that is we're actually just going to grab this function.
We're going to copy it, delete everything for now. We're going
to paste it into our end ext dot j s, and then in our index dot
HTML, we're just going to tell our script tag to use index.js.
So we're just going to say the source is going to be equal to
dot slash index dot j s. And then we're going to say, the
type of this is going to be text slash JavaScript. Now if we save
that, and we save our index dot HTML, we come back to our front
end, we do a little refresh. And we make sure that we go ahead
and disconnect. And we do another refresh, we can see that
even with our index.js in a different file, because we're
doing src equals index.js, and we're importing it into our
HTML, when we hit Connect, it still calls our Connect
function. That's how we can kind of separate our JavaScript into
its own js file that we're a little bit more familiar with.
Now, if you look in the GitHub repo associated with this
course, and you look in the index dot j s, you'll see our
Connect function, we've added some quality of life stuff,
we've added some try catches just to make handling errors a
little bit better, you can go ahead and add those try catches
in yourself if you'd like. But I'm not going to demo them in
this video here.