Now we want to create our fun function.
现在我们要创建我们的 "fund" 函数
And then later on, we're going to create our withdrawal function.
稍后我们还要创建我们的 "withdraw" 函数
And this is where front end JavaScript code. And no Gs are a little bit different.
这里的是前端 JavaScript 代码，它和 Node.js 有一些小的不同
In no JS, we've been using this require keyword to import dependencies
在 Node.js 中，我们一直用的是 `require` 关键字来导入依赖库
in front end JavaScript,  you can't use require, and it won't exactly work.
而在前端 JavaScript 中，就不能使用 `require` 了，它是完全不工作的
Now later on, we're going to use the Import keyword,
现在，我们要使用 `import` 关键字
which is really the better way to do this.
它其实是处理这些操作更好的方式
And this is where our first differences going to be
这就是我们所遇到的第一处不同
using the Import keyword for front end is much better than the require keyword,
在前端中使用 `import` 关键字要比使用 `require` 关键字好一些
especially since the require keyword doesn't actually work.
尤其是 `require` 关键字其实并不能使用
And for those you who might struggle with this disconnect in this change.
你们中的有些对此感到困惑人可能会对这种变化产生一些撕裂感
Once again, in the GitHub repo associated with this,
所以再次强调，在与课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中
we do have a Node js edition of this,
我们还提供了 Node.js 版本的代码
where you can use the require keyword,
你可以在这里使用 `require` 关键字
you just have to go through the readme and download some packages and run some scripts
你只需要阅读一下 "README"，并下载一些包，然后运行一些脚本
that basically transform your code that uses require into code that works with imports.
这些脚本基本上就是将使用 `require` 的代码给转换为使用 `import`
But we're going to teach you the way to work with your front end code here using imports.
但我们的教学方式是直接在前端代码中使用 `import`
Now you'll see when we get to next Jas
现在你会看到，当我们进入到下一个 JS 脚本时
that we will still download code from node modules
我们仍然会从 "node_modules" 中下载代码
and using a yarn lock and a package json etc.
并且仍然会使用 "yarn.lock" 和 "package.json" 等文件
So summary in future seconds, we are still going to do yarn add.
所以归根结底，我们接下来仍然会继续使用 `yarn add`
But outside of a framework
但在这个框架之外，
when we're using this raw JavaScript, this raw HTML setup, like what we're working with here,
当我们使用原始的 JavaScript 和原始的 HTML 设置，就和我们此处的使用方式一样时
we're not going to be doing yarn, add node modules
我们就不能使用 `yarn add node_modules` 了
will add node modules for framework like next react.
所以接下来我们仍然会在这个框架内继续使用 "node_modules"
But for raw JavaScript, we'll be using a different syntax,
但在原始的 JavaScript 中，我们会使用不同的语法
which I'll show you soon.
我马上就会展示这一点
So let's go ahead and start building our fund function here.
让我们继续，开始在这里构建我们的 "fund" 函数吧
To make our fun functions, what would we normally do?
为了构建我们的 "fund" 函数，我们通常是怎么做的呢？
Well, we'd create an async function called fund.
我们要创建一个 `async function` 名为 `fund()`
And in this function, we probably would want to take some ether mount as a parameter,
在这个函数中，我们大概想让它接收一些 "ethAmount" 作为参数
because we're going to want to fund it with some amount of Aetherium.
因为我们要用一定数额的以太币来进行资助
When we call this function, we might want to run console dot log
当我们调用这个函数时，我们可能想要运行 `console.log(``)`
will do a little string interpolation here.
我们要在这里做一个字符串插值
Funding with eth amount, dot dot dot,
`Funding with $...`
these semicolons are going to drive me absolutely insane.
这些分号绝对会让我疯掉
So I'm going to add a our dot prettier dot our rc file into this,
所以我要在这里添加一个 ".prettierrc" 文件
and I'm going to go ahead and add prettier in here. Otherwise, I'm going to lose my mind.
我要在这里添加 "prettier"，否则我会失去理智的
So we're gonna do yarn add dash dash Dev, prettier,
所以我们来执行 `yarn add --dev prettier`
just so we can format our JavaScript with prettier
这样我们就能使用 "prettier" 来格式化我们的 JavaScript 了
come back to index.js. I'm gonna hit command S,
回到 "index.js"，按下 "Command S"
and it looks like it does indeed, auto format with prettier now yay, no matter semicolons,
看起来它确实使用 "prettier" 进行自动格式化了，耶，没有分号了
we can call this fun function the same way we call connect. So in in our index dot
我们可以像调用 "connect()" 函数一样调用这个 "fund()" 函数
HTML, maybe we'll create a new button. Button. We'll give it an
ID of fund will say on click equals fund. And we'll say fund.
And this will be our button here, we save it, we're looking
at our front end. Now the fund button that if we call, we say
funding with undefined because we're not passing it an amount
here. So back in our index console dot log funding with and
we'll just want to make sure that we can actually call that
Funmi function. So we'll copy this line again and we'll say
type of window dot Aetherium does not equal undefined. We'll
go ahead and try to fund here to send a transaction. What are the
things that we absolutely 100% Always need? Well, we need a
provider slash connection to the blockchain. And we need a signer
slash wallet, slash someone with some gas to actually send it and
then And we're probably going to need the contract that we are
interacting with. And to get that contract, we're going to
need ABI and address. And with these all together, we can send
any transaction. So to get our provider, we're going to
actually go ahead and work with ethers again. Now, we're going
to do it a little bit differently, though, before, the
way we worked with ethers is we said const ethers equals require
ethers, right. And this is how we pulled ethers. And now like I
just said to you, though, require doesn't work in the
front end. And we actually don't want to install ethers with a
node modules package. So what we can actually do instead is let's
go to the ethers documentation. If you go to the Getting Started
section, scroll down, they have a section about importing using
Node js, which uses require or imports. And then they also have
some documentation for working with the web browser. So instead
of us doing a node module, what we'll do is we'll copy the
ethers library to our own directories and serve it
ourselves. So what we do is we can come in here, we can copy
this massive file, which is ethers, but in front end
addition, and come back to our file. And we'll make a new file
in here.
Called ethers. We'll do 5.6 point esm.min.js. And we'll
paste that massive thing in here. Now, since I have prettier
when I save it, it's going to auto format. And it's just this
huge file, which has everything ethers, but front end defied if
you will. Now what we can do is we can import this into our
index.js. So instead of using require in here, we'll say
import ethers from and then we'll just refer to that file
that we just got ethers dash 5.6 point esm.min.js. Now, we only
need to do this weird copy pasting of the file import thing
in this HTML JavaScript lesson. In future lessons with Node js,
we are going to do yarn, add ethers, kinda like we've
normally seen. The frameworks like React and next Jas that
we're going to use are going to automatically convert those yarn
added packages to their front end to five versions. But for
this section, this is how we're going to actually import the
ethers package. Now the other thing we'll have to do is on our
front end, we'll have to change this from type text slash
JavaScript to type module changes. The type module allows
us to import modules into our code, which we're going to be
importing this, and we're going to import another module as
well. Awesome. And now though, if we go back to our front end,
do a little refresh with the connect button, we get Connect
is not defined at HTML button.on. Click, so instead of
calling our Connect button from the front end here, we're going
to remove these on clicks from our index dot HTML, and go into
our index.js and add those connect buttons in here. So
we'll say const. Connect button equals document, dot get element
by ID, Connect button. And then we'll say const. One button
equals Doc, you meant dot get element by ID. One button, the
idea of the connect button is Connect button. The idea the fun
button is fun button. And then we'll say connect button.on
Click equals connect. And one button.on Click equals fond. We
go back to our front end, do a little refresh. We'll hit
connect now. And it's actually working, we'll go to our
Metamask will disconnect, refresh, hit Connect, and boom,
it's popping up again. This is just due to that type being
module, if it was text slash JavaScript, that on click button
adding in here, but since we're doing module, we're going to add
those on clicks right in our JavaScript. But now that we've
got ethers in here, what we can do is we can even do like a
little console dot log, just paste ethers in here, or
actually better yet. We'll add it right above the Connect
button. Go back to our front end, we'll do a refresh and we
see the entire ethers object right in our front end which is
perfect, which is exactly what we want here. And since we've
got these two variables here, we might as well update this to
just say connect button dot innerHTML equals connected and
here as well. Connects button dot innerHTML equals please
install meta mask because now connect button is going to be
the same as running this document dot get element by ID
right
here.