and great. Let's go back to continuing our font function.
So we'll say const provider equals new ethers dot providers
dot web three provider, window dot Aetherium. Web three
provider is an object in ethers that allows us to basically wrap
around stuff like Metamask is web three provider is really
similar to that JSON RPC provider, which we use before,
which is where we put in exactly that endpoint, our alchemy
endpoint, or when we're working with Metamask. Here, whatever
endpoint that we have in our network section is web three
provider takes that HTTP endpoint and automatically
sticks it in ethers for us. So this line of code basically
looks at our Metamask and goes, Ah, okay, I found the HTTP
endpoint inside there, Metamask. That's going to be what we're
going to use as our provider here. Since our provider is
connected to our Metamask. Here, we can get a signer or we can
get a wallet just by running const signer equals provider,
dot get signer, this is going to return whichever wallet is
connected from the provider, which again, our provider is our
Metamask. So if we're connected with with account one, it's
going to return account one as the signer connected with
account two, it'll return account two, etc. Now, I'm going
to add console dot log signer here, and then flip to the front
end now and show you what happens when we hit the fund
button. You can see in here we have our JSON RPC signer, the
signer is going to be the account that we've connected to
our front end. Now we have our provider, we have our signer.
Now, we're going to need our contract by getting the API and
the address. So we're gonna need to say const. Contract equals
what? How are we going to get our contract? Well, this is
where we're going to need to know the ABI and the address of
a working with typically, what you'll see a lot of projects do
since once a contract is deployed, the addresses are
going to change is they're going to have some type of constants
file. So they'll create a new file called constants, dot j s.
And in here, they'll add the addresses and any API's and
anything like that for us to use in our fund piece here. Now, as
we're developing, and as we're building, this, the backend and
the front end team are gonna have to interact a little bit,
or if it's just you doing the full stack, you're gonna have to
interact with their back end. So this is why it's so important to
have both your front end and your back end code nearby. So if
we go back to our Hardhead, fund me project that we just made, we
can find the ABI in here. Once again, if we go to artifacts, go
to contracts, we can go to fund me dot soul, fund me dot JSON,
we can find the ABI right here, it's going to be this massive
thing right here. So you can go ahead, you can even copy this
whole thing in this little non squiggly bracket and this little
bracket here, we can copy that. And then we can come back to our
constant.js. And we can just save it as variable, we'll say
Export const, Avi, e equals and paste that in there. And then
back in our index dot j s, we can import it with import
API from constants. Oops. Okay, great. So we have the API. Well,
what about the address, since we're going to be running this
locally, we want to get the contract address of this locally
run contract, we can do that a couple of ways. One way is you
can just have two windows open one with your front end code,
one with your back end code, and the one with your back end code,
you can run yarn, hard hat node, which will spin up our
blockchain node for us, and give us the address in here. Or what
we can do. And this will probably be a little bit easier
is in your window with your front end code and create a new
terminal. And now we'll have two terminals running. And then this
second one, we're going to CD down CD dot dot, and then CD,
hard hat on Me Free Code Camp. And in here, we're going to run
yarn, art head node. And this is going to spin up our local
blockchain in this second terminal in here, where we have
deploying fund me deploy that address, blah, blah, blah, right
here. And just a reminder, if I hit this x, it just hides the
terminal. I can always pull it back up with terminal new
terminal, and I can always hide it, but this is still running
inside of my terminal. So I'm going to hide it. And what I can
do is I can come back over to our constants folder, and at the
top, we can do export const contract address. equals, we'll
pull the terminal back up. And we'll go grab, where it says,
pulling fund me deployed at right here. We'll copy that
address, put some quotes, and we'll paste it in. And now we're
also exporting the contract address, then in our index.js
will import the contract address with comma, contract address.
And now we have both the ABI and the contract address. So what we
can do, we can say const contract equals new ethers dot
contract of, we'll pass the contract address, pass the API,
and we'll pass it the signer. Now we have an ethers contract
object that's connected to our signer, and we have the contract
address, and we have the contract abi, now that we have a
contract object, we can go ahead and start making transactions
the exact same way we've made transactions before we can just
run const transaction response equals a weight contract dot
fund. And then we'll pass a value of ethers dot utils dot
parse, ether ether mount. So this is going to be how we're
going to go ahead and create our transaction. And if you take
this right now, and we go to our front, we give it a little
refresh, make sure we're connected and we hit fund, we're
gonna get this error value must be a string. That's because at
the mount right now is being passed in as nothing. Now
normally, we'll pass parameters directly to our functions. But
what we're going to do is for now is we're just going to hard
code this. So we'll say const. At the mount equals, we'll do
like 77, or something we had fun. Now, what do you think's
gonna happen? Well, we get this other air, insufficient funds
for intrinsic transaction cost, or you might get some other
error, but you're gonna get a weird error here. And that's
because we're not actually connected to our local hard head
node right now. Well, if we look at our Metamask, we're currently
not connected to the right blockchain, we're connected to
rink B, or main net or whatever, we need to get connected to our
local host. If you look in your networks, you'll actually have a
local host object here already. But let's just be super
specific. And we'll add a new network here, we're going to add
something called our hard hat, local host. And we'll hit Add
Network and we'll add Hardhead. Local host in here, the RPC URL,
we can find from our node area, which we scroll to where our
node is running, we can copy this URL and paste it into new
RPC URL, chain ID is going to be 31337 currency symbol is going
to be go or ether. Even though this pop up says it might have a
different currency symbol go, we're just going to put eath in
here. And there is no block explorer, right? Because this is
a local blockchain, we're not going to have a block Explorer.
So we'll go ahead and hit Save.
And now we have an account here, which is great. We're connected
to our local blockchain. And if we switch our meta mask, we can
see we're on the local hard hat. And we are connected. Awesome.
Let's refresh. Let's run fund one more time. And we'll see a
transaction does indeed pop up. This is great. But our account
here doesn't have any money we have, we're broke, we don't have
any local Hardhead Aetherium. So we're actually going to need to
import one of our accounts from hard hat into our meta mask,
which we can do so and you can actually do this for any account
with a private key so hard that gives us these accounts. And
we're going to import the private key of Count zero into
our meta mask. So we're going to copy the private key, we're
going to come back to our front end, click on our meta mask,
we're gonna hit this big button, we're gonna hit import account.
It's like type private key, and we're gonna paste our private
key here. A quick note, if you choose json file, remember how
back in that ether section, we encrypted our key into a JSON
file with a password, you can actually import accounts with
that JSON file with the password. So if you encrypt a
key and you want to add it to meta mask, you can go ahead and
add it in just like this. But for now, we're going to use
private key, we'll paste the private key in and we'll hit
import. And we can see we now have an account, a new account
and account three, with a ton of eath from our local blockchain.
So we'll refresh one more time, we'll go ahead and connect,
we'll make sure that our account three is connected. And if it's
not, we'll go ahead and hit this Connect button. So that now our
account three is what's connected here. And we'll go
ahead and hit fund. And we now see that we can fund this
contract, we can go ahead and hit Confirm. And if we look and
nothing's going to happen on our front end, because we didn't
tell our front end to do anything once we confirm, but if
we go to our blockchain, we can see our fun function was called
we've just made our first transaction on a blockchain from
our own front end, this is awesome, great work. But it's
probably a little confusing to the user. If nothing happens
here, they're going to hit the fun function. And it's going to
be like, Oh, okay, cool. What, what happens? Now, we probably
want to make it a little bit more obvious that something just
happened. And one more thing I want to show you, you don't have
to follow along here, if I hit fund, and then I hit reject,
it's gonna freak out on us and be like, hey, like, you hit
reject, I don't know what to do now. So we're going to make our
code a little bit more robust by adding a try catch. So we'll
tell JavaScript to try running this transaction. And then if it
catches an error, just to console dot log, that error. So
now, if I hit fund, and I hit reject, it's gonna, it'll still
be a little bit mad, but at least we're catching it and it's
not going to break and destroy everything. Okay, cool. We've
got a transaction response here. And when we hit fund, our front
end goes great. You've funded me I'm I'm super confused.