Oh, one
other point, something that you'll probably run into
multiple times. As we're doing this. If you get an error that
looks like this eath. JS query while formatting outputs from
RPC, nonce to high expected not to be too but got form, you will
definitely see this a whole lot. Here's what you do to fix this.
The reason this happens is because you've closed your
hardhat node and then restarted it, and your heart had node
goes, Okay, well, I'm starting fresh, I'm starting from zero.
But Metamask isn't smart enough to know that, what we want to do
is we want to come to our Metamask, we'll hit this big
button, we'll go down to settings, we'll go to Advanced,
and we'll go to reset account. And yes, we're going to reset
it. This isn't something ideally that you'd like to do with an
actual account with actual money on a local network, this is
fine. Now if you reset the account, and you reset the node,
we can go ahead and hit Confirm. And it doesn't give us that
error anymore. So that's kind of the tip there, you want to reset
the nuts so that our Metamask and our blockchain are in sync
with that nonce number.