So we have this transaction response.
我们已经有了这个 `transactionResponse`
And we probably want our front end to give the user some indication,
我们还希望我们的前端能尽可能多的给用户一些指示
hey, the transaction went through.
“嘿，交易已经通过”
So what we want to do is we want to listen to the blockchain for this to finish.
所以我们要做的就是监听区块链完成交易
So we can either listen for the TX to be mined.
所以我们要“监听被开采的交易”
("listen for the tx to be mined")
Or we can listen for an event.
或者我们可以“监听一个事件”
("listen for an event")
We haven't learned about events yet. But we will. So for now, since we haven't learned about events yet, we're just going to
我们还没有了解过关于“事件”("event")的内容
listen for the TX to be mined. Or to listen for the transaction
to be mined, we're actually going to create a new function
called function, listen, or transaction mine in this is
going to take as input a transaction response, and a
provider. Now you'll notice this isn't an async function. For
this section. This is intentional, we don't want this
to be an async function. And you'll see why in a second.
We're going to be using JavaScript promise JavaScript
async functionality to its massive advantage. And this is
why JavaScript actually works so well on the front end is because
of how it's asynchronous. So we're going to create this
function listen for transaction to be mined, we're going to
await in our fund function. And we're going to have this return
a promise. Let's go ahead, and let's learn how to build this.
So we're gonna say console dot log, string interpolation, we'll
say mining. And then in here, we'll say transaction, response
dot hash. All of our transaction response objects have a hash,
which just represent that hash. And we'll do a couple of data
dot, we'll put in our console here, we're waiting for the
transaction to be mined, then what we're going to do is we're
going to return a new promise. And the reason we're going to
return a promise is because we need to create a listener for
the blockchain. We want to listen for this event to happen.
But we want to tell JavaScript, hey, wait for this thing to
finish looking, wait for this thing to finish looking. Now
here's where this gets a little bit tricky. In our fund
function. After we create the transaction, we basically want
to tell JavaScript Hey, wait for this TX to finish. So our code
is going to look as simple as await listen for transaction
mine. And we're going to pass it the trans action response
and our provider. So we're saying hey, listen for this
transaction finish. And we're using this await keyword,
because again, the await keyword says okay, we're gonna stop
right here. We're gonna stop until this function is
completely done. Now in this listen for transaction in mind,
we have to define how we're actually going to listen for
this. So we're going to say listen for this transaction to
finish. Ethers actually comes with a way for us to listen for
transactions and listen for events, which again, we haven't
learned About, but don't worry about that yet. So we can go to
the ethers docs. And we can look up once. Contract dot once.
There's a whole bunch of listeners that we can use to
listen for events and listen for different things to happen, we
can do this thing called provider dot once where we
listen for some event. And once that event fires, we call some
other function that we've defined. Now, we haven't talked
about events yet. And again, don't worry about this quite
yet. One of the events that we can wait for is we can just wait
for the transaction receipt to finish, right, because once we
get a transaction receipt, that means that the transaction has
actually finished going through. So we're going to use this
provider dot once syntax to wait for the transaction receipt,
which is going to be our event, which isn't really an event, but
don't worry about that yet. And then we're going to call some
listener function that we defined, you can also do
provider.on, which will trigger anytime your event fires
provider once just triggers one time, we only care about this
transaction going through one time. So we're passing our
provider object. So we're gonna say provider dot once our event
which is just going to be transaction response, hash,
provided on transaction response dot hash. So once we get this
hash, which will pretty much get right away, we're going to call
our listener function. Now we can create a function listener
like this, and then just pass listener in here. But we're
going to do an anonymous function here, because that's
typically what we see as the syntax for these loops. And so
far, we're doing provider dot once to do this anonymous
function, we're going to do just two little parentheses here. And
this arrow notation. So this by itself represents an anonymous
function. So we're saying, hey, there's some function, it
doesn't take any parameters, and it doesn't have any code, this
arrow function, this whole thing is saying this is an anonymous
function. So we're saying provided at once transaction
hash happens, here's the function that you want to
execute. It doesn't do anything right now. But let's have a do
something. So once this transaction dot response
finishes, we're going to take a trans transaction received as an
input parameter, or our our callback function, or our
listener function. And all we're going to do is we're gonna say
console dot log, completed with a little string interpolation,
transaction receipt, that confirmations, confirmations,
and then completed with transaction receipt,
confirmations, confirmations. So once this provider dot once sees
that there's a transaction hash, it's going to give as an input
rammer to our listener function, the transaction receipt, kind of
that same syntax that we've been seeing this whole time, once a
transaction response finishes, we get the transaction receipt,
and we can do stuff with it. And we see how many block
confirmations it has. For us, this pretty much should always
be one. Now if we save this, go back to our front end, and we
hit fund, it's going to work, we're going to give the user
some indication that it worked, which is great. But it's not
really going to work the way that we want it to work. We have
this console dot log done right after we do the await, listen
for transaction mine, and we come back and we hit fund, we
hit confirm, it actually doesn't go in the order that we want it
to go, it goes mining this thing that it says Done. And then it
says completed with one trip confirmation what what's going
on here, we should write completed before we write done,
because that's the order that we have this in. But it looks like
it's words, it's going out of order. What what's going on
here, what's going to happen is when we call listen for
transaction mine, or listen for transaction, mine function is
going to kick off, but it's going to kick off provided on
once as its own process. So await listen for transaction,
mine will kick off the listener, but it doesn't wait for this
listener to find the transaction response. So this function will
actually finish before provider dot once finishes. So after it
kicks off the listener, it'll run to the next line of our
code, which is console dot log and done. Our front end we'll go
oh, oh, you kicked off a listener earlier. Let me go back
down and let me recheck to see if it's finished. And if it has
finished, I'll go do what it told me to do. And this is where
what's known as the event loop kicks in.
We don't actually wait for this provider that wants to finish,
we add this provided at once onto this queue called the event
loop. And our front end is going to periodically check back to it
to see if it's finished. So we want to adjust our code. So we
wait for the listener to finish listening, which is where we're
going to get into promises here. So what we want to do is we want
to adjust this function to now return a promise. And we're
going to use this syntax a couple of times in the future.
So what we're going to do is we're going to say hey, we want
to wait for the listener To finish listening, we're going to
wrap this whole thing into a promise. And we're going to say
return, new promise. And a promise takes a function itself
as an input parameter. So again, we'll use kind of this anonymous
function notation. And it will take two input parameters
resolve and reject. So resolve says, hey, if this promise works
correctly, call this resolve function. And for us, this
promise is going to be done when the listener finishes listening.
And then we would reject if there was some type of timeout,
we're not going to write the reject function. But in the
future, if you were to do this for production, you'd add some
timeout as the reject parameter. Basically, you're saying, hey,
once the listener finishes listening, we're going to
resolve and if it takes too long, we're gonna say ask for
you, you took too long, and instead of closing it off, here,
we're going to close it off around this provider thing. So
we're gonna say return new promise, resolve, reject. And
only once this transaction gets fired, are we going to resolve
this promise, like so. So what is happening here, so we're
going to put the resolve inside of this provider at once. So
we're saying, once this transaction hash is found, then
we're going to call this function, we're gonna say
console dot log, and then we're going to resolve so this promise
only returns once a resolve or reject is called. And we're
telling it only resolve only finish this function once.
Transaction response dot hash is found, because it's going to be
inside of these little squiggly parentheses for provider dot
once, the promise right now only resolves after it's fired. It's
event here. If this was really confusing, just copy paste this
and move on, we're getting a little bit deeper into front end
stuff here. So hopefully, this was clear, if not definitely
jump in to the GitHub discussions to start asking
about this stuff. But now that we've updated this, we can come
back to our front end, we can hit the fund button. And
hopefully this time, everything will go in order. We'll hit
confirm, we see mining completed, and then we see done.
And the reason for this is because again, our await keyword
is now waiting, it says oh, you're returning a promise, I
need to await I need to wait for it to resolve or reject. And we
only resolve the promise once our provider finds this
transaction hash and this transaction receipt, this is
this listen for transaction mine. In future sections, all of
this is going to be abstracted away for us. So life is going to
be much easier, but it is important to understand what's
actually going on here. Awesome. So now we're giving the front
end some indication of what's going on. Our fun function is
done well, no, not really. Why not? Well, because right now
we're hard coding the eath amount to 0.1. And on the front
end, we probably don't want to hard code it, we probably want
to allow users to fund as much or as little as they want. So we
actually need to change this from just a button to a input
form. So to do this, we're gonna go back over into our HTML. So
we'll go back to index dot HTML. And we're going to change this
fun section here, we're going to add some form information. So
we're going to keep this button as it is, or we're going to add
like a little text box to input as much eath as they want. So
I'm going to create a label, we're gonna say it's for, it's
going to be fund and this label we're gonna say, is eath amount,
and then we're gonna close label, this is basically just
going to create a label. And if we go back to our front end, we
now just have this Etham out label that isn't labeling
anything. Now we're going to create an input, and we're going
to give it an ID of eath amount. And we're going to give it a
placeholder
of 0.1. And then we're gonna close the input. So now if we
flip to our front end, we have eath amount, labeling this
little text box with a placeholder of 0.1. And we can
add stuff in here, you know, blah, blah, whatever. And one
more thing, if you have some tags, but you don't put anything
in between them, you can actually shorten it by just
putting the little closing thing at the back of it like this. So
if you don't have anything between your tags, you can just
close them like this, these two are equivalent, boom, boom,
boom, boom, those are the same thing. Great. When we called
fund right now we're calling fund and we're not passing any
parameters. Let's update our fund to no longer be hardcoding
eath amount in here, and we'll have and we'll have our fund
function populated by whatever we put in this eath amount input
box in our fund function, instead of saying const eath
amount equals 0.1. We'll grab it from this eath amount ID and
we'll say document dot get element by ID eath amount, dot
value. So we're going to grab whatever value In this input box
here, now, in our index.js, we have console dot log funding
with eath amount, if in our front end, we do 1.7. And we hit
fund, we now see in our console dot log, it says funding with
1.7. And we'll get 1.7. And our little fun section confirm, it
will mine it, it'll complete it, and then say, done. Awesome. So
now we've added a little text box here. So people can fund as
much or as little as they want. Perfect, this whole thing can
kind of be considered a form. There's also a form tag, but
we're going to just use this for now.