So in its minimalistic sense, we essentially have a way for people to enter our raffle.
从最简化的角度来看，我们已经为用户基本上提供了参与我们抽奖的途径了
Now we need a way to pick the random winner. And this is where we're going to need chain link VRF and chain link keepers.
现在我们需要一个方法来选出一名随机的优胜者，这里就要用 Chainlink VRF 以及 Chainlink Keepers 了
So let's again, watch some sub lessons about learning about chain link VRF. And learning about chain link keepers.
所以让我们再次观看一些子课程，来学习一下 Chainlink VRF 以及 Chainlink Keepers
We've made some videos about these before. So we're just going to play these videos.
我们之前已经制作了一些相关视频，所以我们会直接播放这些视频
So you can learn about how taling VRF version two works, and also how chain link keepers works,
你可以学到关于 Chainlink VRF 版本 2 还有 Chainlink Keepers 的工作原理
then we're going to come back and we're going to add them into our contracts here.
然后我们会回到这里，并将它们添加到我们的合约中来
If you're already familiar, and you already played with them, feel free to skip those sections.
如果你已经很熟悉，并且使用过它们了，那么你可以自由跳过这些部分
And we'll just get to building them here.
然后我们会直接开始构建它们
Hi, my name is Steven fluid. And today we're going to be taking a look at chain links VRF. version two,
大家好，我是 Stephen Fluin，今天我们要来看一下 Chainlink VRF 版本 2
version two has a few different mental models that we should be aware of.
VRF 版本 2 具有一些不同的思维模式，我们应当注意到这一点
And I want to show you what it feels like to be using it.
并且我要向你们展示一下它的使用体验是什么样的
The big important thing to know about Vera version two is that instead of the Vera one model
VRF 版本 2 和版本 1 的模式相比有一个重要的事情需要知道
where you'd be funding your contract with Link, instead, you're going to be funding a subscription,
你不再是通过 Link 向你的合约输入资金，而是资助一个订阅
which is basically an account that allows you to fund and maintain balance for multiple consumer contracts.
它基本上就是一个允许你为多个用户合约提供资金和维持余额的账户
Let's dive into the docs and see what using Vera fie two looks and feels like.
让我们深入到文档中，看一下 VRF 版本 2 的外观和使用体验
In order to show this off a little bit. I'm going to dive right into the get a random number guide in the chain link documentation.
为了展示这一点，我要深入到 Chainlink 文档中的 "Get a Random Number" 指南
And so it's going to go through a few the requirements of some of the technology we're going to use today.
它会介绍我们今天要使用的一些技术的一些要求
And the first thing it's going to ask us to do is to make sure that we are on the Rinkeby test net.
首先我们要做的是，确保我们已经连上了 Rinkeby 测试网
So let's go ahead and jump over to Rinkeby. Make sure my meta mask is unlocked here.
所以让我们先连上 Rinkeby，解锁我的 MetaMask
And now that I'm on Rinkeby, great,
现在我已经在 Rinkeby 上了，非常好
I should be able to use the VIP version to test net.
我应该能够在测试网上使用 VRF 版本 2
Now we're going to jump over to subscription manager.
现在我要进入“订阅管理”("Subscription Manager")
And the subscription manager is where we're going to manage our subscription account.
"Subscription Manager" 是我们管理订阅账户的地方
Basically, this is the place that you put the funds in order to be able to use it across a bunch of different chains.
基本上，这就是你放置资金的地方，以便你能够进行跨链使用
So we're going to go ahead and connect our wallet here in order to use the subscription app.
我们继续，连接我们的钱包以使用订阅应用
And then we're going to go ahead and create a new subscription.
接着我们来创建一个新的订阅("Create subscription")
So we'll just use my address as the subscription address here.
这里我直接用我的地址作为订阅地址
I'll approve the creation.
同意创建
And as soon as that transaction is confirmed, our subscription should be created.
一旦交易确认，我们的订阅应该也就创建好了
Alright, now we have a subscription. Basically, this is the account where we're going to fund it.
好的，现在我们有了一个订阅，也就是我们要注入资金的账户
And then we can use that account for all of our random Miss requests.
接着我们就可以用这个账户来进行我们所有的随机数请求
So I'm gonna go ahead and just put in 10 link here,
you can put in however much you want. The price and link of
every random number you request, it's going to be based on the
current gas rates on a given chain, as well as the gasoline
that you've chosen. On our funds have been added, let's go ahead
and add a consumer contract. So it's asking us for consumer
address, we don't actually have a consumer address yet. So let's
go ahead and jump over to the documentation and create a
contract that is going to request a number. So if you
scroll down, you're going to see this Vera fee to consumer that
soul contract that we can open it in remix, let's just jump
right there. We're gonna notice a few different things in this
contract at the top, we've got some input. So now you've got
VRF, consumer base version two, we've got an interface for the
VRF coordinator, and then also a reference to the link token
interface. So all of those are specified for you on the Rinkeby
network here in the example code. And then you can refer to
the documentation for whatever chain you're going to be
deploying to. And then you're going to see a few new options
here. So the key hash option is the way that you specify that
gasoline that was described in the documentation. So depending
on the key hash you choose for the given chain you're on the
gas limit will be set differently for your random
number requests. So for example, on a theory main net, we have a
200 way key hash 500 Wiki hash and 1000 graykey hash. You can
also see in our contract Hear that we have a callback estimate
that you're in charge of. So depending on how much gas you're
willing to spend in the fulfill random number, you should set
this value appropriately. Next up is request confirmations. So
this was something in verify would be one that you could not
control. But here now, depending on the chain you're on,
depending on the request and the type nature of the request you
want to make, you can actually change this number. And then one
of the most important and useful features that gives you a lot
more flexibility and control of your VRF is you can actually
specify the number of random numbers you want. And so you
specify the number words, and then that will specify how many
random you went to 56 as you get back from the network. All right
here in the constructor, we're gonna see a address for the
coordinator and address for the link token. And then you'll see
that the subscription ID is going to be created as we deploy
the contract. And so I'm gonna go ahead and get that. So if you
remember when we created the subscription after we found it,
and we see this subscription ID, and now when I deploy this, I'm
going to use that subscription ID. And we've got two methods
that should look very familiar, we've got fulfill randomness
method that takes in randomness is going to be fulfilled by the
Bureau of Oracle, as well as you got request random words, which
is how we're actually going to initiate the request to the
Oracle. So I think we're actually are already ready to go
ahead and deploy this. So let's jump to the deploy screen here
and select the right contract, which in our case, is your FB to
consumer. And I'm going to make sure that I am on injected web
three so that we can actually deploy to the Rinkeby network.
And I'm going to paste in the subscription ID here. And I'm
going to deploy, let's go ahead and pay for that transaction.
And as soon as that is confirmed by the network will show up
here, and we'll be able to copy this address, and then add that
as a consumer and authorize this contract to use my subscription
account. So let's go ahead and authorize this with them another
Metamask transaction.
Alright, we can have your subscription, we can see how
much link we funded it with. And we can see our consumer
contract. So now by doing this, we've authorized our consumer
contract to make requests for randomness. So let's go ahead
and make a request for randomness here. So we're gonna
go back to our contract that we deployed here. And we're just
gonna use the remix interface here to keep things simple. And
I'm going to request some randomness. So obviously, this
is going to use all of the configuration that I specified
in my contract, just kind of hard coded here. So we're gonna
get to words of random is here. So we're gonna hit request
randomness, confirm the Rigby transaction. And then as soon as
that transaction comes back, we should notice that we actually
have a request. And then what we'll be doing is we'll be
waiting for the Oracle to call fulfill random words on our
contract. And then we'll be storing all of those random
words in this s random words, storage variable. Let's go ahead
and check to see if our random numbers come back from the
Oracle. So I'll go in here into random words. And let's request
the zeroeth item of the array looks like we've got a random
number there. And because we requested two random numbers, we
should also have an item in index one. All right, we we've
got our randomness there. And if we go back to the subscription
manager app, you're going to see that there's actually an event
history item here, we'll see that we spent about point three,
three link to get those two random numbers, we've just taken
a journey to see what it looks like and feels like to use Veera
version two,
now that we've learned a little bit more about chainlink VRF, I
hope that you took some time to go to doxa chain link and play
around with it a little bit so that you understand what's
really going on, we're going to use this sample contract in here
to create our function that's going to pick our random winner.
This is an on chain contract that coordinates with a
verifiably random chain link node to give us a random number,
you could look at the code directly on chain, or you can
come right to the chain link GitHub and look at all the code
for how this is actually happening provably and randomly.
And we'll have a link to this in the GitHub repo associated with
this course.