So we're going to create our function here called
pick a random winner, this function is going to be called
by the chain link keepers network so that this can
automatically run without us having to interact with it. And
actually, while we're updating this, I want to add some some
stars here saying view slash pure functions. Now our pick
random winner function, we're actually not going to make
public we're going to make external, external functions are
a little bit cheaper than public functions. Because solidity
knows that our own contract can call this, we're actually going
to change the name of this function, as well, very soon,
but we'll get to that in a little bit. So in order for us
to pick a random winner, we actually have to do two things,
we first have to request the random number. And then once we
get it, do something with it. So chainlink VRF is a two
transaction process. And this is actually intentional. Having
random numbers in two transactions is actually also
much better than having it in one. If it's just one
transaction, then people could just brute force tries
simulating calling this transaction and we'll learn how
to simulate calls soon simulate calling these transactions to
see what they can manipulate to make sure that they are the
winner. We want to make sure that this is absolutely fair.
Nobody can manipulate our smart contract into having them be the
winner of the lottery, this function is actually going to
request it. And then in a second func the random number is going
to be returned. And in the transaction that we actually get
the random number from the chain link network, that's when we're
going to actually send the money to the winner. And if we go to
the chain link documentation, the function that the chain link
node calls is this function called fulfill random words,
this is going to be the requesting one, which we could
even change this to request random winner to make it more
clear, and then we'll make a function fulfill random words.
And this is going to be an internal override, which we'll
explain in a little bit, now fulfill fulfill random words
basically means we're fulfilling random numbers. The word comes
from a computer science terminology, but you can
basically just think of this as fulfill random numbers, because
we can get multiple random numbers. Now in order to make
our raffle contract VRF a bowl, we have to import the chain link
code, we can go back to the documentation, and we're just
going to grab this bottom line and we'll grab the top line in a
second. So we're going to do import, I'm going to write it
out. But if you want to copy paste, you can at chain link
slash contracts slash SRC slash V 0.8, slash V RF, consumer
base, b two dot Sol. And since we're importing at chainlink,
slash contracts, we're gonna need to add that in by running
yarn, add dash dash dev at chainlink slash contracts. And
now that we have this in here, we should be able to import like
so. And we're going to need to make our raffle VRF consumer
base double, we're gonna need to inherit VRF consumer base go
into our node modules at chain link src, V 08 VRF, consumer
base V two, it comes with this function fulfill random words.
And you can see it's an internal virtual function, virtual means
it's expecting to be overwritten, the reason that
it's in the sphere of consumer base V two is so that the VRF
coordinator, which we'll use in a bit knows that it can call
this fulfill random words function. And this is the
function that we're overriding. So back in our raffle dot salt,
we're going to inherit it by doing is VRF consumer base V
two. And now if we scroll down to fulfill random words, we can
add in the input parameters fulfilled pill random words,
which are going to be un 256, Request ID and un 256, a memory
array random words. And if we hit Save Our linter will now
notice, okay, this is what I'm expecting, I'm expecting us to
override the Fill random words, which takes these parameters.
Now if we look in our docs in our constructor, we need to pass
the VRF consumer base V TOS constructor and pass that VRF
coordinator. Again, this V RF coordinator is the address of
the contract that does the random number verification. So
right next to our constructor will add the VRF consumer base V
to constructor and we need to pass the VRF coordinator v2
address. So in our main constructor, we'll add that as a
parameter as well. So we'll say address
VRF core to Nate Torre v two, and then we'll pass this as a
parameter for the VRF consumer basically till now that we have
that we shouldn't see that little underscore anymore. And
we should be able to run yarn aren't had compiled. Awesome.
And we can see compiled two files successfully and our code
is working great.