So now we need to actually have our request random winner function requests a random winner.
现在我们就需要实际用我们的 "requestRandomWinner" 函数来请求一个随机的优胜者了
So let's go back to the documentation. And we'll see how to do that.
让我们回到文档，看一下该怎么做
We can look at this function request random words and see exactly how it works.
我们可以看一下这个 "requestRandomWords" 函数，并了解一下它是如何运作的
On the Vera of coordinator address. We go ahead and call this request random words function,
在 VRF 的 "COORDINATOR" 地址上，我们调用了这个 "requestRandomWords" 函数
we're going to need to call this function on the coordinator contract
我们需要在这个 "COORDINATOR" 合约上调用这个函数
to get the coordinator contract. We're going to use the Vera v2 coordinator interface and the Vir of coordinator address.
要想获取 "COORDINATOR" 合约，我们要用到 "VRFCoordinatorV2Interface" 以及 "vrfCoordinator" 的地址
So we're going to want to keep track of those.
所以，我们要跟踪这些信息
We can do that once again in Arkansas. factor,
我们可以再次在构造函数中完成这个操作
we have the address being passed to our Bureau of consumer base. Let's also keep it as a state variable for us.
我们把这个地址传入到了 "VRFConsumerBase" 中，让我们将其也保存为状态变量
First, let's get the interface so we can interact with that contract,
首先，让我们获取接口，以便与合约进行交互
we can import that from chain link as well
我们同样可以从 chainlink 中把它导入进来
by doing import at chain link slash contracts, slash SRC slash fees 0.8, slash inter faces slash VRF cord to mentor V to interface dot Sol.
`@chainlink/contracts/src/v0.8/interfaces/VRFCoordinatorV2Interface.sol`
And now that we import this interface, same as we did with price feeds,
现在我们导入了这个接口，就和喂价的操作一样
we can do VRF, coordinator v2, interface VRF coordinator.
我们可以 `VRFCoordinatorV2Interface vrfCoordinator`
And then we can save the sphere of coordinator using the address
然后我们可以用这个地址来保存 "vrfCoordinator"
so we can say VRF coordinator equals this address VRF coordinator veto.
我们可以说 `vrfCoordinator = VRFCoordinatorV2Interface`
And we're just going to wrap that address around the interface so that now we can work with this VRF coordinator contract.
接着我们把地址放到接口里，这样我们就能使用这个 "vrfCoordinator" 合约了
Now we're only going to set our VRF coordinator one
time right in our constructor. So what's the best thing that we
can do here, private, immutable, you Gosh, darn. Right, let's do
private, immutable, you have coordinator and we'll change the
name to I underscore the ref coordinator so that we know that
your coordinator is indeed an immutable variable. In order to
request the random word, we need to give it a number of
parameters, I'm gonna go ahead and copy this line into our
contract just so that we can talk about exactly what's going
on with it. And we don't need the AES Request ID. And instead
of coordinator we're going to do I underscore fear of
coordinator. So we're going to call request random words on
that VRF coordinator contract, and we need to pass it the key
hash or the gasoline, I prefer calling it the gas lane, we go
to the chain link, Doc's go to contract addresses. And we
scroll down we can see different gas lanes a different
configuration parameters for different networks is key hash
is going to be the gasoline of the key hash, which tells the
chain link node the maximum price you're willing to pay for
your guests and way if for example, gas prices skyrocket,
and it's going to cost you a ton of money to get that random
number setting a ceiling, we'll make it so that random number
doesn't come back. For us to pick a gas lane, we're probably
going to want to have this gas lane or this key hash stored
somewhere. So let's go ahead and make that a parameter of our
constructor as well. And we'll save that as a state variable.
So we'll do comma bytes 32, gasoline or key hash or whatever
you want to call it. And then we'll make a new state variable.
And we're only going to set this once. So we'll make this a
private, immutable. I underscore gasoline, and then we'll say
gasoline equals gasoline.
So now, we can just swap this out, or I underscore gasoline.
Okay, what's next, we need a subscription ID, the
subscription ID is going to be the subscription that we need
for funding our requests. There's actually a contract on
chain, which we can use to fund any subscription for any of
these external data or external computation bits. And in this
contract, there's a list of these subscriptions for people
to make requests to. So we need the ID of the subscription that
we're using to request our random numbers and pay the link
Oracle gas, the subscription ID is probably also going to be
something we're going to pass as a parameter to our lottery. So
once again, let's scroll up to our constructor, we'll add a new
parameter. And our subscription ID actually doesn't need to be a
un 256, it can actually be a little bit smaller with a un 64.
So we'll pass a un 64 sub scription ID, we'll make a UNT
64. Since we're only going to set this once we'll make this a
private, immutable. I underscore sub scription ID down here and
we'll say I subscription ID equals sub subscription ID.
Alright, awesome. So now we can change this to our subscription
ID. Okay, what's next? Request confirmations request
confirmations is a un 16, which says how many confirmations the
chain link node should wait before responding. So if you
make a request, and there's only one block confirmation, maybe
you don't actually send it because you don't you're afraid
of some type of blockchain reorganization or something,
we're not going to worry too much about this. And we're
actually just going to make this a constant of three. So we're
not even going to have this be per amortizable we're gonna have
this one be a constant. So we'll say a you int 16 Private
constant request, confirmations equals three, and we're using
the capslock and underscores for our constant variables here. And
now we'll grab request confirmations and stick it in
right here. What's next callback gas limit callback gas limit is
going to be the limit for how much gas to use for the callback
request your contracts fulfill random words, this sets a limit
for how much computation are fulfilled random words can be
this is a good way to protect ourselves from spending way too
much gas. If, for example, we accidentally code our contract
in a way where fulfill random words is incredibly gas
expensive. It'll block the random number from responding.
We are going to make this parameter sizable because we
want to change it depending on how we code our fulfill random
word. So in our constructor, let's add one more, we'll add
you int 32. Since the size of this is a un 32, callback, gas
limit, and we'll save the sub top as a UNT 32, private,
immutable, I underscore call back. Yes limit. And we'll save
this. I call back gas limit equals call back Yes, limit. And
then we'll take this, and we'll stick it here. All right, we got
one more number of words, this is going to be how many random
numbers that we want to get, we only want one. So we're gonna go
back up to the top, we're going to create a you int 32. And
we'll make this also a private constant. Num words equals one,
because we only want one random number. And then that'll be the
last thing we need to add for our IVF coordinator dot request
random words. Now this request random words function returns a
request ID a un 256 Request ID a unique ID that defines who's
requesting this and all this other information. If we want to
save it, we can do u and 256. Request ID IVF coordinator
requests random words. Now for now, we are going to emit an
event with this request ID. And we'll go over why we're going to
do that a little bit later, create a new event at the top.
And we're not going to follow the naming convention here.
Because we're going to change the name of our functions a
little bit, we're going to call this requested raffle winner.
And we're going to take a un 256 indexed Request ID. Down here,
we're gonna do omit requested raffle winner Request ID. And
now we have a function that we can use to request a random
winner using chain link VRF. Now again, we're going to set this
up so that the chain link keepers call this on an
interval, but we'll do that in a little bit. For now, let's
figure out what to do once we get that
random number.