Once we get that random number, we're going to want to pick a random winner from our array of players up here.
一旦我们获取到了随机数，就要从上面的玩家数组中获取一个随机的优胜者了
So what do we do? Well, let's go in here.
我们该怎么做呢？让我们先来到这
And let's pick a random winner using something called the module function.
我们要使用一种被称为“取模函数”("modulo function")的方法来选择一个随机优胜者
Now we're gonna get an array back of random words, or random numbers, if you will,
现在我们得到了一个包含随机数的数组
since we're only requesting one random word, this random words array is going to be of size one with one random word in it.
因为我们只请求了一个随机数，所以这个随机数数组的大小就是一，也就是包含一个随机数
Now this random word is a un 256. So this random word could be something like this.
这个随机数是一个 uint256，所以它会是，这————样————的
Well, obviously without the hyphens, but it could be something absolutely massive like that
当然，肯定没有连字符，反正它就是一个很大的数
our players array is only going to be so big. So how do we get a random winner from this potentially massive random number,
我们的玩家数组不会太大，那么我们该如何从这个巨大的随机数中获取到一个随机的优胜者呢
we can use something called the modulo function, the
module operation, a mod N yields, the remainder are after
the division of an operand a by the blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. So what does this mean? Well, we can use the mod
function to get a random number out of our players array. So
let's say our players array or excuse me, our s players array
is of size 10. And a random number is 200. So how do we pick
a random person out of this players array, or, let's say our
random number is 202. If we do 202, which is our random number,
mod 10, we're gonna basically do 202 divided by 10. But instead
of having the decimals, we're just going to say, Okay, how
many times is 10 evenly divide into 202. And what's the
remainder, what doesn't divide evenly into 202? Well, 20 times
10 equals 200, with two leftover, so two doesn't evenly
divide, or multiply into 200. So that means 202 mod 10 is going
to equal to two. So that's how the module function works. And
we can use that so we're always going to get a number between.
So we're always going to get a number here between zero and
nine, which works out perfectly because that which works out
perfectly, because those are the indexes of the 10 people in our
array. So let's use that here. We'll say a un 256 index of
winner is going to be equal to random words, at index zero,
because we're only getting one random word module, the S
underscore players dot length. So this will give us the index
of our random winner to get that address of the winner will do
address payable, recent winner equals s players at this index
of winner so awesome. So now we'll have the address of the
person that got this random number, the person's that's
going to be our verifiably random winner. Now, it might be
kind of cool to brag to people that you're the recent winner.
So let's go ahead to the top and we'll create a new state
variable for our most recent winner make this state variable
in a new section called lottery variables. We'll say address
private s underscore recent winner and it'll start out as
nobody but as we get winners update it with s recent winner
equals recent winner and we'll probably want people to know who
this is winter is so down below, we can do function get recent
winner, it's going to be a public view that's going to
return that address. And then we'll just say return s
underscore recent winner, since again, the recent winner is
going to be a storage variable. So now that we have a recent
winner, what else are we gonna do? Well, we're probably going
to want to send them the money in this contract. So we're going
to do exactly what we did before with sending the money, we're
going to do that bull success, comma, blank equals recent
winner, call, I'm gonna say value, it's going to be address
of this dot balance, we're going to send all the money in this
contract, and we're going to pass it no data. And now we
could say require, you know, success, whatever, we're going
to be a little bit more gas efficient here. And we're just
gonna say, if not success, then we're going to revert a new
transfer failed error. So we're gonna go to the top, or say,
error name of the contract is raffle, underscore, underscore,
transfer failed, like that, then go back down, and we can now do
revert, raffle transfer failed like that. And now that we've
picked a winner, right now, we don't have a way to actually
keep track of the list of previous winners. So we're just
going to omit an event. So there's always going to be that
easily query double history of event winners. So we're going to
create a new event in the events section called the event winner
picked. And this is going to be an address indexed winner. And
we'll scroll down and we'll do MIT winner picked the address of
the recent winner. This looks pretty good.
This looks pretty good here. Now you'll notice our request ID as
this little underscore here and saying, hey, it's an unused
function parameter, since we don't use this, but we still
need fulfill random words to take a request ID and a random
words array. But we don't use Request ID, we can just comment
out just the request ID part like this, this tells our
function, hey, yes, we know that you need a un 256. But we're not
going to use the request ID. So we'll leave it in here. But
we'll leave it blank. Now let's run a little compile here. We'll
use yarn, hard hat, compile, or hh compile, we'll see if we're
coding things correctly. And indeed, we don't see any errors.
So perfect, we can continue. So we've added the chain link VRF,
where we have a way to verifiably get a random winner.
This is fantastic. Now let's update this contract so that not
only can it pick a verifiable winner, but it can also do this
all programmatically and automatically trigger picking a
random winner based off of some time interval without us having
to interact with it. And in a decentralized context. In order
for us to automatically trigger smart contracts based off of
some parameter be a time parameter, maybe the price of
some asset is some number, maybe there's a certain amount of
money in the liquidity pool or really whatever trigger that you
want, we can use chain link keepers. To do this. Steven
fluid has done once again, an amazing introduction to chain
the keepers. So we're going to follow along with another sub
video section of Steven explaining chain link keeper
sauce, he's going to be using the COVID test net, but be sure
to use whatever test net is in the documentation. When you play
with this and you try this.
My name is Steven foon. Today, I want to show you how to use the
chain link keeper network in order to automate your contracts
and give them access to off chain computation. Let's go
ahead and dive in. So what we're going to look at today is we're
going to start on the chain link documentation webpage. And if
you just scroll down a little bit, you're going to find using
chain link keepers. Now there's really two parts to building a
chain link keeper up kept smart contract. So the first thing is
you need to write a smart contract that's compatible by
implementing these two methods. And then second, you want to
register that smart contract for upkeep with the channeling
keeper network. So let's go ahead and do both of those
things. So let's start off just by copying and deploying this
sample code that we've got. With this one click to remix, what
we're gonna see here is a very, very simple contract. That is
just a simple counter. So we can see it's got a counter here. So
it's got just a simple number. And then you're able to specify
when you create the contract and update interval, and then the
contract is going to verify Hey, has enough time passed. And if
it has, let's update the counter. And you're going to
notice that chinley compatible or timekeeper network compatible
contracts use two really important methods that are part
of this keeper compatible interface. The first is check
upkeep, and check upkeep is special because this is where
the off chain computation happens. So this is a method
that's not actually run on chain. This is run off chain by
a node from the channeling keeper network. And so what's
really nice about this is that the gas used here isn't actually
gas, it's on chains. This is just being run by a chain link
node. And then what happens is if your check upkeep method
returns, the upkeep is needed. Then it's going to go ahead and
perform upkeep. On chain, so you can actually generate data off
chain, and then pass that in. That's called the check data.
And then that becomes the performed data that's passed
into perform upkeep. And so the PErforM upkeep method is where
you're going to want to verify that things are correct. And
that things actually should be modified and run on chain, and
then actually make the state change. And so let's go ahead
and compile this contract and deploy it to the COVID network.
So let's go ahead and within remix, we can do this
compilation. And we're going to compile and deploy directly to
COVID. So the zookeeper network is currently as of the filming
of this, available on both COVID as well as the theory of main
net. And let's go ahead and play the counter contract. And let's
see what's not updating more than every 30 seconds. And so
let's go ahead and deploy. So meta masks can ask for a little
bit of payment, in order for me to deploy this contract to the
COVID network. And it looks like that is live. So now what I'm
going to do is I'm going to be able to take this keeper
contract, and copy its address. And now we're going to register
that contract for upkeep. So we're going to jump over to the
application that powers the champion keeper network, there's
a few different ways you can use, you can interact directly
with the registry contract. But there's a very, very nice
interface that lets you do this. So let's go ahead and register a
new upkeep and it's giving me an error that says you need to
connect your wallet. So let's go ahead and do that. So I'm going
to just connect wallet here, and I'm gonna give it access to my
account. And then from there, we should actually be able to
register. So I'm going to use an email address here. I'll give my
contract a simple name. I'll paste in that address from the
deployed contract, and then I'll give it a gas limit. And then
check data is this special thing where you can actually register
multiple upkeeps On the same contract in passing data to
specify how you want checkup keep to be run of, we're just
going to ignore that that is an optional one. And then we'll
give it a starting balance of around 10 link, it's gonna go
ahead and use Metamask again to register that transaction on the
network. And once it's confirmed, my upkeep should be
registered with the network and funded with 10 Link To kick
things off. Alright, if we go ahead and view the upkeep, we
can see it's registered. And as soon as the next round of the
keeper nodes executes, which should be roughly about every
block, we should see that the check upkeep method is going to
return that hey, upkeep is actually needed because the
timestamp is more than 30 seconds ago. And then we should
go ahead and perform upkeep. So as soon as I take a look at this
in remix, I can actually make this bigger here, we're going to
be able to see from the methods of the contract, if we check the
counter, it's going to start at zero. And as soon as that 30
seconds has passed, we'll be able to hit the counter again,
we'll see that the channeling keeper network has performed
upkeep on my contract. Alright, we just refresh and we see the
balance of the upkeep has been decreased by about point 01
link. And we should also see within our contract that our
counter has now updated via proof that perform upkeep method
call. And now our counter is at one showing us that our contract
is being approved by the chainlink keeper network. And
everything is working exactly as we expect. So as you can see, it
is very, very easy to create a contract that is compatible with
the keeper network. And it's very easy to register that
upkeep and start seeing that your contract automation and
option computation are working flawlessly.
Now that we've learned a little bit more about how chainlink
keepers work if you want to take some time to go through the
documentation and open up way down below this open and remix
button. So you can actually work with one of these and see these
in action for yourself on a test net, feel free to do so we're
gonna be using a setup very similar to this keepers counter
setup in the chain link documentation.