So now let's update our code so that this request random numbers automatically happens using chain link keepers.
现在让我们来更新代码，使用 "Chainlink keepers" 自动执行这个 "requestRandomWinner"
And if we look at the example contract can actually read more about what's really important for this to work.
如果我们看一下这个示例合约，就可以更多地了解对于这项工作来说真正重要的事情
And we need a check upkeep and a perform upkeep function in our code.
我们需要在代码中实现一个 "checkUpkeep" 和一个 "performUpkeep" 函数
So instead of request random winner, this is going to be the PErforM upkeep that we're going to change.
所以我们不再是使用 "requestRandomWinner" 而是需要把它改成 "performUpkeep"
But first let's make this check upkeep
但首先要做的还是创建 "checkUpkeep"
checkup keep function is basically going to be checking to see is it time for us to get a random number to update the recent winner and to send them all the funds.
"checkUpkeep" 函数就是用来查看是否到了我们该获取随机数，更新最近优胜者，以及给他们打钱的时间了
So let's go ahead and make that function.
让我们来创建一下这个函数
I'm going to add some notes here, just so that it's clear what's going on.
我会在这里添加一些注释，这样可以清晰地说明这里正在发生些什么
And maybe I'll even do natspec To tell developers what's going on with this function.
我甚至可能会使用 "Natspec" (“自然语言规范”)来告诉开发者们这个函数的功能是什么
So we're going to create this function check upkeep.
所以我们来创建这个函数 `function checkUpkeep()`
And if we look at what this needs, it needs to be external override
并且我们可以看一下它需要哪些关键字，它需要的是 "external override"
external override.
`external override`
And if we see this override keyword, this means that okay, there's probably a perform upkeep somewhere else.
我们看一下这个 "override" 关键字，它的意思是可能其它地方还会有一个 "performUpkeep" 方法
And if we scroll to the top, and we're going to import this keeper compatible interface,
我们拉到顶部，这个地方会导入这个 "KeeperCompatibleInterface"
so that we make sure that we implement both check upkeep and perform upkeep in our code here.
这样我们可以确保代码会实现 "checkUpkeep" 以及 "performUpkeep" 这两个方法
If you want you can just import keeper compatible in here or just the keeper compatible interface
如果你想的话，你可以只导入 "KeeperCompatible" 或是直接使用 "KeeperCompatibleInterface"
in our code. We're going to do
在我们的代码中，我们的做法是
import at chain link slash contracts slash SRC slash V 0.8 point two interfaces slash keeper compatible interface that soul
`import "@chainlink/contracts/src/v0.8.interfaces/KeeperCompatibleInterface.sol"
and now we're just gonna say contract raffle is Veera of consumer base V two and keeper compatible interface
现在我们的合约 "Raffle" 就是 "VRFConsumerBaseV2" 以及 "KeeperCompatibleInterface"
and this keeper compatible interface inheritance just make sure that we add checkup keep and perform upkeep,
继承这个 "KeeperCompatibleInterface" 只是为了确保我们添加的有 "checkUpkeep" 以及 "performUpkeep"
which we're going to add in a little bit.
稍后我们再自行添加
And if we look back at the docs we can see checkup keep takes a bytes called Data check data as an input parameter.
我们回来看一下文档，可以发现 "checkUpkeep" 接收一个 "bytes calldata checkData" 作为输入参数
So we'll do bytes called data. Check data as a parameter.
Now this check upkeep bytes call data allows us
to specify really anything that we want when we call this check
upkeep function. Having this check data be of type bytes
means that we can even specify this to call other functions,
there's a lot of advanced things you can do by just having an
input parameter as type of bytes for us though, we're going to
keep it a little bit simple. And we're actually not going to use
this check data piece. So similar to how below we're not
using Request ID, we can just comment it out. However, we
still need to make sure that this parameter is type of bytes
called data. Now anyways, let's go ahead and annotate this check
upkeep function, we'll say this is the function that the chain
link keeper nodes call they look for the to return true. Look
back at the documentation, we can see that this check upkeep
returns both and upkeep needed and to perform data, which
again, we're going to ignore this upkeep needed is going to
be true or false. If it's true, that means it's time to get a
new random number following should be true in order to
return true. So in order for it to be time to request a random
winner, what should happen, our time interval should have
passed, which we haven't defined yet. But we will lottery should
have at least one player and have some eath. And then our
subscription is funded with Link similar to how with channeling
Vir f your subscription needs to be funded with Link, the same
thing needs to happen for check upkeep and keepers to run your
subscription needs to be funded with link. Now we're going to
add one more additional piece here, we're going to say for the
lottery should be in an open state, something that we want to
avoid when we're waiting for a random number to return. And
when we've requested a random winner. We're technically in
this weird limbo state where we're waiting for a random
number to be returned. And we really shouldn't allow any new
players to join. So what we actually want to do is create
some state variable telling us whether the lottery is open or
not. And while we're waiting for our random number to get back,
we'll be in a closed or a calculating state.