Now what we could do at the top of our contract, we can just say
Boolean, private, s underscore is open. And we can just set
this to true if we're open otherwise false. Well, what if
we have a ton of different states? What if we want it to be
like pending, open, closed, calculating, etc? What do we
have a ton of different states? Well, we could make this a U and
256. Private s underscore state. And we could just keep track of
the state having like zero b pending a one reopen to be
closed, three, be calculating, etc. But this can be a little
tricky to keep track of. So a better way to actually keep
track of all this in our code is to use an enum enums, can be
used to create custom types with a finite set of constant values.
So we can create, for example, a state created locked inactive,
and it's basically a new type for a smart contract for us,
we're going to create a new type. And if we go back to the
layout of variables, and our smart contract types should
actually be first thing in our contract. So we're going to
create an E new called raffle state. And for now, and we're
just going to have it be open, we're just gonna have to be open
or calculating. Now when we create an enum like this, we're
kind of secretly creating a un 256, where zero equals open, and
one equals calculating. However, this is much more explicit that
we know what each one of these numbers actually means. Now that
we've created this new type called raffle state, we can
create a new lottery state variable of type raffle state.
So the exact same way we declare any other variable, we'll name
its type, which is going to be raffle state. And this is going
to be a storage variable. So we'll go ahead and do private s
underscore raffle state in our constructor, right when we
launched this contract, we should open up this raffle. So
we'll say s, raffle state equals and we could use a un 256.
Wrapped in type raffle state like so. Or we can be more
explicit and say raffle state DOT open. Now we know that the
raffle state is in an open state and we only want checkup keep to
work is if the lottery is actually open. Additionally, we
probably only want people to be able to enter if the law
battery's open. So let's go ahead and create another if
statement and revert if the lottery isn't open. So we can
say if s underscore raffle state does not equal raffle state DOT
open, then we're going to revert with a new error, we're going to
create raffle underscore underscore, not open. And of
course, at the top will create error, raffle not open. Now
additionally, let's go down when we're requesting a random word.
Let's update the state to be calculating so other people
can't jump in here. So right above our VRF coordinator dot
request, random words will do s underscore raffle state equals
raffle state DOT calculating so that nobody can enter our
lottery and nobody can trigger a new update. And then once we
fulfill after we pick our winner, we'll say s raffle state
equals raffle state DOT open again.