Something else that we
forgot to do was after we pick a winner from s players, we need
to reset our players array. So let's add that in here as well
as players equals new address payable. array of size zero. So
we'll reset the raffle state. And we'll reset our players
array. Alright, great. So now that we've learned about enum,
let's add it to our checkup keep here, we're going to check these
four things. And if they all pass checkup keys will be true
and will trigger the chain the keepers to request a new random
winner. So first, we'll say bool is open. It's going to be equal
to raffle state. That open equals equals s underscore
raffle state. So you can think of that as this boolean is open
is going to be true if raffle state is in an open state, and
it will be false if raffle state is in any other state. So great.
We haven't is open Boolean that we can check later on. What else
do we need? Well, we need to check to make sure our time
interval is past well, we don't have a time interval yet. So
let's create a time interval. In order to check the time we can
use another one a solidity is globally available variables
with block dot timestamp block that timestamp returns the
current timestamp of the blockchain to get the current
timestamp, we're gonna need block dot timestamp. But to get
if enough time has passed, we're going to need to get the current
block dot timestamp minus the last block timestamp, which we
don't have yet. Let's go ahead and create a state variable to
keep track of the previous block timestamp. So this is going to
be a new state variable that we're going to make. I'm gonna
say u and 256. Private s underscore last timestamp.
And right when we deploy this contract, we'll update this with
the current timestamp s last timestamp equals block dot
timestamp. Alright, awesome. Now we have a last block timestamp.
But we're going to need to check that the difference between the
current timestamp and the last timestamp is greater than some
interval. So we also need to create an interval. And this is
going to be some interval, this is going to be some number in
seconds of how long we want to wait between lottery runs. So
let's go ahead and add this to our constructor as well. And do
a comma here. And we'll do u and 256. Interval. And we're going
to create another global variable u and 256 Private s
underscore interval. And in our constructor and we'll say s
interval equals interval. Now interval isn't going to change
after we set it. So instead of making a storage variable, let's
make it an immutable variable to save some gas. Okay, perfect.
Now that we have all this, I'm actually create a boolean to
check to see if enough time has passed. So we'll say Boolean
time passed equals the current block that timestamp minus s
underscore last timestamp. And we should check to see that this
is actually greater than I underscore interval. So we have
a Boolean check to see if we're open. It'll be true if we're
open and we'll have a boolean to see if enough time has passed.
This will be true if enough time has passed. What else should we
check? While we should check to see if we have enough players.
So we'll do Boolean has players equals and we'll check to see if
s underscore players dot length is greater than zero. If s
players dot length is greater than zero as players will be
true, otherwise it'll be false. And we'll also see if we have a
balance so we'll do Boolean has balance equals address. This dot
balance is greater than zero. Then finally, we're going to
take all these booleans and turn them into the return variable
that we're looking for. We're gonna say Boolean up keep
needed. Equals is open and time passed. And as players and as
balance, like that, so all these combined is gonna be this
Boolean upkeep needed. And if this returns true, it's time to
request a new random number and it's time to end the lottery. If
this is false, it's not time yet, it's not time to end the
lottery up. Now again, if we go to the chainlink, documentation
upkeep needed, actually needs to return that Boolean upkeep
needed and some bytes memory perform data. So we need to
update we need to update our function here. And say returns
full upkeep needed, comma, bytes memory, perform data star slash.
And since we've initialized Boolean up, keep needed up here,
we don't need to say what type of upkeep needed is down here.
Since this will automatically get returned performed data is
something that we can use. If we want to have checkup, keep do
some other stuff. Depending on how this checkup keep went. We
don't really need it to do anything else. So we can just
leave it as such. Right. So now we have a check upkeep, we have
a way to check to see if it's time to trigger picking our
random winner of our lottery
or our raffle.