Let's add a little bit of natspec to make this look even
more professional and and give people who are reading our
contract even more information. So let's add title here at title
and we'll say a sample raffle contract will say an author is
going to be me Patrick Collins or you can put your own name
there as well at notice. This contract is for creating and
untampered orrible decentralized smart contract. And then we'll
do add Dev, this implements chain link VRF v two, and chain
link keepers. Alright, awesome. We've got our type declarations,
we've got our state variables, we've got lottery variables,
which are still state variables, we've got our events. Now it's
time for our functions. Afterwards, we've done a little
bit of natspec, at least on our check upkeep. If you want to add
some more natspec on things like enter, raffle, perform upkeep,
etc, you can absolutely do so. And then down at the bottom, we
have our views slash pure getter functions. Let's see, do we want
any other getter functions here? Well, we probably want to give
people the chance to get a raffle state. So we'll do
function, get raffle state, this will be a public, you returns a
raffle state. We'll say return s underscore raffle state, we
probably want to give people the chance to get the number of
words. And this is going to be a little bit interesting here
running. So if we do function, get num words, public view
returns, you went to the six return num words, you'll see
something interesting happened here. We pull up our compiler
and run hh compile. Hopefully everything works here. Oh, and
everything doesn't work because I didn't import this correctly.
Let's fix that. Let's try again.
Oh, there's a couple things I missed. Let's fix es players.
This is why it's good to compile as you code as players dot
length. Let's try again. And I spelt interval wrong. I
underscore inter vol strike to compile again, see how many more
spelling mistakes I made. And there it is. I underscore in
error go to paste that and we do get another error here. Invalid
type for argument in a function call invalid implicit conversion
from literal string to bytes called data requested. Since
we're passing this empty string here. And checkup keep needs a
call data called data actually doesn't work with strings. So we
need to make this bytes memory instead. And our compiler is now
happy with us. And I spell it the timestamp wrong. That's a
lowercase s so and you might see some squiggles here on Check
upkeep, we could make this a view function since we're not
actually modifying any state. But I want to keep it public for
reasons I'll show you a little bit later. But finally we get
the the yellow squiggly that I was looking for here. And if we
run hh compile, we should see a warning in our compiler as well.
Okay, so we see all those yellow squigglies here. Unnamed return
variable can remain unassigned. We need this bytes memory in
here because that's what the keepers are looking for. Morning
function state mutability can be restricted to view for our
function checkup key. You can make a view if you want, but I'm
going to keep it public for reasons I'll show you a little
bit later. And finally, function state mutability can be
restricted to pure this is what I wanted to show you since num
words is actually in the bytecode, since it's a constant
variable technically isn't reading from storage, and
therefore this can be a pure function. Returning num words
doesn't actually read in storage, it literally will go
and read the number one. So doing get num words in solidity
with num words being a constant variable, it's going to
literally be the exact same as saying get one and we would
return one here, we might also want to get the number of
players. So we'll create a function get number of players.
And this will be a public view, returns a un 256. Turn s
underscore players dot length. We're also probably going to
want the latest timestamp. So we'll do function get latest
timestamp. public view returns you in 256. And we're just going
to return s underscore last timestamp. And maybe we'll want
to do request confirmation. So we'll do function GET request
confirmations. Public pure since request confirmations is also a
constant function returns you went to you went to 56 Turn
request confirmations. All right, we've got some wonderful
getters here. Some views slash pure functions, we have a way to
get a random number we have a way in a decentralized context.
Automatic automatically execute. picking a random winner we have
a way for people to enter our raffle to enter this lottery.
And we have a bullet proof way to solve creating a truly fair
decentralized lottery. Oh my goodness. Let's do one more
compile for good measure H H compile. And these are just
warnings. So we're good to go here. Our code is compiling
successfully.