Like I said Normally, this definitely isn't going to be the way that you're going to write your smart contracts,
就像我说过的，通常来说，这并不是你编写智能合约该用的方式
it's almost impossible to write a full smart contract without making any mistakes. And without flipping back and forth between documentation,
你几乎不太可能在不参考文档而且不犯任何错误的前提下直接写完一份完整的智能合约
I have already written this contract many times myself, and I still made a whole bunch of mistakes.
我自己已经多次编写过这个合约了，然而我仍然会犯很多错误
So it is totally reasonable and totally rational for anybody and everybody to make mistakes going through this.
所以对任何人来说，在这个过程中出错都是完全可以理解的
And to use resources and to write tests along the way.
同样的，在这个过程中参考资源，编写测试也是很合理的
Now that we have our raffle dot Seoul created,
现在我们已经把 "Raffle.sol" 写完了
it's time to add everything else.
是时候添加其他内容了
So we're going to come over here, we're gonna create a new folder, and add our deploy folder per usual.
所以我们来到这边，新建一个文件夹，也就是我们通常会添加的 "deploy" 文件夹
And we're going to do exactly what we've already done a couple of times,
而且做法就和我们之前几次完全一样
we're going to create some scripts to deploy our raffle contract.
我们要创建一些脚本来部署我们的 "Raffle" 合约
Now with our raffle contract, there's a couple of things in here that we want to make note of
现在，关于我们的 "Raffle" 合约，有几点需要注意的地方
first thing is that our constructor right now is absolutely massive.
首先是，我们的构造函数现在真的是挺大的了
There are a ton of parameters in here that we need to account for.
这里有许多参数需要我们去考虑
Let's take a look at our constructors and see if there's any contracts that we're already interacting with.
让我们来看一下我们的构造函数，看看是否有我们已经正在交互的合约
Okay, VRF, coordinator v2. This is a contract address,
OK，"VRFCoordinatorV2"，这是一个合约地址
entrance fee, no gasline, no subscription ID no callback, guestimate No, and interval. No.
"entranceFee" 不是，"gasLane" 不是，"subscriptionId" 不是，"callbackGasLimit" 不是，以及 "interval" 也不是
So knowing that this is an address should be a tip that Ah,
那么，知道这是一个地址也就意味着有这么一个提示
okay, we're probably going to need to deploy some mocks. For this,
啊，我们很可能需要为它部署一些 "mock"
since we're going to need to interact with a VRF coordinator contract that's outside of our project.
因为我们要交互的 "vrfCoordinator" 合约来自于我们的外部项目
But let's go ahead and start working on our raffle deployment script
现在让我们开始编写我们的 "Raffle" 部署脚本
first, and we know we're going to have to deploy some mocks. So we'll just keep that in mind.
首先我们知道要部署一些 "mock"，我们要记住这一点
So let's create a new
file. Oh, one, deploy raffle.js. And let's get started deploying
our raffle contract. Now, this is going to look really similar
to what we've done before. And we're going to do it again here.
If you want to use your previous deploy scripts as a reference, I
absolutely recommend you do so. But let's get started with
module that exports equals an async function. That's going to
take get named accounts and deployments. As input
parameters, then we're going to do const. Deploy log equals
deployments, then we're gonna say const, Deployer, equals
await, get named accounts. Let's go to our config and update
module that exports to to have this I'm just going to copy
paste, so that employer is going to be defaulted to account zero
and player is going to be defaulted to account one, if you
want to go ahead and write this out, feel free to pause and
write out your name accounts. Right now, there's gonna be a
lot of boilerplate in our heart hat.config.js. So feel free to
have the GitHub repo for this lesson up with you or your
previous scripts that you've already written as a reference
named accounts Deployer. And we're also going to have a
player named account so that we can separate different users or
different players who are interacting with our contracts.
But for now, we're gonna grab our Deployer. And we're gonna
get started. Now similar to last time, we would just do const,
raffle equals await ploy, raffle, comma, and then add all
of our stuff in here, right? So this would be from Deployer.
args, we're going to have a ton of args. So we're going to come
back to this. And then log is going to be true. And then we're
going to have wait confirmations, there's a little
bit more boilerplate we need to work with here in our Hardhead
config, we don't have a network here. So let's add our network
information. So we can get those block confirmations will be
specific in here, as well. And we'll say default network is
going to be hard hat. And then we'll say
networks, and we'll add our network information that's going
to be working with heart hub, which has a chain ID of 31337
miles, we'll put that in here as well. And block confirmations
were just set to one lot this column here, we're also gonna be
running some staging tests on the Rinkeby network. So we'll
add rink B in here with a chain ID of four, block confirmations
of six, and we need to add a URL and then also some accounts for
our URL. We've done this 100 times. We'll do const. rinky
dink could be RPC URL equals process study and v dot rake,
the RPC URL, that's private key, blah, blah, blah, we're going to
add all these same variables from our last projects. So I'm
going to ask you to pause here and just copy paste all those
variables from our last project. Boom, like so since running
rink, prpc, URL, private key corn market cap and ether scan,
we're also going to want to make sure you folder, excuse me, new
file, dot env. And we're going to drop all of our information
in here our rink, prpc, URL, private key, ether scan API key,
and then our coin market cap API key as well. Now that we have
our private key or ring prpc URL down in URL, B RPC URL, and for
accounts, we're just going to add that single private key. Now
for weight confirmations is going to equal For network
config dot block con formations, or one, we're gonna have to
import network from Hardhead, which looks like my VS code
automatically did for me. Thanks VS code. So this is how we're
going to deploy a raffle. Obviously, we have a ton of
arguments that we need to account for. So let's get to it.
Let's look at our raffle constructor to see what we need
to get. Okay, well, the first thing that we need to get via of
coordinator v2, we're gonna use the same strategy we used in our
Funmi project with using mocks, if we're on a development chain,
and using the actual contract address if we're on a test net,
or a live network, so let's get to it. So let's go ahead,
recreate that helper, hard hat config dot j s and create that
const. Network. Config, say it equals for hard hat, we're going
to use a mock. So we don't need to put that in here for now. But
for rink B, let's go ahead, but a foreign here, so the name is
going to be Rinkeby. And we're going to need to go to the chain
link documentation, the VRF contracts, and we're going to
need to grab the RF coordinator for the Rinkeby. Test net, we're
going to grab this address here, plop it in here, we'll say V RF
core did an eight tour v two, bam, right like that. So back in
our deploy raffle, we're gonna have to pick whether or not to
use the V RF coordinator v two in the network config or some
mock that we deployed, which of course, leads us to us having to
deploy a mock, let's create the new file 00. Deploy marks.js. So
same thing module that exports equals async function where it's
taking, get named accounts, and deployments, as its input
variables from the heart at runtime environment, or do const
deploy COMM A log equals deployments. And then const,
Deployer equals await, get named accounts, Excel, and then we're
going to grab the chain ID as well as we're going to only
wants to deploy this on a development chain. So we'll do
const chain ID equals network dot config dot chain ID. Now
we're going to only want to deploy mocks, if we're on a
development chain. So once again, we're going to go to our
helper config, we're going to add those development chains in
here. We'll say const, development chains equals hard
hat, and localhost. And then we're gonna want to export both
of these. So module, dot exports, equals network config,
and development chance. Now in our deploy mocks, we're gonna
want to grab those are saying const development chains, equals
require dot dot slash helper helper hardhat config. Now we
can check to see if development chains dot includes the network
dot name that we're currently on. If we're in a development
chain, we're gonna go ahead and log local network, the
protected, deploying box. And now we'll have to deploy a mock
VRF coordinator, where do we get a mock VRF to coordinator Well,
let's go ahead and create one of those.