We go to the chainlink. GitHub again, we go to contracts. So C 0.8,
我们再一次来到 Chainlink 的 GitHub，前往 "/contracts/src/v0.8/"
actually have a mocks folder with VF coordinator v2 Mach dot Sol,
这里有一个 "mocks" 文件夹，里面有一个 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock.sol"
and we're just going to use this as our mock.
我们就用它来作为我们的 "mock"
So in our contracts folder, we're gonna create a new file called test
所以在我们的 "contracts" 文件夹里，我们要创建一个新的文件，名为 "test"
（实际上应为创建一个新的文件夹，名为 "test"）
new file called V RF core, in a core, the two mock dot Sol,
再新建一个文件，名为 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock.sol"
and we're just going to import this mock and have it be our mock.
然后我们直接导入这个 "Mock" 作为我们的 "mock"
So we'll do spdx.
我们先写下 `SPDX`
We'll do pragma, solidity, carrot zero, point 8.0, or seven or whatever we want to do,
再写下 `pragma solidity ^0.8.0`，或者是 7，或是任何我们想要版本
we'll do import at chainlink slash contracts slash SRC slash v 0.8. Slash, mocks, slash VRF. Pour did a tour B to mock that soul.
接着是 `import @chainlink/contracts/src/v0.8/mocks/VRFCoordinatorV2Mock.sol`
And we'll just check to see if it compiles with Hardhead compile,
我们用 hardhat 编译一下，看它是否能编译通过
and it looks like it's compiling as well. Awesome.
看起来编译过程一切正常，非常好
So now that we have our mock contract, we can actually go ahead and deploy it.
现在我们有了 "mock" 合约，就可以继续进行部署了
So we'll do a weight loi, the RF core de ne Tor V to Mach comma,
这里我们写 `await deploy("VRFCoordinatorV2Mock", )`
and then we'll give it our parameters in here.
然后在这里把我们的参数传递进去
We'll say from Deployer.
我们告诉它 `from: deployer`
Log is going to be true,
`log: true`
and then we're going to do our arguments.
接下来是我们的 `args`
Now, what are the arguments of this VRF
coordinator, v2 Mk. Well, if we open the VRF coordinator v2
Mock, right in our VS code, or on GitHub, we can actually see
We will roll over to the constructor that it takes two
things. It takes a base fee and a gas price link. What are these
first one? Well, the first one is this const base fee. If we go
back to the documentation, we can see that there's this
premium section of 0.25 Link rink B, this means that for each
request, there's a base fee of 0.25 link for every request. So
anytime we want to request a random number on Rinckey, it's
going to cost us 0.25. Link, or you can think of it as 0.25
Oracle gas to make this request. So back in our deploy mocks, we
can say base V equals, we could resemble Rinckey here and do 25,
blah, blah, blah, or we could do ethers dot utils dot parse eath,
of 0.25. And I'll even put a little comment here, say 0.25 is
the premium, it costs 0.25 Link per request. And remember, the
reason that this cost 0.25 Link per request versus the price
feeds didn't cost anything is because the price feeds. If we
look back at a chain that link, each one of these price feeds is
being sponsored by a group of protocols who are paying for all
these requests already, since there isn't a sponsor for this,
we are the only ones requesting the randomness, we get to be the
ones to actually sponsor getting this random number, then the
second thing here is going to be the gas price link. So let's
create another const here to const. gas price link. But what
this is, is actually a calculated value is a calculated
value based on the gas price of the chain. Here's an example if
we were to request a random number on Aetherium, and the
eath price skyrocketed up to like to like a billion dollars,
gas would be incredibly, incredibly expensive. Now when
chain link nodes respond chain link nodes pay the gas fees, who
give us randomness, and do external execution, the chain
link nodes are actually the ones that pay the gas when returning
randomness or executing an upkeep or etc. If we go to our
raffle dot soul, and scroll down to perform upkeep, or fulfill
random words, it's actually the chain link nodes that are
calling these two functions and paying the gas for it, they get
paid in Oracle gas to offset those costs. But if the price of
eath, or any native blockchain skyrocketed the chain that nodes
itself to pay the gas fee. So the chain link nodes have a
calculated price have a calculated variable called the
gas price per link, which fluctuates based off the price
of the actual chain, so that they never go bankrupt.
Basically, the price of a request changes based off the
price of gas for that blockchain, you can kind of
think of this as the link per gas, if you will, for now we can
kind of just set it to whatever we want. And we'll just set it
to one e nine, which is going to be equivalent to 1123456789. So
now that we have the base fee, and the gas price link, we'll
grab this base fee, we'll have these be the arguments for our
VR chord, enter V to mock, so we'll say and actually we can
delete that will say const, args equals base fee, and gas price
link, then we can take this args variable and just plop it in
here. Now we can do log mocks deployed, then we can do log
that a little line like this to let people know that this deploy
script is done, then we'll just do a module that exports dot
tags equals all and mocks. So now that we have a view of
coordinator v2 Mock deployed, we'll come back over to our
raffle and make some code around it. Similar to what we just did
with our deploy mocks. We can say if development chains that
includes network dot name, we'll do some stuff. And we need to
import development chains from our helper Hardhead config. And
we need to import network from hard hat. My VS code
automatically added them Wow, thanks VS code. Let's even just
do const args and make this variable down here. Stick it in
args. Our first argument is going to need to be this Vera fi
to coordinator so let's make a variable we'll say let VRF core
need torby to address and if we're on a development chain,
we're going to grab that mock contract. So we'll say const
PRF, Cor de ATAR V to mock equals await ethers dot get
contract, the RF cord the cord to NATO Tor v two MK, and then
we can set the RF coordinator v two address equals VRF core
denater V two mach dot
address.