Cool. We have that address here. Else if we're not
on a local network, the VRF v2 coordinator address is simply
going to be derived from our network config. So let's import
the network config as well from our helper Hardhead config and
we'll say else VRF coordinator v2 address equals network config
of our chain ID. Let's which actually sorry, we do need the
chain ID cons chain ID equals network dot config dot chain ID,
chain ID of VR coordinator V to chain ID. You're a coordinator
v2. Alright, perfect. We've got the setup to work with our VRF
coordinator v2 address. What else do we need from our raffle?
Well, we need an entrance fee, we probably want to change the
entrance fee depending on what chain we're on, we're on a more
expensive chain, we might want to make this higher than others.
So let's go ahead back to our helper Hardhead config and make
an entrance fee based off of the blockchain, so for NP, maybe we
want to make it 0.01 eath. So we could say ethers dot utils,
parse ether of 0.01. And once again, thank you VS code for
automatically dropping that in for me. And we're also going to
want an entrance fee for our heart app, we can also set a
default in here, but let's just be a little more explicit. So
we'll say 31337. The name of this is Art app, we don't need
to give it a veneer of coordinator v2 address because
we're going to deploy a mock. But we do want an entrance fee.
And let's just give it the exact same entrance fee here. So we'll
say ethers dot utils dot parse ether 0.01 E. Alright, great. So
on our deploy here, we can just say const entrance fee equals
network config. Chain ID of entrance fee. Let's start
populating our arcs here. So the first one is going to be your Fe
two coordinator address. Next one is going to be our entrance
fee. Got it? Got it. Now we need our gas lane. On Rigby and other
networks, there are different gas lanes that we can choose
from, let's grab the only gas Lane from Rinckey, the 30, gray
key hash, let's drop this, of course into our network config
as gasoline, pop it in here, we're hard hat, our mock
actually doesn't care what gas line we're working on, because
we're going to be mocking the gasoline anyways. So we can just
say gas lane, we can just go ahead and use the same one or
really anything here, it doesn't really matter. Now here we'll
say const, gasoline equals network config.
Chain ID, gasoline, and we'll grab the gas lane. And we'll
stick it into our argument array, we've got this one, we've
got this one, we've got this one. Now it's time for the
subscription ID. Now if you haven't run through docstoc
chain link for the chain link VRF, I highly recommend you do
so so that you can understand what this subscription ID is we
know that we can actually make a subscription ID using that front
end using that website VRF dot chain dot link, which is great
and all but what if we're on all local chains, we can get a
subscription ID no problem in here. But it's a little bit
harder on a local network. Now I'm actually going to teach you
how to create and fund subscription it is completely
programmatically. So you don't even need to use the UI if you
don't want to. However, for the purpose of this course, we're
still going to use the user interface, we're still going to
use that website for us to get our own subscription IDs. But
you could 100% automate the process of creating a
subscription ID and funding a subscription ID. Because when
you create and fund subscription IDs, you're just calling create
subscription and fund subscription on that smart
contract. So on our development chain, we have our V RF
coordinator v2 Mock, and what we're going to do and on our
development chain, we're going to create that subscription. So
we're gonna say const, transaction, response equals
await VRF coordinator v2 Mock dot create sub scription. And
then we'll run const transaction receipt equals weight trends
action response, dot Wait, wait one block confirmation. And
inside this transaction receipt, there's actually an event that's
emitted with our subscription that we can get this is another
place where emitting events is incredibly helpful. So in fact,
if we open back up a Vera v2 coordinator mark, and we look
for create subscription, we see we emit subscription created
with the subscription ID, we can actually get this event emitted
from our transaction receipt. Now to assign it, let's go ahead
and create a sub subscription ID up here. And then we'll say
subscription ID equals transaction receipt that events
of zero dot args dot sub ID. And again, be sure to watch that
events video if you want to learn more about how to work
with events in hardware. Now that we have a subscription, we
need to fund the subscription on a real network, you'd need the
link token to actually fund the subscription. The current
iteration of the mock allows you to fund a subscription without
the link token. So what we can do is we can just run a wait
your F corps inator Mark, if coordinator B to Mach dot fund
subscription, and we'll give it the subscription ID and we'll
need to do some fundamental this, we can just create some
variable, we'll say const VRF, subscription fund amount equals
ethers dot utils, dot parse ether, of, we'll say 30 VRF
subscription, fundament. We'll just paste that down here. We
could do this as well for a real test net or live networks. But
just so that we become familiar with the user interface, we're
not going to do a test net programmatically. And for a test
net, we're just going to use exactly what we've been doing so
far. Or we can put a subscription ID and our helper
config. So we'll say subscription ID, we'll put
something in here right now, we'll just leave it as zero. But
later on, when we actually create a subscription, we'll
update our subscription ID. And so we'll say subscription ID
equals network config. Change ID of subscription ID. Perfect. Now
we can add this to our arguments array. What else do we need
subscription ID, we need a callback gas limit or callback,
gas limit is going to vary network to network. So once
again, we're gonna go into our helper configure callback gas
limit. And for us, we'll set a pretty high limit of 500,000
gas. So we'll say call a gas limit of 5.123 500,000. Gas. And
for hard hat, we'll do the same thing. So we can say const,
callback, gas limit equals network config, chain ID,
callback, gas limit, grab this, put it into our argument array.
What else do we need? All we need now is the interval. So we
can change this network to network as well. Rigby will say,
interval will ever just be 30 seconds for both hard hat and
for Rigby. So we'll do the same thing here. Say const.
Interval equals network config. Chain ID, interval, and we'll
grab this, pop it in the end of our array. All right, awesome.
Now we have an argument array and drop it right in here and
perfect. Everything in our constructor for our raffle
contract. Great. This is looking fantastic. We've got wait
confirmations we got logging arguments Deployer. Okay, well,
what next? Well, let's go ahead and add that verification piece.
So once again, create a new folder utils, new file
verify.js. We can either copy paste this from our last
project, or we can grab this from the GitHub repo associated
with this course, once we have our verify script in here, we're
going to import it by saying const. Verify equals require dot
dot slash helper Hardhead config. And then we can add that
same bit of code down here to verify our contract, we'll say
if we're not on a development chain. And we have process
studying v dot ether scan API key, then we're going to log
verifying dot dot and then await verify raffle dot address and
the arcs. Now we'll just do a log of a whole bunch of hyphens
say that this script is done module dot exports dot tags
equals say this will be all and raffle. All right, so let's test
this out. We'll do hardhat deploy, or yarn, hard hat deploy
and see if this script works correctly. Looks like we ran
into an error network config not defined. So let's spell this
right. Network config. There we go. And that looks much better.
Let's try this again. It looks like our deploy scripts are
working well. local networks protected, deploying mocks
deployed VRF coordinator v2 Mock mocks deployed and then we went
ahead and deployed our raffle. Awesome, this is massive.