Now
we're not going to test the deploying this to a test net
quite yet, because well, we don't have any unit tests yet.
We need to write unit tests before we want to ever test
running this on a test net. So we have our deploy script, we
have our contracts, that means it's time for us to write some
tests. We'll come over here we'll create a new folder called
test. And for now, we'll just make our unit tests. So unit
tests, and in here we create a new file called raffle.test.js.
And let's write some unit tests. Now for these unit tests, we are
going to be a little bit verbose here, we're going to make our
coverage really, really good here. It's not gonna be perfect,
but this is going to be pretty verbose. So I'm gonna go pretty
quickly here. So you can feel free to pause, slow me down,
speed me up whatever you need to learn this section. It is really
good muscle memory to go through writing these tests and
understand what you should be thinking about when you're
writing these tests. So feel free to speed up the parts You
already know and slow down the new parts. Because we are going
to go over some new information here. writing tests may seem
like a tedious process. But I promise as you get better at
writing these tests, you'll realize that these are the
things that you can rely on when stuff doesn't work. And when
you're not sure how to code, something, getting this muscle
memory down, writing these tests is going to make you a fantastic
engineer. So let's go through and we'll write some of these
verbose tests here to try to make this really good and have
this have really good coverage. And if you want to go back later
on, and see if you can give it even more coverage, and even
better tests, please feel free to do so. But let's get started.
Let's write some tests. So we're going to start out pretty much
the same way we've been starting everything out, we're going to
grab our development chains, so that we only run our unit tests
on a development chain. So we'll do const development chains,
equals require dot dot slash dot dot slash helper, RD, hard hat
config, and then we'll say not development chains, that
includes network dot name, and describe that skip. Otherwise,
we'll do describe, so this first describe is going to be our
raffle unit tests. And this is going to be an async. function.
So raffle unit tests so that it comes on the next line, it looks
a little bit better. Alright, great. Now, what are some of the
main things that we're going to need to deploy? Well, we're
gonna need to deploy a raffle, we're probably going to want a
VRF core to a tour be to mock graded before each, that's going
to be an async function, where we go ahead and we get these
will say const. Employer equals await, get named accounts.
So we're gonna need to import get named accounts or require
get name accounts from hard hat, then we're going to want to
deploy these using our fixtures. So we can say await deployments.
And then we're going to import deployments as well from hardhat
dot fixture, and we're going to call all, we're going to deploy
everything. And again, if we look at our one, our raffle has
the alt tag, and our Oh, our mocks also have the alt tag,
okay, perfect. Once we deploy everything, we can say raffle
equals await ethers dot get to contract. And we got to import
ethers from hard hat, like so. And we'll say it will get the
raffle contract and we'll connect it to our Deployer. And
then we're going to do the same thing with VRF coordinator v2
Mock equals await ethers dot get contract, the RF coordinator, B
to MK connect this to deployer as well. Alright, great, our
first set of tests describe, they're going to be the
constructor. And this is going to be an async function. And
let's do this. Let's create an IT initial initializes the
raffle correctly, this is going to be an async function. Now I
just want to make a note, because ideally, we make our
tests have just one assert, or it just keep that in mind is
that ideally, we want to have just one assert for it. But
we're going to have a bunch because like I said, we're being
a little bit loose here. So we want to just make sure that our
raffle is initialized correctly. So we'll say const raffle state,
and we'll get that raffle state because we want to make sure
that we start in an open raffle state. So we'll say const,
raffle state equals await raffle dot get raffle state. And then
we want to say assert dot equal ope and then we need to import
assert from Chai. So assert equals require Chai assert dot
equal raffle state.to string because again, raffle state is
going to be a big number. And even though a raffle state is of
type raffle state, it'll return a zero if it's open and a one if
it's calculating. So this gets transformed just into a un 256.
When we call it like this, a raffle state variable here will
be a big number. So we want to just to string a file. So assert
dot equal raffle state DOT two string zero. We'll also make
sure our interval gets set correctly. So we'll do const
interval equals await raffle dot get interval. And I don't know
if we have one of those it's actually C inter ball see if we
have one of those. We don't have a good interval let's go ahead
and add again interval function so we'll do function get in
trouble. We have public view returns you went to six return I
underscore interval will have good interval will say raffle
dot get interval and will also say assert dot equal interval.to
string. It should equal one Ever is in our helper config, right?
Because we're using the interval and helper config. So we say
interval.to string should equal. So we'll import that as well.
Network config. And we'll say the interval should equal
network config. Of let's also make, get our chain ID up here,
chain ID, say const. Chain ID equals network dot config, a
chain ID, network config of the chain ID of interval. Alright,
cool. So let's test this so far, HH test or yarn, hard hat test.
And cool looks like it passed. And we have our little gas
output here. Awesome. Let's go to our Hardhead config, just so
that it doesn't always print out at gas, but there for now. So
I'm going to copy paste the gas reporter section from our last
project, like so. And we're going to have enabled gas be
false for now. So now if we run a Hardhead test, again, we
shouldn't have that gas bid printed out, we should just see
the tests and perfect, that's what we see. And our constructor
test passes. Yay, what's next, got our constructor. And we
probably could have written more tests for the rest of these. But
let's just move on. Alright, enter raffle, that's going to be
our next describe block. So it will do describe,
enter, raffle. And this is going to be an async function. And
we'll say it reverts when you don't pay enough, right, because
one of the first things that we check is that they're paying
enough. So we want to make sure that this actually reverts if
they don't pay enough. So this will be an async function. Where
we're going to do that same expect await thing. So we're
going to import expect from Chai, which comes from those
waffle matchers. And we're gonna say await, expect raffle dot
enter a raffle. And we're not going to pass any value here,
we're going to expect it to dot b dot reverted with. And if we
look here, we want it to be reverted with this raffle not
enough eath entered. So we can put that in quotes raffle not
enough eath entered. Now we can try this out. Make sure that it
actually works. Ah ah test dash dash grep. Put this in quotes
that you don't pay enough. And awesome. We're passing there.
What else do we want to test? Well, we want to test that if
the raffle isn't open, we also revert but we'll test that in a
little bit. As we kind of test the rest of the functionality.
We want to see that it records players when they enter. So this
will be an async function. And now we'll enter the raffle.
First we're going to need that raffle entrance fee. Let's go
ahead and save that at the top. So we'll say let raffle VRF
coordinator be to mock raffle entrance fee and then our before
each will say raffle entrance fee equals a weight ethers dot
get entrance fee. This should be raffle dot get entrance fee. So
now we have this raffle entrance fee, you can use it to enter the
raffle we'll say a weight raffle dot enter raffle with a value of
raffle entrance fee. And we can make sure that our Deployer here
has been correctly recorded. So since right now we're connected
to the Deployer. We'll just make sure that that deployer actually
is in our contract. So we'll say const player from contract
equals await raffle dot get player of zero, because we
record them in our players array and we have our get players
function which pulls them out. And then we'll say assert dot
equal player, player from contract should be the Deployer.
So now we can grep for this in our hard head test. Make sure
this works. HH test dash dash grep. Deployer is not defined.
We've got it up here. But we actually didn't save it
globally. So we got to do let common Deployer. And we'll say
deployer equals await get named accounts. And we'll wrap it like
this to get the deployer Awesome. Let's try this again.
And awesome. What else should this do?