a raffle dot once this needs to be an async
function, not just a regular function. Let's try that one
more time, get latest timestamp is the correct function. So
let's update this with the correct latest. Let's put latest
in there. Because I'm spelling something's wrong. I sure am
looks like we're printing out recent winner here when we
haven't even initialized it. So let's move it up. And then we'll
do console dot log recent winner. So I know this is a
massive test here. But let's give it a try and see if
everything kind of does what we think it should do. And it's
slowing down here, which is good because we're doing a lot of
stuff. And uh huh, we finally get this passing thing to come
out. And we did a ton of console dot logging so so there's a lot
of stuff in here of the signers are getting printed out. So
let's just make this a little easier to read. We'll add dot
address to all these, we can see who the winner is. So it looks
like the winner is going to be account number one, which is
great. So what we can do now that we know account number one
is going to be the winner, we can get that winners starting
balance way down here before we call fulfill random words. So
we'll say const winner, starting balance equals await accounts
one dot get balance, yes, you can just call get balance right
like that. And now that we have the winner starting balance back
in our tests, we can say const winner, ending balance equals
await ounce one dot get balance. And we can make sure that this
winner got paid what they need. So now we're going to do a big
assert with some money stuff, just trust me, this is what the
math is. So we're going to do assert dot equal winner
balance.to string,
excuse me winter ending balance.to string should equal
the winner starting balance dot add the raffle entrance fee that
multiplied by the additional and trance that add the raffle
entrance fee that we paid.to string. So this math is
basically saying the winner should end with a balance of all
of the money that everybody else added to this contract. And
that's it. So we can run this test one more time. And Gosh,
darn it, it passed. Okay, so there was a lot of code here.
And this might have been one of the hardest pieces of this
entire course is going to be this part right here. So if you
struggled a little bit with this, don't let that bog you
down. This is probably one of the more difficult sections of
this course, let's do a quick refresher of just this test that
we're doing. And then we'll see in an action when we do it. In
our staging test. What we did is we're picking a winner resetting
the lottery and we're sending money. Basically what we're
doing is we're testing that this fulfill random words thing does
what we want it to do a random winner wins and they get the
money. So how do we actually do that? Well, we first started off
by having a bunch of random people enter the lottery. Great.
Sounds good. Now what we wanted to do was we want to call
perform upkeep and fulfill random words, we want to pretend
that the random number was drawn. And that's what this code
down here does is it calls that random number but and what we
could have done was we could have had all these assert and
checked all the variables. After we did this, right. We could
have totally done that. However, on a test net where we don't
always know exactly when a transaction is going to finish.
We have to wait If we have to listen for an event to be fired,
before, we could call the transactions that would end this
whole thing, we needed to set something up to listen for that
event to be fired. And we said, hey, only once this event is
fired only once this transaction is called, can we do our testing
now for our local network, we are mocking the VRF
coordinators, we have control, we know exactly when this is
going to run. But on a test net, we don't. So you'll see in our
staging tests, we won't have any of this here. And we'll have to
rely on setting up a listener to listen for the channeling VRF
and the keepers to fire their events. And that's why the
staging test is going to be so important to make sure that
we're doing everything correct. And that's why we set up our
local tests like this, so that it mimics what we're going to be
doing on our statement test what we're going to be doing on a
real network here. And again, we're setting up this listener
and we're saying, Ah, once we do here, this event, then we're
going to try to actually check all of the balances and check
that everything is working as intended. And if we don't see
it, we're going to reject. And if there's a timeout, if it
takes more than 200 seconds, we're going to say okay,
something went wrong, we're going to cancel it. And
actually, I'm going to bump this up to 300 seconds, because I
think 200 seconds is not going to be enough. And depending on
how quick the rink B test that is, you might have to bump this
up even bigger. So just keep that in mind.