Let's try our staging test out from start to finish.
So now in order for us to test this staging test, from end to
end, you first going to need to get our sub ID for the
channeling fear F then we're going to need to deploy our
contract using the sub ID, we're going to need to register the
contract with chain link VRF. And it's somebody we're going to
then need to register it with chain link keepers. And then of
course, we're going to run the staging tests. So let's do it.
So first thing we're going to need to do is what? Get our sub
ID for chain link VRF. Okay, great. So we're going to come
over to VRF dot chain dot link. And we're going to need to
create a new subscription. If we don't have enough rink B eath.
Let's we want to head over to the full blockchain solidity
course, here, we're going to scroll down. And we're going to
look for the recommended test and here, which is ranked v. And
we're going to use the faucets link to get some Rigby link, run
Fosses dot chain dot link, let's switch over from COVID to a
cerium. Rigby, we know we're going to need some link and some
eath. So let's just go ahead and get both. Alright, great now
that our transaction has gone through, let's just double check
our wallet here. And it looks like we do indeed have Ethereum
here. And if you don't see the link, you can head over to link
token contracts, Link token contracts in the chain link
documentation. We'll scroll down to Rigby, we'll grab this
contract address import tokens and we'll paste it in here. Add
Custom tokens, import tokens. Great. Now I can see my eath and
my link here, perfect. We have some eath we have some link,
let's head over to V REF subscription management. And
we're going to create a new subscription. Again, we could
totally do this programmatically, because the
user interface here is only helping us facilitate call
contracts to the registration contract that's completely
decentralized and on chain. So let's go ahead and create
subscription will create subscription will confirm the
transaction and Metamask on the Rinkeby network will do a little
bit of wading in great once it's gone through, you can go ahead
and click the add funds button. I'm going to show you what it
looks like if you accidentally refresh and jump off though. So
if you refresh and you go back to veer off the chain dot link,
you should have a new active subscription. And you'll see
this number here. If you click on it, this is your subscription
ID great. So we can actually take this, come back to our code
into our helper Hardhead config. And we can paste our
subscription ID under subscription ID for our Rinkeby
network here. Awesome. Now that we have a subscription we can
see it's not funded with any link. So we don't have any
Oracle gas here. And we don't have any consumers. Right our
consumer is going to be a raffle or a lottery contract. So let's
add some funds first and we don't need to add A whole lot
because we're only going to be testing once. So let's go just
go ahead and add to link here, this number might change
depending on different costs of the test nets and how much link
token there's available. So if you're actually working on a
main net, be sure to head over Doc's touching that link EVM
chains contract addresses, you can read more about the costs
some of these different chains, so you can figure out exactly
how much to put in here. And if you go to the full blockchain
solidity course, Jas, we can scroll down to Lesson Nine,
there's a recommended link amounts or rinky saving tests
for chain link VRF. For now we're going to put two for
keepers, we're going to put eight, but feel free to refer to
here so you know how much to put in. So let's go ahead and
confirm, we're going to approve adding funds here, go ahead and
confirm. And we're now funding our subscription to so we can
pay that Oracle gas to get our random numbers. Great. And once
we're funded, we can close it, we'll do a little refresh. And
we can see the balance is now to link when we don't have any
consumers perfect. So we've got our sub ID, we funded it. Now
let's go ahead and deploy our contract. And we already know
that we should be all good for deploying our contract, we go to
our Dotty and V will need to add all of those same parameters
from our previous projects, we'll need to shrink the RPC
URL, we'll need our private key. If we want to verify we'll need
our ether scan API key. And if we want to do gas output, we'll
need our coin market cap API key. So let's make sure we have
all that. And we'll look at our deploy script. Once again, just
real quick look at our helper hardcat config just real quick,
and it looks like we do indeed have everything in here. And we
should just be able to deploy it in one command.
So we should be able to do yarn, hard hat or just h h again,
ploy, dash dash network Rinkeby. Let's go try this out. All
right, it looks like we've compiled successfully, we've
deployed it successfully. And we've even verified it, we can
go and open it up on Rinku ether scan. And we can see our code
here has been verified. And it's looking beautiful. We can read
from it, which is great. We can see all these commands here now
that it's verified. And if we look at the Git raffle state, we
should indeed see that it's open, right, and it's going to
stay open until somebody ends the raffle and updates the
amount of eath that the contract actually has. Now that we've
deployed a contract using that sub ID, we need to register the
contract with chain link V REF. And with chain link keepers. So
we need to add this consumer does tell chinley VRF. Hey, this
is the contract that you're looking for now. So we're gonna
go back to V REF dot chain dot link, and we're going to grab
this contract address, and we're going to add it as a consumer,
your subscription is ready, you can now add consumers we're
gonna add consumer. And again, this website is just here to
help facilitate us interacting with the contract. So we're
going to approve that user, we'll go ahead and confirm and
the transaction is going through. While we wait for this
to go through, we can go to keepers dot chain dot link, and
do the same thing work with the user interface to register a new
upkeep. So we'll go ahead and add our email Hardhead free code
camp@gmail.com. We'll call this raffle upkeep. We'll paste our
upkeep address in here we have our admin address, and you can
ignore this bit right here. For gas limit, this is going to be
the gas limit of the PErforM upkeep function. If we did our
gas estimator, we could just check to see how much that
perform upkeep costs. But for now, I'm just going to put
500,000 That's probably overkill, but that's fine. Check
data, we're going to keep blank because again, our checkup keep
doesn't take anything. And then starting balance, we're going to
put as eight. And if you forget to put a starting balance here,
you can always find it later. So let's go ahead and register,
we're gonna get a Metamask pop up, we're gonna go ahead and hit
Confirm. And we can go back to our VRF and see that it's indeed
been added and awesome, we now have a consumer on our VRF. So
now let's just wait for our keepers to go through upkeep
registration requests submitted successfully on domain net, you
might actually have to wait a little bit for your request to
go through, but I'll test that it should automatically go
through. Now if we go back to keepers dot chain dot link, we
should now see we now if we scroll down to my upkeeps We
have a raffle upkeep here and I have to because I accidentally
use the same account that I tested on, you can ignore the
two you'll have one but this is the one that we just created.
And we can actually see what our balances and then what the
minimum balance for this actually is. So it looks like
eight Link was a little bit too low. So let's go back to Fosses
dot chain dot link slash rinky. Now that we have some more link,
we can come back to our raffle upkeep. And we go ahead and hit
add funds. And we'll add just three. And we'll go ahead and
confirm we first need to give permission to spend. We approved
our link transfer now let's actually transfer the link to
the contract and alright funds added successfully. So now let's
do a little refresh. Now we no longer see that message saying
that it's underfunded and we have our balance and we can see
that it's more than the minimum balance. We have See the history
that we just funded this twice. Once this actually kicks off,
we'll see activity type will be like perform upkeep or something
got our sub ID, we've deployed the contract, we've registered
with chain link V REF, we've registered it with chain link
keepers. Now all we need to do is run the staging tests. Now
running our staging test is essentially going to be the same
as us calling this enter script, right, because all we're doing
in our staging test is entering the lottery. And then we just
have a whole bunch of validators that we're running to make sure
that things are doing as we expect, since our contract is
actually verified, what we could do on Rigby ether scan is we can
actually go to this right contract section of the
contract. And we could even connect our wallets to it. And
once this turns from red to green, after a little refresh,
we'll now see that it's green, it's connected, we can even call
functions on this contract ourself, so we could enter the
raffle ourself, we would add, you know, however much eath to
enter the raffle, and that would kick off the keepers in the VRF,
as well. So we could call it via ether scan, we could obviously
call it via our staging tests here, we could call it via our
scripts, we could call it via the console, there's a ton of
ways to actually do this. But moment of truth here, we're
gonna run our staging tests, which is going to have us enter
the lottery, and set up a listener to make sure that
everything works correctly. And additionally, we'll see on our
raffle upkeep history, we'll see a transaction go through, and
then we'll see a transaction on our chain like VRF as well. Are
you ready? I sure am.
Let's do this. So we'll do h h, test, dash dash network, rink B.
And that should be all we need to do. In our state and tests,
we probably should have added some console dot logs in here to
tell us hey, to tell us what steps that we're on with each.
But we forgot to. So if you follow along with the repo
associated with this, we've added the console dot logs in
the test there. But all right, if we go to the ether scan for
this contract, we go back to the rink the ether scan for this, we
paste in that address, the first step that we're doing in this
test, of course, while we're setting up this listener, the
first transaction is going to be entering the raffle that's going
to kick everything off. Right. So if we refresh a little bit on
ether scan, we do indeed see we've entered the raffle. And
we've updated the balance of the raffle. Okay, awesome. So raffle
has been entered. Now then what happens? Well, if the raffle has
been entered, if we go to raffle dot soul, if it's open, if
enough time has passed, if there's players and it has a
balance, which we just checked does, this will get kicked off
by the keepers. So if we go to the keepers, and we do a little
refresh here, after a little bit, we do indeed see checkup
key passed and we see a perform upkeep having gone through
great, what does perform upkeep to well perform upkeep calls the
chainlink VRF. So now if we go over to chainlink, VRF, we do a
refresh here, go down to history, we do indeed see one of
the transactions has gone through we can see the
transaction hash, the link spent, etc. And now if we go
back to our tests, we do indeed see raffle unit tests for friend
fulfill random request winner pick event fired. And this means
that we just went through this entire process of having a
perfectly truly decentralized raffle work on an actual
Testament with our integration tests working correctly.
Absolutely massive, huge congratulations if you've made
it this far. And if you just walk through the integration
test with me now bounce over contract has now been reset to
zero because our wallet address just won the lottery right and
got the money back. Now you might be wondering, Hey, I see
the Create raffle function. And I see enter raffle but I don't
see didn't the chain link nodes just call perform upkeep and
fulfill random words, I'll come no matter how often I refresh, I
don't see those transactions here. Well, those are actually
going to be considered internal transactions fulfill random
words, it's actually called through the VRF coordinator and
the VRF coordinator contract then calls for full randomness.
So we can go to internal transactions. And one of these
transactions is going to be the transaction to the VRF
coordinator contract, which calls our contract. Same thing
with perform upkeep. Perform upkeep, the chain link nodes
actually call through the registry contract and then the
registry contract calls perform upkeep. That's what we see here.
And if we go through the internal transactions, we'll see
him there. Now let's look at this enter raffle as well. And
since we've learned about events and logs, we can actually go to
the logs section now. And we can see our log or event being
emitted here we can see the name raffle, enter, we can see the
topic zero which is going to identify this entire event. And
then we also see this number here which is what which is
index topic, one address player and then there's no data
associated with this right because we only have index
parameters which again show up as topics so this is absolutely
phenomenal.