All right, this is fantastic. At this point, you should be set up with Visual Studio Code no Jas and get.
太好了，真是太棒了。现在，你应该已经配置好了 Visual Studio Code, node.js 以及 Git。
And I'm going to be working out of a folder called Hard Hat Free Code Camp
并且我将在一个名为 Hard Hat Free Code Camp(hh-fcc) 的文件夹下进行工作
at this point, you should have
现在，你应该已经有了
node, dash dash version, get dash dash
node --version 以及 git --version
And if you're using Windows,
如果你使用的是 Windows
this should say WsL or your boon to or something like that.
这里应该显示 WSL 或者 Ubuntu 或者其他类似的东西
And if you have all that, that means we're ready to go.
如果这些你都有了，那就表示我们已经准备好了
Now a quick note something that you'll see me do a lot. And you can do this as well.
现在我会对我经常做的一些操作做一个快速的解释，你也可以这样做
Oftentimes, when my terminal gets really, really big, or there's a ton of commands in here
通常，当我的终端变得非常非常大，或者是有成吨的命令放在这里时
gets a little bit overwhelming for me.
会让我感到有些困扰
So one thing that you can do is you can type clear, and hit Enter to clear it.
你可以做的一个操作是输入 "clear"，并按回车以清除它们
Or what you can do is you can hit Command K, if you're on a Mac,
你也可以按 "Command + k"，如果你是在 Mac 上
or Ctrl K, if you're on a Linux or a Windows,
或者是 "Ctrl + k"，如果你是在 Linux 或 Windows 上
and it's one of my favorite keyboard shortcuts that I use all the time.
这是我最喜欢的快捷键之一，我经常会使用它
Additionally, the trash can and the X here are very different.
另外，这里的终止键和X键是非常不同的
If I go to a couple of enters here, and we're down here,
比如说我在这里按几次回车，我们现在处于这个位置
if I hit the trashcan, and then pull my terminal back up,
如果我点击关闭，然后再把我的终端打开
by doing the toggle, or by doing terminal new terminal,
通过切换，或是通过“终端-新建终端”
you'll see all those lines are still here.
你可以看到这些行仍然还在这里
But if I hit the trashcan, and then pull the terminal back up,
但如果我点击终止按钮，再把终端打开回来
you'll see it actually refreshes mine a special command that prints stuff out.
你会看到它刷新了我的一个特殊指令，打印这些东西
trashing your terminal is basically deleting whatever's running in it,
终止你的终端基本上就是删除其中运行的所有东西
and the x is just hiding it.
而X键只是暂时隐藏它
And as hitting Ctrl tilde or toggling our terminal or whatever command it is on your environment,
无论是使用 "Ctrl + ~" 还是切换我们的终端，或是你环境中的任何此类命令
that's equivalent to hitting the hide, not the trash.
它都相当于点击隐藏而不是终止
So if we want to remove and start a terminal over,
所以，如果我们想删除并重新启动一个终端
we hit the trashcan, and then we pull it back up.
我们需要点击终止，然后再把它打开
Alright, so now we're gonna start working with ethers.
好了，现在我们就要开始使用 ethers
And we're going to start learning to code, our transactions and our contract deployments
并开始学习代码，交易，合约部署
and everything programmatically at a relatively low level.
以及一切以编程方式存在的相对底层的东西
And we're gonna learn how to deploy and interact with the contracts using the ethers JS package.
我们将学习如何使用 ether.js 包部署合约并与之交互
Now to get started,
现在让我们开始吧
I'm going to recommend you create a folder
我建议你新建一个文件夹
where you're going to put all of your projects in it,
并把你所有的项目都放到这个文件夹里
I'm going to create a new directory called H H. hyphen, FCC,
我现在就新建一个文件夹名字叫 "hh-fcc"
which stands for hard hat Free Code Camp.
表示 "Hardhat Free Code Camp"
And once we run that command, we can cd into hh FCC.
运行完这个命令，我们就可以使用 "cd" 进入 "hh-fcc"
And this is where we'll create all of our projects for this course moving forward, so that we have them all in one place.
这里就是我们这门课程用来创建所有项目的地方，它们全部放在这一个地方
Now to get started, whenever you create a new project,
现在开始，每当你创建一个新项目时
you always want to create a new folder.
你都要想着创建一个新文件夹
So to create a new folder, we're going to do MK dir,
要想新建一个文件夹，我们输入 "mkdir"
and we're going to call this ethers, simple storage, like that.
并把它叫做 "ethers-simple-storage" 就像这样
And now, if you type ls, you'll see that there is one folder named ethers, simple storage.
现在，如果你输入 "ls"，你就会看到一个文件夹，名字是 "ethers-simple-storage"
ls is how you list all the contents of your folder.
"ls" 就是你用来显示文件夹内所有内容的方法
You might have a lot of other folders in here,
也许你这里还有很多其它文件夹
I only have the one since I created this new folder for this.
而我这只有一个，因为我这里是一个新建的文件夹
Now what you can do, you can type code, ethers simple.
And then if you hit tab, it should autocomplete for you. And
if you enter, Visual Studio code should open up a new Visual
Studio code for you. That is inside of either simple storage
if you open up your terminal now, your home directory for
this workspace is going to be through simple storage as this
is what pops up. If that doesn't work for you, we can also do is
you can hit File, Open folder and then open the folder that
you just created or that you want to open this again we'll
open up VS code. And if we open up our terminal we see we're
inside of ether simple storage. This is so powerful because as
we create files
we'll be able to See those files in our Explorer here, this
button here stands for the Explorer. If we click it, we can
see the different files in here. And I'm going to go ahead and
actually delete this file dot txt, because we're not actually
going to use that. Now it's this part of the course, where we're
actually going to start jumping into some JavaScript. Since this
course is in JavaScript course, if you're unfamiliar with
JavaScript, it might be a little bit tricky. If you want to come
into this with a better understanding of JavaScript and
Node js, there is a Free Code Camp YouTube video teaching No,
Jas for beginners. And a link to this will be in the GitHub repo
associated with this course. There's also a JavaScript Free
Code Camp video that I'm also going to put in the description
for this course, keep in mind that JavaScript and Node js are
slightly different. And we are going to go over some of the
differences as we code along here. But for the most part,
learning one means you've learned the majority of the
other. So if you want to pause and go through these videos,
before continuing here, please feel free to do so you don't
have to, you can absolutely continue on with the course as
is. And if you get confused or stuck on some JavaScript piece,
feel free to pause, Google it and come back. But just to
reiterate, you can check out the JavaScript programming full
course. And also the Node js full course, as those are both
going to help you. Like I was saying before, Node js is a
JavaScript runtime. So it's not exactly JavaScript. But we're
going to write our code in JavaScript. And if that's
confusing, just don't worry about it right now. And as we go
through this course, I'll show you where the differences are.
But basically, you can think of no Jas and JavaScript kind of
being the same thing. The big thing about Node js is it allows
us to write JavaScript code in the back end, as opposed to
running JavaScript on the front end, JavaScript is made to be a
browser run language, like running inside of, you know,
Chrome, brave Firefox, etc. No, Jas allows it to become a a
scripting language, a back end language, which is why the
syntax between the front end JavaScript and the back end
JavaScript or the no JS JavaScript are going to be a
little bit different. Additionally, as we go along in
this code, if you're familiar with TypeScript, all of our code
is going to come with a TypeScript edition. TypeScript
is what's known as a statically typed version of JavaScript. And
it'll be it'll be this one. It'll be TypeScript, not
TypeScript edition. I'll go ahead and fix that and remove
this one to make it clear. TypeScript is a type safe
version of JavaScript, which is that's confusing, don't worry
too much about that. But we are going to do all of our
programming in JavaScript. And then if the code is different
enough, I'll show you how to do it in TypeScript as well.
However, for most of them, we're not going to show you the
TypeScript editions, because it's going to be really similar.
But you can always refer back to the GitHub repository to see all
the code for the TypeScript. Now, if you're new to this
space, I actually do recommend you go ahead and start with
JavaScript and learn how to do TypeScript later on. TypeScript
actually catches bugs early on, making it a lot easier to code
your projects in the long run. However, it does take a lot of
extra typing. And it can be a little bit frustrating learning
how types work for beginners, JavaScript is a little bit more
loose as a language and lets us kind of do whatever we want, but
it can cause a headache later on. So if you do run into some
issues, and you do run into some bugs, it might be a good idea to
try TypeScript on for size, and see how that fares. Well. Let's
go ahead and begin working on our local development
environment and getting set up to do everything in ethers Jas
and in JavaScript. Oops. And I actually went and renamed this
folder to ether symbol storage dash, FCC. Reason I added this
dash FCC is all the GitHub repositories associated with
this course, all the GitHub repos that have this dash FCC to
know that it is part of this hard hat JavaScript course.
Awesome. Let's jump in. Let's start working with solidity and
our smart contracts locally in Visual Studio code, as you can
probably tell by the name of this folder. And of course, if
you looked at the code, this project is going to be our
simple storage project, but developed locally using ethers.
So the first thing that we want to do is want to get in that
smart contract code. So what we can do is make sure we have the
Explorer selected, we can go ahead and right click and select
new file and do simple storage. So just close this for now. And
we can copy paste our simple storage code from our last
section into VS code.
If you closed remix or you forgot where it is, you can just
go to the ethers simple storage FCC repo, it's simple storage
dot Sol, and we can just copy all the code in here and then
come back over select Symbol storage that Saul and paste it
in. Now an important note about Visual Studio code is that when
you see this little white.up here, it means that this file
isn't saved to save your Git file. To save, and it'll go away
like that. Or what you can do is you can hit command S or Ctrl S,
depending on if you're on a Windows, Mac, or Linux. Now
you'll see here that this code is a little bit hard to read the
simple storage dot salt, it doesn't have the syntax
highlighting that we saw in remix. So we want to go ahead
and add a Visual Studio Code extension to give this syntax
highlighting. So what we can do is come over to this bar over
here looks like this. And if you don't see it on the left hand
bar, you should click these three dots, and it should be in
here. But we'll go ahead and click Extensions. And what we're
going to do is we're going to look up, solidity plus hard hat.
And we're going to install this solidity plus hard hat
extension. For VS code. Now that we have this installed, if we go
back over to our simple storage dot sole, you'll see that all
the highlighting is back in. And now it's much easier to read.
Right? So this is good. We have our code in here we have our
syntax highlighting. Now let's add an auto format or or default
format or right now our code is pretty good with the way that
it's formatted. But what if we, we accidentally do some stuff
like this or like this, or maybe even like this, we add a ton of
new lines, etc, our code can start to look pretty gross. And
even though the code itself is fine, and it'll run the exact
same way, with all this extra whitespace, it doesn't look very
good, right. And due to that, it can be a little bit hard to
read. What we want to do, then, we want to open up our settings
and adjust our vias code so that it auto formats whenever we
save, so whenever we save, so that whenever it goes from the
little white dot here to no white dot, this whole thing gets
automatically formatted to some looks really nice. Okay. So what
we can do is we can open up our command palette to open up our
command palette, you can hit View command palette, and we'll
get a little pop up that looks like this. Another way to open
up your command palette is you're gonna hit Command, Shift
P, or Ctrl, Shift P, depending on your Mac, or Linux or
Windows. And what we want to do is we want to type in settings,
and we're going to open Settings JSON, we don't want to open the
default settings JSON. We don't want to touch these. But we want
to open our JSON settings. You'll also notice there are
user settings and workspace settings. These are pieces that
we can adjust as well. But we're going to just go right into the
JSON settings. So So I already have some stuff in here, but
yours might be blank. Or you might have some stuff in here as
well. So what we're going to do is if you have stuff in here
already, we're going to add a comma, then we're going to do
quotes, solidity. Close the brackets, we're gonna do a
little colon and something like this. This means that we're
going to apply some settings to our Visual Studio Code. Whenever
we're working with solidity, one of the things we're going to add
in here is going to be an editor, Doc's default, for
matter. And you might even get a pop up that tells you some
different things that we can use for a default format or our
default format, or is going to be Nanak, foundation, dot hard
hat, hyphens solidity. This will mean that any time we go to
format our code, it'll use the hard hat solidity plug in, as
its default format, or the hard hat solidity plugin comes with
some formatting, and a lot of other really useful tools for us
writing our code. So now that we have this part in, the next
thing we're going to do is add format on Save. If we haven't
already, we could add it in here in our JSON, but I'm going to
add it not in the JSON file, I'm going to add it in the overall
file. So if we open that command palette back up, and we type in
settings, open user settings, this is another really good
place where we can look in add settings with the UI. So these
two do essentially the same thing. It's just that this one
has dials and a little bit more context versus settings that
JSON just says Okay, give me the raw code for it. This tells us a
little bit more. So you can use either one. But we're going to
look for format, on save. And you're going to want this
checked if you haven't already. This means that every time we
save VS code is going to try to format our code for us. So now
that we have this checked, we have settings dot JSON added in.
And remember, we want to save this. Remember, if you see this
white dot, that means not saved. So you're gonna want to save it
and close it out. Let me close this out too. If we come back in
here and we add a bunch of random new spaces or whatever,
you want to make it look a little bit ugly, and then we
save it. It should automatically reformat to look much nicer,
right. So if we do something like this, we'd save it
reformats it to look much nicer this one make them more readable
for you, and more readable for anybody else who looks at your
code. And it's just really nice. And this line of code for your
settings dot JSON is located in the full blockchain study
course.js. So you can also just copy paste it, we are going to
end up overriding that default format or with another format
are called prettier pretty soon. But it's great to have a default
format or so that if you don't feel like adding the prettier
code sometime in the future, you can just rely on your default
formatter. Awesome. While we're doing formatting, let's also add
a default format or for our JavaScript code. And just to
test it out, let's go ahead and create our new file, we'll call
it deploy dot Jas. And in here, we can do something like
function Hi,
console dot log, hi, and then just add and then just make it
look kind of gross, maybe something like this. If you hit
save, and it does some auto formatting, that's great, you
can actually turn that off by going back to your command
palette, and saying, Save without formatting. And that way
it will be saved and not formatted. The way we can add
some other formatting here is we're gonna install another
extension, this one is going to be called prettier. So we can
just look up prettier and extensions here. And you'll want
to install this prettier code formatter. So we're gonna go
ahead and install this. And great, now it's installed
prettier is a form is a code format, or that works for many
languages like Python, JavaScript, and even solidity.
And pretty soon we're going to use prettier for both JavaScript
and solidity. But for now, we're just going to use prettier for
JavaScript, we can enable this by opening back up our command
palette, we'll go to preferences, open Settings. And
the same way we added a solidity section, we're going to add a
JavaScript section. So we're going to add a comma here, some
quotes, brackets, we're going to type in JavaScript, close that
colon brackets. And we're going to do the same thing at the door
dot default, or matter. Net we're going to do and then in
here, we're going to do e s BENP, that prettier, hyphen VS
code. And this will make prettier the default editor for
JavaScript. Now, like I said, pretty soon, we're going to have
prettier override both of these for solidity and JavaScript. And
we're going to give prettier some parameters so that no
matter who uses your code, they will always have the exact same
formatting. But now that we have prettier in here as the default
editor, if we come back to deploy dot j s, and we hit save,
it should format to look a little something like this. Now,
we go ahead and we do something like this. If we go ahead and do
something like this, it'll reformat to look like look like
that. And then additionally, if you want to go back to the
command palette, open user settings, not in JSON mode, and
we go to default format, or you can actually even select the
default format or for all languages, if you want to use
prettier for all formatters. Feel free to go ahead. Alright,
great, got our JavaScript format, or in as well, let's
start writing some JavaScript code.