But I do want to give you a quick bit background on asynchronous programming.
我要给你们简要介绍一下异步编程的背景知识
So far, the programming that we've done has been synchronous.
目前为止，我们所做的编程都是同步的
And solidity is an example of a programming language, that synchronous,
solidity 就是一个同步编程语言的实例
Synchronous means it just goes one line after another.
同步的意思是说它就是一行接着一行往下运行的
If our code looks like this, this is synchronous write,
如果我们的代码看起来是这样的，那这就是同步的，对吧？
our main function is the first thing that actually gets called.
我们的 main 函数首先被调用
Then we do console dot log, that variable equals five, and then console dot log. Again,
接着会运行 "console.log" 然后是 "variable = 5" 最后是再次运行 "console.log"
this is synchronous programming in JavaScript,
这就是 JavaScript 中的同步编程
all of our solidity is synchronously programmed.
我们的 solidity 则完全是同步编程的
There will be some exceptions to this when working with oracles.
使用预言机的时候会有一些例外
But for now, everything is synchronous.
但至少现在全都是同步的
JavaScript can be asynchronous,
JavaScript 可以是异步的
meaning that we can actually have code running at the same time.
这意味着我们可以让代码同时运行
A good example I like to use to understand the difference is with cooking.
有一个我很喜欢的例子可以用来区分二者的区别，就是类比烹饪
In synchronous programming, for cooking,
在同步编程中，用烹饪的例子来说
you might put popcorn in microwave, wait for popcorn to finish.
你可以把爆米花放到微波炉里，等待爆米花制作完成
And then, and then maybe you'll pour drinks for everyone.
接着，你可能会给大家倒点喝的
And now this is synchronous programming.
现在，这个过程就是一个同步编程
Now, it might be a little bit weird
但这个过程可能看起来有些奇怪，
for you just to put the popcorn in the microwave,
你先把爆米花放进微波炉
and then just stare at it, waiting for it to finish. And then pour the drinks,
然后就只是盯着它，等它做好，然后再去倒喝的
you typically can pour the drinks while your popcorn is in the microwave.
通常来说你可以一边倒喝的一边用微波炉加热爆米花
And this is where asynchronous programming comes in.
这就是要引入异步编程的地方了
If setting up for this movie night, we're asynchronous, what you would do is you'd put popcorn in the microwave.
如果把这个过程设置为一个异步的过程，你要做的就是先把爆米花放进微波炉
And while the popcorn is in the microwave, or drinks for everyone,
然后在爆米花还在微波炉里的时候，就去给大家倒喝的
and then you'd wait for popcorn finish,
最后你再等待爆米花制作完成
since there's nothing left for you to do,
因为你暂时也没什么其他事要做了
but it doesn't make sense for you to wait for the popcorn to finish to pour your drinks,
干等着爆米花做好再去倒喝的实在是毫无意义可言
you can just go ahead and pour the drinks right away and then wait for the popcorn to finish.
你完全可以先去倒喝的然后再等爆米花做好
So asynchronous programming is way for us to do stuff
所以异步编程就是这样一种行事方式
without waiting around for things to finish.
即不必干等着一件事做完再去做别的事
And this is really advantageous
这种方式是很有好处的
in JavaScript by default allows us to do this asynchronous programming,
JavaScript 默认就允许我们使用异步编程
however, sometimes we do want to wait for our popcorn to finish.
不过，有的时候我们确实就是想先等爆米花做好
For example, if instead of just pouring drinks,
比如说，如果这里不只是倒喝的
maybe the next thing instead of pouring drinks was placed salt on popcorn.
可能是给爆米花撒点盐而不是倒喝的
Of course, if we want to play salt on our popcorn,
当然了，如果我们要给爆米花撒盐
we do have to wait for the popcorn to get out of the microwave.
那我们确实要先等爆米花从微波炉里拿出来
So even though placing popcorn in the microwave has this wait time we need to be
able to tell our code I want you to actually wait for it or No,
you're good. You can go on and do another task. So that's kind
of the difference here. And I'll leave some links in the GitHub
repo associated with this course to understand this a little bit
better functions that have functions that come with this
waiting period return something called a problem. This, if put
popcorn in the microwave was a function in JavaScript, it would
be a promise based function. A promise can be either pending,
fulfilled, or rejected. And this is how we know if our popcorn is
done. If our popcorn was a method, putting popcorn in the
microwave, were a function in JavaScript, when we're waiting
for the popcorn to finish, it's in a pending state. When it's
when the popcorn is finished, it would be fulfilled. And if we
aborted halfway through, and we stopped waiting, it would be
rejected. So putting the popcorn in the microwave returns a
promise. With this promise, we have to tell our code, hey, we
want you to wait for the popcorn to finish or you can go ahead
and you can just keep doing stuff. So let's put this all
together with some JavaScript syntax here. Let's say again,
we're going to be setting up this movie night. And we need to
cook popcorn, pour drinks for everybody. And then we need to
start a movie. So let's write some pseudocode to pretend what
this code would look like if this was actually a function. So
we create some function called setup, Movie Night. And in here,
we would say okay, what's the first thing we need to do? Okay,
we need to cook popcorn. So let's say we have some cook
popcorn function. So we'll say, okay, cook popcorn, then the
next thing we're gonna have to do is we're gonna have to pour
drinks, or drink. So we'll call some pour drinks function. Now
here's the thing, we only want to start the movie once our
popcorn has been cooked. And once our drinks have been
poured, so if either one of these returned a promise, so if
either one of these returns a promise, like cook popcorn, for
example, we would need to tell our code here to actually wait
for the popcorn to finish because cook popcorn is going to
be a function where we could say let status equals cook popcorn.
And while the popcorn is being cooked, the status is going to
be ending. Once the popcorn gets cooked, it'll be fulfilled. If
the popcorn breaks, the microwave explodes, the status
would be rejected. But we don't want the status to be in a
pending situation. Before we move on, we only want to start
our movie once these two functions have completed. And
let's say both of these return these promises things. So we
need to tell our code, hey, you have to wait. Or you have to
wait for cook popcorn and for poor drinks to finish. So what
we can do now without getting too deep into the weeds on how
all this works, one of the easiest things that we can do
and you'll see us use this syntax quite often is we'll turn
this function into an async function. When our functions are
async, we get access to a keyword called await the await
keyword tells any promise based function to wait for that
promise to be fulfilled or rejected. So we say okay, we
want to await for our popcorn to cook. And then we want to await
to pour drinks. And then we can just go ahead and start the
movie. And we only start the movie here once these two have
been completed. And this is why throughout all of our code,
you'll see this await keyword used a lot. But it can only be
used in async functions. So basically, whenever you see this
await keyword just now Ah, okay, the function that's being called
is promise based. And we don't want to move on to the next step
until that function has completed. So that's a little
bit more about promises and asynchronous programming.
Hopefully, that's clear. If not, like I said, there's some links
in the description to learn more about asynchronous programming.
The reason I wanted to go through this is because most of
the functions that we're going to be working with are going to
be asynchronous. For example, when we deploy a contract, what
do we have to do? Well, we have to wait for it to be deployed.
If we don't use synchronous programming, and we just leave
our function main like this, what would happen is we would
write some code like contract dot deploy, and we wouldn't wait
for it to finish. Obviously, if we don't wait for it to finish,
and we try to run some code on a contract that hasn't finished
deploying it, it's not going to work. So we want to do this, we
want to have our main function be an async function, so that we
can we can wait for our contracts to deploy, we can wait
for things to happen, we can wait for our popcorn to finish,
we can have the flexibility to tell our code to either wait for
our popcorn to finish or continue on. So now that we have
our main function as an async function, we're going to add
some code to our main function down here. And the code that's
added here is some syntax for working with asynchronous
functions. And if this part is confusing, I'm just going to say
for now, absolute, don't worry about this. If you want to try
to understand that later. That's fine. But for those who are
following along, we're just going to add an add
then catch air air you can follow along typing this
yourself or you can just copy paste it into your code.
Basically what this allows us to do is we have our main function,
that's an asynchronous function. So when we call the main
function, this is some other syntax for waiting for it to
basically finish and then printing any errors it gets. And
that's why we do this but Again, if this big lump of code, if
you're like what is going on with this big clump of code,
honestly, for now, just copy paste it. So great. We have our
asynchronous function main, we have some code. And then we have
this lump of code, which basically just calls our main
asynchronous function. Okay, great. I'm gonna delete all this
for now. But you can still find that common in the GitHub repo
associated with this course. Awesome. Okay, so now that we
have our real basic setup, let's go ahead and start coding. And
if this set apart is confusing, and the async await stuff is
confusing, don't worry too much about it. It'll make more sense
as we progress.