as we progress. All of our code basically is going to be inside
of this async function main, which is going to be our main
script for deploying our simple storage dot soul store deploy
script is going to replicate exactly what goes on in remix,
in remix, what was the first thing that we always did? Well,
the first thing that we would do is actually compile all of our
code. So we're going to want to compile our code in our
JavaScript project as well. In order for us to compile our
simple storage contract, we're going to use a tool called Silk
Jas, and JavaScript actually has a way to install projects
directly into our setups and into our folders. If we scroll
down this silk Jas is exactly what we're looking for. Because
it has a way to compile a contract that imports other
contracts via relative paths, you can see a section in this
readme and most documentation will have something like this,
if it's JavaScript compatible. For Node js usage, it says to
use the latest stable version of the solidity compiler via Node
js, you can install it via NPM npm install. So NPM is what's
known as a package manager. And we actually installed NPM just
by installing no Jess, right, if we do no dash dash version, you
should also be able to do NPM dash dash version. Another tool
that it comes with is something called core pack. And you can
type core pack dash dash version, now we can install with
NPM using npm install silk, however, I like the yarn package
manager a little bit better. So we're actually going to install
the yarn package manager instead to do all of our package
management. If you go to the installation page, the newer way
to install yarn is just by running core pack enable. And
the older way is to install with NPM. If you go ahead and run
core pack enable after that finishes, you should be able to
run yarn dash dash version. Alternatively, you can just run
NPM i dash g core pack, and then you can run core pack enable.
The last option you have is you can run NPM i dash g
yarn. This will install yarn globally for your system. But
this is considered the outdated way to install yarn. And ideally
you run core pack enable. But in any case, after you run those,
if you run yarn dash dash version, you should get
something that looks like this. Now that we have yarn, we can
actually use yarn to install all of our projects, instead of NPM.
Back in silk Jas where it says npm install soak, we can do the
yarn equivalents of NPM install sock, which is going to be yarn,
add sock, this will actually go ahead and install solc to our
project. If we open up our folders, you'll actually see
that this added a couple of different folders, it first
added a package dot JSON package dot JSON is a file that tells us
a lot about our project and the dependencies that it works with.
For example, we've installed the soap package of 0.8 point 13.
Our yarn dot lock tells us the exact version of all the
different packages of our project. For example, the reason
this is so important too, is solc has a ton of dependencies
as well. So yarn dot lock tells us exactly what version of solc
and all the different dependencies of solchen. Any
other project that we add. This is autogenerated file, don't
edit the file directly. The final bit is we got this node
modules folder. This node modules folder is going to be
where all the installed code that we just downloaded is, for
example, if we look at node modules, we can see there's a
sock folder. And inside this sock folder is all the code
associated with this soap package that we just installed.
And since we're working with zero point 8.7 of slowly, we
actually want to install that specific version. So we're going
to do yarn add solc at zero point 8.7 Dash fixed and you'll
see in our package dot JSON you can now see zero point 8.7 Dash
fixed in our dependencies section for sulk. Normally you
can just add your salt version like yarn add zero point 8.7 But
there was an issue with zero point 8.7 So we had to do zero
point 8.7 Dash fixed.
You can find the different releases and the different
versions if you go to sulk Jas releases and then to tags
Alright, great. Now that we have sold, we have the ability to
actually compile our contracts, we could either compile them in
our code and have it automatically run whenever we
hit Deploy, or, or we could compile them separately. If you
want to go back after this section is an example in the
sculpt Jas repository that shows you how to actually compile silk
right in your code. We are actually going to compile them
separately using a soap Jas command. The yarn command is
both used to install dependencies and it can be used
to run scripts. If you go to sulk Jas and you scroll down, it
says in order to use the command line, you actually need to
install it globally. If you want to install this globally using
yarn Global Add solc at zero point 8.7 Dash fixed you can
absolutely go ahead. However, since we're inside of this
folder here, which has the yarn dot lock the package json and
the node modules yarn will be smart enough to know i You're
looking for the soak in this folder. So we can actually go
ahead and compile our contract using yarn and solc Jess if you
want to see all the different commands soak Jas allows we can
just run yarn. So Jas dash dash help, and you'll see it'll spit
out a list of all the different options that soft Jas has. You
can also run yarn, so Jas dash dash version to just make sure
that we're on the correct version, which is indeed zero
point 8.7. Now to actually compile our simple storage at
soul, let's run the compliation command we will run yarn, so J
S, dash dash bin since we want the binary dash dash ABI since
we also want the ABI dash dash include path node modules. Since
we want to include any contracts or files in our node modules, we
aren't using any for this project, but in the future, you
will need to include this dash dash include path node modules
do dash dash base path of period, this period means that
the base path is going to be this folder dash O period, which
means we're going to output the compiled binary and ABI to this
folder. And then finally, simple storage dot soul. Since this is
the contract that we want to compile, auto completed it from
simple storage to simple storage. So by typing simple,
and then hitting Tab, but let's go ahead and hit enter, you'll
see it's running this command to compile this contract. And
you'll see two files get output. One called Simple Storage soul
underscore simple storage that API in simple storage Sol
underscore simple storage dot bin, the ABI is obviously the
ABI of this contract, which will need in the future. And then the
bin is going to be the binary, or the really low level of this
code back and remix. If you compile simple storage, that
soul, you can actually look at compliation details, like the
ABI which we just got, or the bytecode, which if you look at
this object 60806 That's the same as the binary here 60806.
Alright, great. So now we've compiled our contracts here.
Now, obviously, now if you hit up on your keyboard, you can
actually cycle through your most recent terminal commands. And if
you hit up enough, we can see this command that we just ran
typing this out or hitting up a whole bunch every single time,
it's going to be really annoying to do anytime we want to
recompile. So what we can do is we can add a script section in
our package dot JSON to shorten some yarn scripts for us. So
what we'll do is back in our package, dot JSON, a lot of
comma, and we'll add a section called scripts, add the colon
and the brackets. And in here, we'll say anytime we say
compile, we will run this long command. So I'd compile we'll
put some quotes. And we'll paste that in there. So now instead of
typing that whole thing out, as long as we're in the same folder
that our package json is in, we can run yarn compile. And this
will run that whole script for us without us having to type the
whole thing out scripts are a really useful way to make it
easier for us to run long commands. All right, great. Now
we have our code compiled, this is going to be equivalent to US
hitting this compile button for us to actually go ahead and
deploy.