Hardhead has this fantastic tool built in called The Hard Hat Network
Hardhat 内置了一个很棒的工具叫做 "Hardhat Network"
hard hat comes built in with Hard Hat Network,
Hardhat 内置 Hardhat Network
a local Aetherium network node designed for development,
它是一个专为开发而设计的本地以太坊网络节点
akin to ganache, that allows you to deploy your contracts and run your tests and debug your code.
与 Ganache 相似，它允许你部署合约，运行测试以及调试代码
Whenever we run a command in hard hat, or a script and hard hat or a task and hard hat,
每当我们在 Hardhat 中运行命令、脚本或者任务时
we by default deploy to this fake Hard Hat Network.
我们都是默认部署到这个虚拟的 Hardhat Network
This Hard Hat Network is very similar to ganache,
这个 Hardhat Network 与 Ganache 十分相似
except for instead of having this UI,
除了没有这个 UI 界面
it runs in the background for our scripts.
它在我们脚本的后台中运行
In fact, if we go to our hard hat.config.js,
事实上，如果我们打开 "hardhat.config.js"
we can scroll down to the bottom to this module that exports section
我们可以滑倒底部找到这个 "module.exports" 部分
and add more information about our default networks.
并添加有关默认网络的更多信息
So right now, if we don't have anything in this module that export,
现在，如果我们在 "module.exports" 中没有任何相关信息
by default, it adds this piece called default network hardhat.
那么默认情况下，它就会添加 "defaultNetwork: 'hardhat'"
So anytime we run a script,
所以无论我们什么时候运行脚本
without specifying a network, it automatically uses this fake Hard Hat Network.
只要没有特别指定某个网络，它都会自动使用这个虚拟的 Hardhat Network
And this fake Hard Hat Network
并且这个虚拟的 Hardhat Network
comes automatically with an RPC URL and a private key for you.
会自动为你提供一个 "RPC URL" 和一个私钥
So you don't even have to add one in.
所以你不必再额外添加一个了
This is one of the major advantages of working with Hardhead.
这是使用 Hardhat 工作的主要优势之一
It just automatically gives you this fake blockchain. And these fake private keys,
它会自动为你提供一个虚拟区块链以及虚拟私钥
if you want to be a little bit more explicit. And I always recommend being more explicit,
如果你想让这里更明确一些，并且我也认为明确一点会比较好
we can add the default network in to the module that are experts.
那么可以在 "module.exports" 中添加一下 "defaultNetwork"
So now our default network is explicitly stated as hard hat.
所以现在我们的 "defaultNetwork" 被明确指定为 "hardhat"
However, in any script, you run,
不过，无论任何脚本，你都可以在运行时
you can choose whatever network you want to work with.
选择你想要使用的任意网络
So if I want to explicitly say
所以如果我想明确指定
I want to run our deploy script on our fake Hard Hat Network,
我想在虚拟的 Hardhat Network 上运行我们的部署脚本的话
I can do yarn, hard hat, run scripts, deploy dot j s, dash dash network, hard hat,
我可以这么做 "yarn hardhat run scripts/deploy.js --network hardhat"
this is us telling her that,
这就是我们在告诉 Hardhat
hey, we want to run this script on the Hard Hat Network.
嘿，我们要在 Hardhat Network 上运行这个脚本
Hopefully, you might be able to see where this is going.
希望你已经看明白这是怎么一回事了
Having this network flag
有了这个网络标识之后
makes it incredibly easy to switch across different chains, different block chains, different private keys, etc.
在不同链，不同区块链，不同私钥等等之间的切换就会变得非常容易
So we have our default network set the hard hat here,
现在我们把这里的 defaultNetwork 设置为了 hardhat
we can add other networks in here as well.
我们也可以在这里添加其它网络
The way we do that is we're going to add a networks section.
方法就是添加一个 "network" 部分
And we're going to define any of the network sections that we want.
并按照我们的需要定义它
And remember to put a comment there so that your Visual Studio code doesn't get mad at you.
记得这里要加个逗号，这样你的 Visual Studio Code 就不会向你报错了
So recently, we worked with Rigby so let's go ahead and add a Rinkeby network in here.
就近期来说，我们使用的是 Rinkeby，所以我们来添加一个 Rinkeby 网络
So we're gonna say another network is gonna be really
所以我要指定另外的网络是 "rinkeby"
cool. So I should just be able to change the network flag to Rigby now, right?
酷！所以我现在应该能够切换网络标识为 Rinkeby 了，对吧？
Well, not quite.
好吧，并不是
If you try to run that,
如果你尝试运行，
you're gonna get invalid value undefined for hardhat config networks. Rigby, that URL,
就会得到 “无效的未定义值 HardhatConfig.networks.rinkeby.url”
it's expecting you to tell it, hey, what the URL is,
它希望你能告诉它，嘿，这是什么 URL
since this isn't the hard hat network,
因为这并不是 Hardhat Network
we need to tell hard hat exactly how we're going to connect to rink B.
所以我们需要告诉 hardhat 如何链接到 Rinkeby
And this is where a lot of what we learned before is going to come in handy, again,
这就是我们之前学到的许多知识再次派上用场的地方了
exactly the same as what we did before.
就和我们之前做的完全一样
We're going to create a new Dotty v file, and we're going to add our Rigby URL in this dot env file. Just
remember, dot env is an r dot get ignore just in case. So in
our Dotty env, we're going to add that RPC URL from alcmi back
in here before we just said RPC URL. But since we might want to
work across multiple networks, it's usually good to specify
exactly what network each URL stands for. So we're gonna say
Rynkeby RPC URL equals and then paste that URL in here. Now, as
you probably have guessed, we can add our URL to our Rinkeby
network here. for readability, I usually like to add them as
variables right above the module that experts. So I'll say const
Rynkeby. RPC URL equals process dot E and V dot Rynkeby RPC URL.
And once again, we're going to be pulling that Rinckey RPC URL
from our environment variable. Of course, in order to pull that
environment variable in, we're going to need to use that dot
env package again. So to add that in, we're going to yarn add
dash dash dev dot EMV. And at the top of our Hardhead config,
we're going to add require dot EMV, and then do dot config to
enable the config. Now this means we should be able to pull
our rink the RPC URL from our dot env. Now that we have that
in our Rinkeby network, we can add URL Rinckey RPC URL.
Awesome. So we have an RPC URL for different network. But what
else do we usually need? Well, we usually need a private key to
work with an actual network, or that doesn't automatically give
us a private key for rugby, because Hardhead can't just give
us test and the Etherium, we need to have an actual account
an actual test nets. Hardhead doesn't control those. So we
have to actually give it a real URL and a real private key. So
to add private keys, you actually add something called
accounts, you add a list of accounts that you want to give
to hard hat for us, we're only going to add one, which is going
to be our private key. And for our private key, we're going to
do the exact same thing. We're gonna say const private key
equals process dot e NV dot private key. And since this
private key is going to be a real private key for a real test
net, again, we are going to have to grab this from our meta mask.
So it will go to our meta mask, three dots, account details,
export private key, and we'll add our password in here.
And then in our dot env will add private key equals and then add
our private key. Now I know I've said this 100 times, but please,
please, please, for learning this, do not use a real key that
is connected to any real money just in case, please use a new
meta mask. I've know I've said it a bunch. But some people go
no, I'm going to be okay, I'll be safe. Just to be super, super
safe here, please use a brand new meta mask. So now that we
have a private key, we're going to add it in here account
private key. And now we have an account here. One more thing I
like to do is I like to give the chain ID of the network, which
for Rigby is going to be for every single EVM base network as
a new chain ID and EVM network basically just means solidity
works on it. This includes all test nets, there's a good site
called chainless.org, which may or may not be going down at some
point, it has a list of all these different networks. For
example, you can see on here a theory main net has a chain ID
of one byte and smart chain is 56, avalanches, 4311 for
Phantom, opera 250, Polygon, 137, etc. Each one of these EVM
compatible chains has their own chain ID, rank V, the chain ID
is for adding the chain ID is helpful here for later on. And
we'll get to that in the future. But for now, just go ahead and
make sure to add your chain IDs. Okay, now that we have the RPC
URL, we have the private key, we can go ahead and test deploying
this to an actual test net, and actually did something incorrect
here. And we're gonna get an error here. And I want you to go
ahead and try to figure out and debug this error yourself.
You're ready. Alright, let's do it. We'll do yarn, hard hat, run
scripts, deploy dot j s, dash dash network Rinkeby. And we get
this wonderfully weird error, which we see we have deployed
contract. So we know that in our deploy script, we get to at
least this line, but then we're getting an error, I highly
likely hear what's going on saying cannot read properties
have no reading send transaction, if you want, you
can absolutely go to this spot. But it basically it looks like
it's having a hard time understanding what the private
key or what the account of this is. And what do you think I'm
going to recommend we do? Well, if it's not clear, after doing a
little bit of triaging and debugging, we're going to copy
this air. And we're going to come on over to Google and paste
that right in. It looks like we do get a question here from
stackexchange Etherium. And it looks like it's really similar
to what we're doing. We scroll down. They're running nearly the
exact same script that we're running, they're using MPX
instead of yarn. They've got a pretty minimalistic deploy file.
Let's scroll down and see what the answers have to say. I've
seen this error where my private key wasn't properly populated. I
would also use an environment variable I'm pretty sure Are
environment variables good. But we have a second one saying in
your heart head, I can think that Jas, it should be accounts
instead of account, it works for me, let's go back to our head
config and see if that's what's going on. Uh huh, we put account
in this should be accounts. So let's swap that over to
accounts. We'll clear our terminal. And we'll run this
again. Uh huh. And now it's reading a little bit longer,
which is good. This means that we're probably deploying this to
rink B, which is what we want to see. Awesome. And now we can see
deployed contract to, and we have a contract address here. So
we'll grab this contract. And we'll pop on over to bring the
ether scan, that's numbering the ether scan. And we'll go ahead
and we'll paste this in. Awesome. And we see our contract
was created about 26 seconds ago. Perfect. Now for this part,
you don't have to deploy this to rink be with me, if you follow
along here. That's good enough. So remember, the flying to test
that's can take a long time. So for this one, you don't have to
deploy with me.