Alright, great. So we've deployed to rink be using hard hat. This is fantastic.
很好，我们已经用 Hardhat 把合约部署到了 Rinkeby 上，真是太棒了
Now something that we notice, once again is oof,
现在我们会注意到，又一次，哦
our contract isn't verified?
我们的合约没有被验证
Do we have to go back through and do this verify and publish and all that stuff again?
我们需要回去重新验证，发布以及执行其他相关操作么？
Luckily for us, we actually don't need to do that.
幸运的是，我们不需要做这些
So what can we do?
那我们要做的是什么？
Well, back in our deploy script, we can add some code to automatically verify right after we deploy.
回到部署脚本，我们可以添加一些代码以使合约在部署后可以立即自动验证
So let's go ahead and do that.
让我们来试着做一下
Right below our main function, we're gonna create a new function called verify,
在我们的 main 函数下面，我们将创建一个新函数，名为 "verify"
we're gonna say async function, verify.
我们要输入 "async function verify"
And we're gonna have this function get past some arguments,
并且我们要让这个函数接收一些参数
we're gonna have to get past a contract, address, and some arguments or the contract.
我们要提供 "contractAddress" 以及合约所需要的一些参数
Since our simple storage doesn't have a constructor,
因为我们的 "SimpleStorage" 没有构造函数
the arguments for simple storage are just gonna be blank.
所以提供给 "SimpleStorage" 的参数为空
But in the future, when we have contracts that do have constructors,
但是在将来，当我们拥有具有构造函数的合约时
the arguments are going to be populated.
这个参数就不再是空的了
And when we get there, you'll see what I mean,
到那时你就明白我的意思了
we need at least the contract address, and we're going to add some code in here
我们至少要提供 "contractAddress"，并且还要在这里添加一些代码，
to automatically verify our contracts after they've been deployed.
才可以在部署完成后自动验证我们的合约
This auto verification process works on block explorers
like ether scan, it might not work on block explorers like
eath, pler, or other block explorers. But if you want to
verify on these other block explorers, I'm sure they have an
API to allow you to do that as well. Now, ether scan in most
other block explorers have a section on their website called
API documentation, or something to do with API's. These are ways
for us to programmatically interact with ether scan, and do
stuff with them. One of the main things that we can do is we can
actually verify our contracts through this API. Ether scan
even has a tutorial in here called verifying contracts
programmatically. And the link to this will be in the GitHub
repo, they have an API endpoint that we can make some requests
to to go ahead and verify our contracts. Now, we could
absolutely make the raw API calls and follow the tutorial
here. But there's actually an easier way than even going
through this tutorial here. Hardhead is an extensible
framework, meaning you can add something called plugins to it.
There's even an advanced section in the documentation called
Building plugins. If we scroll down to the bottom, we can see
some popular plugins that the nomic labs team or the Hardhead
team has created. And also a number of community plugins as
well. One of the most used Hardhead plugins is going to be
this hard hat ether scan plugin that makes this verification
process much, much easier. Install it, you can just run npm
install bash, just save dev at nomic labs harden ether scan,
and then add it to our hard hat dot config. Since we're using
yarn, we're just going to go ahead and use yarn. So back in
our code, we'll do yarn, add dash dash Dev, at nomic, labs,
slash hard hat slash hyphen, ether scan. Now that we have
this plugin, we can go to our hard hat dot config, scroll to
the top and add this plugin do require at nomic labs slash hard
hat, ether scan. Now that we have this plugin, the hard hat
documentation has some more information about the usage, how
to actually use this plugin, and how to run different commands
with it. In order for us to use this verification, we actually
need an API key from ether scan. This is basically a password for
allowing us to use the ether scan API. So we're going to come
to ether scan. And we're going to go ahead and sign in. And
actually we're going to click to sign up and create an account.
And we'll go ahead and create an account. We'll go ahead and
verify our registration by clicking the verification link.
And we'll click the Login. Now that we're logged in. On the
left hand side, we can scroll down to API keys. And we can go
ahead and create a new API key. We call this H H hyphen sec,
which stands for hardhat Free Code Camp. Great, this new API
key will copy this and we'll go back to our code and we'll add
this somewhere since the API keys basically considered a
password. Where do you think we should add this? That's right in
our dot env. So in our dot env, we're going to add a new entry
called ether scan API key. And we're going to add that API key
that we just got. Now that we have our API key, back in our
Hardhead, config, we're going to create a new section in a module
dot exports, tell hardhat that we have this ether scan API key,
or new section is going to be called ether scan.
And in here, we're gonna say API key is going to be ether scan
API key that we're going to define up here the same way we
define these other keys. So we'll say const, ether scan API
key equals process dot e NV dot ether scan API key. And if
something like this pops up, you can generally just hit enter,
and it will autocomplete it for you, which is awesome. Great. So
now we have an ether scan API key back in the heart had
documentation, it tells us by adding this, we actually get a
new task called verify. Let's try that out. So open our
terminal back up. And we'll do yarn, RT hat. Let's see what
pops up. Wow, we did get a new verification here. When we run
yarn hard hat harder, it actually looks into our hard
hat.config.js and checks for any plugins. If there are new
plugins there, it'll add them as a new task that we can do. You
can manually verify your contract by doing yarn or MPX
Harnett verify dash dash network, the deployed contract
address and any constructor arguments yourself. But we want
to be a little bit more programmatic than this. So what
we're going to do is we're going to go back and create this
verification function, it is good to know how to do it via
command line so that if you want to verify something in the
future, manually, you can, let's build this verify function
though. So we're going to take the our contract address and
some arguments. And for our sake, we're going to do console
dot log verifying contract that that just so that we know we
might have to wait for a little bit. And in our code, we can
actually run any task from hard hat using a run package. So up
at the top, we're actually going to import run from hard hat as
well run allows us to run any hard hat task. So in our code
here, we're going to do a wait to run. And then we can do there
it thought. Now part of that allows you to add different
parameters as well in this run. And it's usually best that you
go ahead and add them in here so that we're really specific with
what we're doing. If we do yarn hardhat verify dash dash help,
we can see what parameters we can actually pass. Well, it
looks like we can pass the Verify parameter. So we'll do
colon, verify. If you go to the actual GitHub for the
verification tasks, you can actually see you can do more
than just verify, you can do verify, get minimum build,
verify, get constructor arguments, verify, verify, which
is what we're going to be working with, and a couple of
other subtasks as well. The second parameter that goes
inside run is going to be a list of actual parameters. This
second parameter here is just kind of the sub task, if you
will, of our verify task. And this is going to be an object
that contains the actual parameters. And this is where we
pass in an address, which is going to be our contract
address, and then our construct or arguments, which is going to
be arcs. Now normally just this right here should be enough for
us to go ahead and use this verify contract in our main
function, but we're going to add one additional thing to it.
Because in practice, sometimes there's some errors that can
come up. One of the errors that often comes up when running a
wait is that the contract has already been verified. And
you'll actually likely run into this, because ether scan will
get smart enough by seeing enough bytecode that is exactly
simple storage that it will start to just automatically
verify any bytecode that looks like simple storage. And then
this await will throw an error, which we want to avoid. So what
we can do is we can add a try catch onto this await. So
outside of the way, we're going to add a try. And we're going to
add these little brackets that wrap around our weight. And then
we're going to put a catch. This is known as a try, catch and
solidity also has tried catches. But basically, this e is going
to be any error that this section throws. So we're going
to do is we're going to say if this message is already
verified, then we're just going to continue. So we're gonna say
if e.message.to lowercase, we're going to make sure it's to
lowercase that includes already there. If five, then we're just
going to console dot log already verified
like that. Otherwise, we're just going to console dot log e. The
reason we do This is because of this errors, our verification
function will break, and our whole script will end. And we
don't want our whole script to end, we want our script to keep
continuing if the verification doesn't work, because it's not
really a big deal. So I know this might seem like a lot of
code, feel free to copy and paste it from the GitHub repo to
just move along. But awesome. So we now have a verify function
using the Verify task in hardhat. Let's go ahead and use
this now in our main function, right below our deploy, we'll do
console dot log deployed contract two, and then the
contract address. But before we call this main function, let's
think for a quick second. What happens when we deploy to our RT
Hat Network? Well, remember, if we deploy to our Hard Hat
Network, will our contract need to be verified I need to scan?
Well, we know there's a we know there's a rink ether scan, we
know there's a COVID ether scan, we know there's a main net easy
scan. But is there a Hardhead ether scan? No, of course not.
Right? The hard at runtime environment is a network local
to our machine. So it doesn't make sense for us to verify a
hard hat network deployed contract on ether scan. So we
actually don't want to call this verify function, when we're
working with our local network. This is where these chain IDs
are going to come in quite useful. What we can do is we can
check to see if the network that we're running on is a live
network or it's a test net, or it's a network that actually can
be verified, we can actually get network configuration
information by importing a network like this. And we can do
something like console dot log network dot config. Now, if I
run yarn, art, hit run scripts deploy.js. On our Hard Hat
Network, since I'm not passing a network flag, we get this
massive output that looks like this. Our network dot config
contains a ton of information about the current network that
we're on, you'll see here that the chain ID of the Hardhead
network is actually 31337 gas price, which gets set to auto
block gas limit the current fork of Aetherium that we're working
with, and all these other pieces here. This chain ID is really
important. Because we can use this chain ID to figure out
which one is a test net, or which one is a live network. And
remember, running the script is going to be the same as doing
dash dash network, hard hat,
you'll see our channel ID is still 31337. Again, that's
because the default network in our heart had config, it's hard
hat, which is the same as saying every single time we run a
script, we're secretly running it with dash dash network hard
hat. So now we only want to verify on our test net. So what
we can do is we can say if network dot config, that chain
ID equals equals equals four, which is going to be rank B, ad.
And a JavaScript equals equals equals is nearly the same as
equals equals, except no type conversion is done, which just
means in JavaScript, four equals four, and four equals equals the
string of four, but four, but if you were to use four equals
equals equals four, this is false. This is true equals
equals four equals equals would be true, four equals equals to
the string of four would also be true, but four equals equals
equals to the string of four is going to be false. So you can
kind of do whatever you want here equals equals or equals
equals equals. So we want to say if the network dot config dot
Trinity is four, so if we're on Rinkeby, then we can go ahead
and actually verify. But we also want to make sure we only verify
if our ether scan API key exists. So we can also in here
is site and this double ampersand means and we can say
process dot e NV dot ether scan API key. This is some Boolean
tricks that we're doing here, basically, so our first
conditional we're saying if network dot config chinati
equals equals equals four, this section can be true or false,
obviously, right? The chain ID that we're running on can be the
hardest network, which would mean this doesn't equal four, or
it would be Rinckey, which means this does equal four. But
there's no conditional on this side. So how does this side
work? In JavaScript, if an object exists, and you try to
cast it as a Boolean, it will be converted to true. If it doesn't
exist, it will be converted to false. So in JavaScript,
basically, if either scan API key exists, if we have this in
our data in VI, this will be true. And if not, this will be
false. So another way to read this line here is saying if
network dot config that Trinity is for AKA, if we're on rink B,
and our ether scan API key exists, then do some stuff. And
that's what we're going to do here. So in here, we'd want to
run verify, or verify function and pass it the contract address
which is going to be Simple Storage dot address and the
constructor arguments which we know are going to be blank. And
since our verify function is an async function, and it deals
with promises and stuff, we want to add the await keyword here.
Awesome. So we've added a way to actually verify our contract.
But we're not quite done. See on ether scan and all these block
explorers the instant we deploy the contract and the instant we
send the contract, ether scan might not know about the
transaction yet, it might take a hot second for ether scan to be
up to speed with where the blockchain is. So it's usually
best practice to wait for a few blocks to be mined, until you
actually run your verification process. We've actually learned
how to do this already with the deploy transaction. So before we
actually verify we run, we want to run a weight, simple storage.
Deploy transaction Wait, six. So we will wait six blocks, and
then we'll run our verification process. Now, if you want to go
and test this out right now, you absolutely can. I'm going to
keep going, though, because again, testing all these on a
test net takes a little bit of extra time. So I'm going to
finish the rest of our main function, and then I'm going to
run everything all together.