This is perfect. We've now got a successful deploy dot j s script
简直完美，现在我们有了一个成功的 "deploy.js" 脚本
that can deploy, verify, and then interact with our code. This is fantastic.
它可以部署，验证并与我们的代码进行交互，真是太棒了
This hard hat thing seems pretty cool. What else can we do with hard hat
Hardhat 真是太酷了，它还能做哪些事呢？
like I showed you before.
就像我之前向你们展示的
Hard Hat comes with these tasks.
Hardhat 自带的任务有这些
And the number of tasks that Hardhead can come with can be extended by us writing plugins,
并且 Hardhat 可执行的任务数可以通过我们编写的插件进行扩展
we can actually write our own tasks in hardhat.
我们实际上可以在 Hardhat 中编写我们自己的任务
And in our Hardhead dot config, it can
defaulted with this task account, we can see task
accounts, prints the list of accounts, and just prints a list
of accounts here actually go to the heart had documentation to
learn more about creating our own tasks, one of the ways that
you can define tasks is directly in our heart head.config.js. But
typically, what people do is they have a new folder called
tasks where they put all their tasks. So for now, I'm gonna go
ahead and delete this section here. And we're going to create
our own task. You'll notice that now that we've deleted that
section, if we run yarn RDAP, we no longer see the accounts task
in here, because we've just deleted that task. So let's
create our own new task. We'll call this block number.js. And
we'll use this to get the current block number or whatever
blockchain that we're working with. So let's create this task.
First, we need to import the task function, we can get it by
saying const task equals require arhat slash config. The hard hat
slash config has the task function. To define a task, we
can now just say task, give it a name and a description, the name
is going to be blocked number.
And then the description is going to be prints the current
block number. Now that we have this task, there's a couple of
things we can actually do with it, we can add different
parameters to it by using the dot add command, which allow us
to pass parameters to the task. And then we could also set
actions which define what the task should actually do for us,
we're just going to do dot set action. And define what we want
this function to do. So we're going to make this an async
function, that's going to take as an input, the task arguments,
which are going to be blank for us, and the HR E, which I'll
define in a second. Now, let me explain the syntax really
quickly. This might look a little bit weird, but this is
what's known as a JavaScript arrow function. In JavaScript,
you can actually define functions without even using the
function keyword. For example, if we go back to our deploy
function, we have our async function verify down here.
However, another way we could have defined this is is without
using the function word at all, and actually turning this whole
thing into a variable, we could have said instead, we could say
const verify is going to be an async function that takes
contract addresses and arguments. And here's the
function definition. These two lines are essentially
equivalent. There's some slight differences between between
using the function keyword and having your function be a
variable. But for the purposes of this course, they're
basically the same. Which means though, that this by itself is a
function, just not assigned to a variable. But essentially, the
two of these do are exactly the same. And that's the syntax that
we're doing here. You can imagine this sort of being like
const block task equals async function, which takes the params
and then runs that arrow function. Or you can think of it
as async. Function, block task parameters, and then the
function definition, these are all essentially the same. The
major difference is that we're never giving our function a
name, we never give it this block task variable. This is
known as an anonymous function in JavaScript, because it
doesn't have a name. Now that we have our function in here, we
can now call some function to get the block number. Well, how
can we get the block number when we run tasks, we automatically
pass our anonymous functions, the task arguments, which in
this one, we don't have any, but we also pass this HR II object.
This HRV is the heart hat runtime environment. Back in our
deploy script, this is basically the same as this require hard
hat in here. So this HRV can access a lot of the same, this
HRV can access a lot of the same packages that the hard hat
package can. So we can do Hae dot ethers, just like how you
can import ethers from hard hat. And in our ethers package,
there's actually a number of functions we can use like dot
Pro, biter dot get block number. Let's save this to a variable
const blocked number equals, and this is going to be a
synchronous, so we're going to want to add a weight here. And
then let's do console dot log block number. Or better yet,
we'll string interpolate this and say current block number
like this. Now though, if I try to run this task, you'll notice
it doesn't show up in the heart Atlas of tasks, let's do yarn.
Art app. Hmm, I don't see block number in here. Well, this is
because we need to add it to our config dot config will add
require dot slash tasks slash block number.
And in order for us to import it, and let's add a module that
exports I'll explain what this does a little bit later. But now
that we've required it, if I run yarn hard hat, and now see
blocked over is one of the tasks that I can use. Now for a run
yarn, art hat block number, we get current block number is
zero. And this makes sense because this is defaulting to
our Hard Hat Network, which gets reset every time we run it. But
if I run yarn, hard hat block number A dash dash network
Rinkeby, what do you think I'm gonna get? Again, a much larger
number, current block number is right here. Because this is the
actual block number of Rigby versus the block number of our
heart ad network is going to be zero because it gets reset every
single time, we run one of these scripts now scripts and tasks
both can basically do the same thing. They both can interact
with contracts, they both can deploy smart contracts, they can
both pretty much do everything. I prefer scripts just as a
general rule of thumb, because I don't always think adding a
special thing from the command line makes sense. So I prefer
scripts, but you'll see a ton of tasks and examples out there as
well. I think tasks are really nice for specific use cases. But
for the most part, we're pretty much going to use exclusively
scripts, but it is good to know what a task looks like and how
to use it. I think tasks are better for plugins and scripts
are better for your own local development environment. But if
you want to do everything with tasks, you absolutely can.