Now that we have some tests,
现在我们有了这些测试
we can actually start testing to see how much gas each one of our functions actually costs.
就可以开始测试一下每个函数实际要花费多少 Gas 了
One of the most popular extensions for hard hat is the hard hat gas reporter.
Hardhat 最受欢迎的扩展之一是 "hardhat-gas-reporter"
This is an extension that gets attached to all of our tests,
这是一个可以附加在我们所有测试上的扩展
and automatically gives us an output that looks like this,
并自动提供类似这样的输出
that tells us approximately how much gas each one of our functions cost.
以告诉我们每个函数大约消耗了多少 Gas
We scroll down in here, we can read the instructions on how to actually install this
如果我们向下滑动到这里，可以阅读到有关如何安装这个扩展的说明
npm install Hardhead gas reporter
"npm install hardhat-gas-reporter"
which we're going to use with yarn.
但我们会使用 yarn 来安装
So we're gonna say yarn, add hard hat, gas reporter, dash dash Dev.
所以我们运行 "yarn add hardhat-gas-reporter --dev"
And now that that package is installed,
现在这个包已经安装好了
we can go over to our config and add some parameters in here
我们可以转到 "config" 文件中并在这里添加一些参数
so that we can work with this gas pit.
这样我们就可以使用这个 gas reporter 了
But our neath our ether scan section,
就在我们的 "etherscan" 部分下面
we're going to add a new section called gas reporter.
我们要添加一个新的部分名为 "gasReporter"
To have it run, whenever we run our tests
为了让它能在我们运行测试时运行
we're going to do enabled is going to be true.
我们要写下 "enabled" 为 true
And then up at the top, we can add it by adding require hardhat gas reporter.
然后在顶部，我们可以通过添加 "require("hardhat-gas-reporter")" 来添加它
Now that we have it in here, we can do yarn hardhat test,
现在我们已经有了这个包，就可以运行 "yarn hardhat test" 了
and after we run our tests, it'll automatically run this gas reporter.
并且在运行完测试之后，它会自动运行这个 "gas reporter"
So we see our tests go ahead and run.
现在我们看到我们的测试运行好了
And then we get this output that looks like this that tells us
并且我们获得了这样的输出，它告诉我们
how approximately how much our contracts and methods cost.
我们的合约和方法大约消耗了多少 gas
So our store function looks like It costs approximately this much gas
所以我们的 "store" 函数看起来大约需要这么多 gas
and our simple storage costs approximately this much gas.
以及我们的 "SimpleStorage" 大约需要这么多 gas
This is incredibly helpful for figuring out
how to optimize our gas as best as possible.
Now I usually like to take it a step further though.
Having the gas output it like that is nice, but we can make it even better.
I like to output it to a file by doing output file. Yes, report dot txt
and then my dot get ignore like to add it in here,
but doing gas report dot txt sentence it's not really
important for the gas report to get pushed up to GitHub. Do no
colors is true. The reason we add this is because when we
output to a file, the colors can get messed up basically. And
then the biggest addition we could do is we can add a
currency in here. So that we can get the cost of each function in
USD for a blockchain like Aetherium. Now in order to get a
currency here, we actually need to get an API key from corn
market cap, just like we did with ether scan, you can go to
coin market cap, corn market cap API, get your API key now, and
we'll go ahead and sign up. Choose a basic plan. We'll agree
and create my account, we'll get an email verification. And we'll
go ahead and verify. Now in the coin market cap dashboard, we
can copy our key. And yep, you guessed it exactly what we're
going to do with this key, we're going to drop it into our dot
env file, or say coin market cap, API key equals and then
paste it in there like that. Now that we have our corn market cap
API key in here, we can go back to our header dot config and add
it in this corn market cap parameter. We're gonna do the
exact same way we did above, we'll do const, coin, market
cap, API key equals process dot EMV, that coin market cap API
key, and then we'll take this sticking in here. So what this
is going to do is actually going to make an API call to corn
market cap, whenever we run our gas reporter. This is why
sometimes you'll see me comment this out and uncomment it
because I don't always want it to make this API calls. But now
what we can do now that it's enabled, we have an output file,
we can see the currency and we have our API key, all we can do
is run yarn hardhat test. And after all our tests pass, we're
going to see a gas report.tx T that we can go ahead and read
from which has that gas report. And now it actually has the USD
price of each one of these transactions, it looks like at
current prices, with Aetherium being $3,000 per eath, and a gas
price of 43 Gwei, the store function would cost $6. And the
simple storage function would cost $64. The current the
Hardhead gas reporter actually comes with some different
options, though, if you're going to be deploying to different
network, for example, with binance, Polygon, Avalanche or
hecho. For example, let's say we wanted to deploy the polygon,
let's see how much deploying the polygon would cost well in our
WMV UHD ad token,
Matic And now we'd rerun this test. And if we look at our gas
report that takes T will now see the gas price of polygon right
now is around 37 Gray per gas. And the cost of Matic is 147
automatic and USD. Now we can see the cost of calling the
simple storage method is going to be $0.00. Now this of course
is rounded down, but it's going to be really, really cheap to
call store versus deploying the contract is going to cost three
cents, I make it a habit to select false for my gas reporter
whenever I don't want to actually work with the gas here.
Awesome. Now sometimes when we're working with our code, if
we don't have these environment variables specified Hardhead
might get a little bit upset with us. So oftentimes, I'll add
some code in here. So that these variables are always populated,
because we didn't specify our rink prpc URL, ring P RPC URL is
going to be undefined. And that might throw some errors blow. So
oftentimes, what we'll do is I'll add an or parameter here,
these double pipes mean or, and in JavaScript, if we say some
variable equals something or something else, what is really
happening is we're gonna say, okay, rink, the RPC URL is going
to be equal to process dot E and V dot rink, the RPC URL. But if
this rink, the RPC URL doesn't exist, it's going to be whatever
else is over here. And I might write something like HTTPS eath
Rinkeby. Example, or something like this, just so that I don't
make hard hat mad if I don't use rank B. And we can do something
like that for all these. So you'll see this syntax,
oftentimes in a lot of code setups. Now the last thing that
I'm going to show you before going into the TypeScript
edition of This is test coverage. And as we progressed
to this course, I'm going to show you more and more tools
that you can use to make sure that our simple storage contract
is safe and secure. And we take all the steps we can to prevent
any hacks from happening if we deploy in real life. One of
those tools is a tool called solidity coverage. And this is
also a hardhat plugin that we can use for our code. solidity
coverage is a project that goes through all of our tests and
sees exactly how many lines of code in our sample store dot Sol
are actually covered. And this can be a Good tip off. If we
don't cover some line of code, solidity coverage will say, Hey,
you don't have any tests for this line, maybe you should
write some tests for it. We can add solidity coverage the same
way we've been adding all of our packages. npm install dash, just
save Dev, or since we're using yarn, yarn, add dash dash Dev,
solidity coverage. And we can then add this to our config, the
same way we've been adding everything to our config, go to
our config, and we'll write require solidity coverage. And
there's some configuration pieces we can add down here
below for this, but we're just going to use the default now we
can do is run yarn, RT hat coverage. And this is going to
go through our tests and print out a file that looks like this,
we'll also get a file called coverage dot JSON, which is
basically this chart broken down a little bit more often put my
coverage dot JSON in my dot get ignore. And I know we haven't
actually seen dot Git ignore, do what it's supposed to do. But we
will soon we can see here that about 50% of the code 50% of our
statements in simple storage dot soul are covered. About two
thirds of our functions are and 50% of the lines, It'll even
give us exactly what lines aren't tested right now, which
we can see exactly 31 and 32 of simple swords, outsole aren't
covered, which makes a lot of sense, because 31 to 32 is this
Add Person function, which we didn't call and we didn't add to
our tests. If you want to take this time to pause and try to
make this solidity coverage be 100% across the board, by
writing some more tests, I highly recommend you do so it'll
be a great learning exercise. We'll also add the coverage
folder. So covered adjacent and the coverage folder, which
again, I'll explain what the dot get ignore folder does a little
bit later.