Alright, also now let's do this with TypeScript.
好的，现在让我们使用 TypeScript 来进行操作
So I am going to go ahead and just start this from our JavaScript section.
我将直接从我们的 JavaScript 部分开始来继续操作
However, if in the future, you want to start a new Hardhead project,
但如果将来你打算开始一个新的 Hardhat 项目
you can actually start a new project with yarn, hard hat.
那么你可以这样操作 "yarn hardhat"
And then do great and advanced sample project that uses TypeScript,
然后选择 "Create an advanced sample project that uses TypeScript"
(“使用 TypeScript 创建一个高级示例项目”)
you'll add a ton of plugins. And you'll wait a while for everything to get uploaded.
它会添加大量插件，你需要稍等一段时间直到所有内容上传完毕
And you wait, and you wait a little bit for everything to get downloaded.
然后再稍微等一会儿直到所有内容下载完成
We're not going to do that though,
我们并不会这样做
because I'm going to show you how to convert this to JavaScript Anyways,
因为我将向你展示如何把这个转换为 JavaScript (口误，应为 TypeScript)
if in future hearted sections, as we're coding along with JavaScript,
在未来的 Hardhat 部分，我们仍会采用 JavaScript 来编写代码
if you want to code along with TypeScript, you absolutely 100% can.
但如果你想用 TypeScript 的话，也是百分百可以的
But let's go ahead and show you what the main differences are.
现在让我来向你展示它们之间的主要差别是什么
Now that advanced TypeScript thing is going to add a whole bunch of packages that you may or may not want,
现在，这个高级 TypeScript 选项添加了一大堆你可能用的到也可能用不到的包
I will talk about some of them in our next lesson.
我会在下节课中讨论其中的某些
But there are going to be some that you absolutely do need.
但有几个是你肯定会用到的
Those are going to be at type chain slash ethers, dash v five, at type chain, slash hard hat,
它们是 "@typechain/ethers-v5 @typechain/hardhat"
at TypeScript, at types, slash Chai, at types, slash node, at types slash moko,
"@types/chai @types/node @types/mocha"
TS node, type chain and TypeScript.
"ts-node typechain" 以及 "typescript"
And I have a link in the GitHub repo associated with this course,
我在课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中提供了一个链接
I've got this yarn ad that you can just copy paste,
这里有一个 "yarn add" 后面的你可以直接复制粘贴
if you want to just copy paste that into your project to run it.
如果你想的话可以直接把它们复制粘贴到你的项目中运行
Oops, and I should have added those as dev dependencies.
哎呀，我还应该把它们添加到 "devDependencies" 里
So we're going to actually just make them dev dependencies real quick,
我们可以很快地把它们放进 "devDependencies" 里
just by deleting these two lines, and adding a comma here.
只要删除这两行，然后添加一个逗号就行了
Awesome, that looks much better.
不错，看起来好多了
And then of course, what we're going to do is we're going to convert all of our JavaScript to TypeScript.
当然，接下来要做的就是把 JavaScript 转换到 TypeScript 了
So anywhere where we have J S, we're going to put Ts,
所以只要是 "js"，一律替换成 "ts"
obviously, if you're coding this from scratch with TypeScript,
显然，如果你要从头开始使用 TypeScript
you would do the.ts From the get go.
这里就要直接写成 ".ts"
This includes our hard hat dot config, that's also going to be TypeScript now.
And additionally, we're going to add a TS config dot JSON.
This is going to be our TypeScript configuration.
Typically, for a setup, we're gonna go with something like this.
And you can copy this from the GitHub repo associated with this course.
It's basically telling TypeScript,
what versions of Typescript and what files to include for working with TypeScript.
Now let's go ahead and start with our deploy dot TypeScript.
For usual, instead of using require,
we're gonna go ahead and use import,
we're gonna do the exact same thing.
We're gonna have import ethers run network, from hard hat.
And then in our verify function, we're going to add that we're gonna add the types for these arguments.
So contract address, is going to be a string.
And args is going to be an array of arguments.
So we're gonna say it's gonna be any array,
because it could be string, it could be numbers, it could be balloons, it could be anything.
We're also going to say for IE, going to say for IE, it could be any,
even though this is technically an error type,
we're just going to put any for simplicity. For now.
All of our TypeScript scripts are included in our TS config,
or any TypeScript files are manually added here,
which we have Our entire scripts folder here, which is good.
So now we need to add ethers in here.
Well, if we look at our hardhead.config.ts, we're using require here still,
and we need to swap this out for import
for Donnie V, you can use dot env slash config for it to grab your dot env file.
Now that we've imported everything, go back to our deploy.ts,
we can see that that linting has gone away.
If you want to be even more explicit, we can go ahead and add import
at nomic labs slash hard hat ethers like so.
reason we don't need to import it here is because these two packages also work with Hardhead ethers,
so they automatically import it. But if you want to be super explicit,
you can go ahead and add it like so.
Now, we're almost good to go.
But remember, our Harnett dot config is also importing our tasks.
So we're going to need to update our tasks or block number to be TypeScript fide.
So of course, instead of const require, we're going to import task from our that slash config.
And we're going to be sure to export our task from lock number as the default.
So we're going to do export default task like so.
And now we should be good to run our scripts.
So we can just do yarn, art hat, run scripts, employee.ts.
We can do network hard hat if we choose. And awesome.
Now, it's when we get to the testing, that things get a little bit different here.
So let's go ahead and change this required to import.
Just to make it happy there.
Let's try to run yarn, art head test, we get a whole bunch of errors, and in VS
code will actually go ahead and get these errors right from the
linter. One of the trickiest things that you run into as a
developer in this space is calling functions on contracts
where those functions don't exist, or vice versa. We're not
calling functions on contracts that do exist. Right now the
typing for our contracts is just type contract, which isn't super
helpful, because type contract doesn't necessarily have all the
functions that we want it to have. We want our contracts to
be of type contract, but we want them to be of the type of our
contract, because if they're the type of our contract, they can
have all the functions that we want them to have. So to give
our contracts the correct typing here, we actually can use this
tool called type chain, which gives our contracts correct
typing type chain has a hardened plugin, which allows us to use
type chain and TypeScript natively together, type chain
slash hard hat was one of these things that we already
installed. And to add it to our hard hat, we got to just go to
the hard hat config, and add it in import at type chain slash
arhat. Now once we import that in to our config, if we run yarn
hardhat, we now get a new task here called type chain, you read
the description, it says generate type chain typings for
compiled contracts, this will enable all of our contracts to
have their own typing. So we can have a simple storage variable
of type simple storage contract, which is much better, because
we're always going to know exactly what we can do with each
contract. To create this, we run yarn,
arhat type chain. And this is going to create a new folder
called type chain slash types. With types for all of our
contracts, you can even go into our simple storage sub Ts, which
is going to have all the different functions and
everything to do with our simple storage contract automatically
coded into Typescript and JavaScript for us, which is
incredibly helpful. And again, no, I haven't shown you what
this is yet. But in our dot Git ignore, we usually want to add
type chain and type chain dash types into our dot Git ignore so
we don't push them up to GitHub. Now back in our test, we're
going to add the exact types of these different objects here. So
we're going to import them from that folder that we just
created. So we'll do import simple storage, comma, simple
storage underscore underscore factory from dot dot slash
types, ain slash types, the simple storage factory is going
to be simple storage factory and then civil storage of course, is
going to be simple storage. So now when do let simple storage
factory which is going to be of type, simple storage, underscore
underscore factory, and then simple storage, which is going
to be of type simple storage contract. And if we command
clicked into simple storage, once again, we can see all the
contract functions that we know and love, are here. In addition,
we have all the functions of the actual contract itself. Once we
do that, we're pretty much good to go we just need to have a
couple of new things here. Get contract factory returns a type
ethers dot contract factory. So what we just need to do is we
need to wrap this in a simple storage factory type. So We'll
just do a little wrap like this. And we'll say, as simple
storage, I'm just going to sort of factory. And that's good to
go. Now that we've added all this, we can run yarn, Hardhead
test. And boom, our test run is normal, but with TypeScript and
with this additional typing that makes our lives substantially
substantially better. And that's going to be all you need to know
for TypeScript, reusable, all of the branches have an optional
TypeScript branch that you can use to reference to work with
TypeScript.