So now we have our contracts in here and our code is compiling successfully.
现在我们有了我们的合约，并且我们的代码已经成功编译
We're probably going Want to deploy our code?
接下来我们要做的是部署我们的代码
Now in our last section, I know we use the scripts module.
在上一节中，我们用的是脚本模块
And we made our own manual deploy script.
并且创建了一个手动部署脚本
However, something that you'd notice, the more that you work with just raw ethers, or even just hard hat
然而，你可能会注意到，当你使用原生 ethers 或仅仅是 Hardhat 进行工作时
is that keeping track of all our deployments can get a little bit tricky.
跟踪所有部署会是一件棘手的事情
If you just use a deploy script,
如果你只使用一个部署脚本
it's not saving our deployments to any file.
它就不会把我们的部署保存到文件中去
Additionally, having everything in the deploy script for deploying
此外，把所有部署都放到一个部署脚本中
can make the tests and the deploy scripts, maybe not work exactly hand in hand.
可能会使测试和部署脚本之间无法完全兼容
And there are a couple of other things that might be a little bit tricky to work on,
而且还可能会遇到一些其他比较麻烦的事
we're actually going to work with a package
我们会使用一个包
that makes everything I just mentioned, and a couple other things way easier.
它会使我刚才提到的所有事情还有一些其他事情变得更容易一些
And this package that I'm talking about is going to be the hard hat deploy package.
而我所说的这个包就是 "hardhat-deploy" 包
There's a link to this package in the GitHub repository associated with this course.
这个包的链接也会放到课程关联的 GitHub 仓库里
It's a hardhat plugin for replicable deployments and easy testing.
它是一个用于可复制部署及简便测试的 Hardhat 插件
And if we scroll down to installation, we can see we install it basically the normal way.
如果我们向下滑到安装部分，就能看到可以用通用方法安装它
They're using npm. And we're gonna go ahead and use yarn.
他们用的是 npm 而我们还是会继续使用 yarn
So for us to add it, we'll do yarn, add hardhat dash deploy.
所以要想添加它，就要执行 "yarn add hardhat-deploy"
And then of course, we're gonna do dash dash Dev.
当然了，还有 "--dev"
Once done deploying this require statement to our hard hat.config.js.
一旦部署（口误，应为“安装”）完成，就需要在我们的 "hardhat.config.js" 中 "require" 进来
Once again, basically the config is our entry point.
再次强调，这个配置文件就是我们的入口点
This is where we're gonna get started.
基本上就是我们一切开始的地方
And we can go ahead and delete our deploy.js script.
然后我们就可以删除我们的 "deploy.js" 脚本了
Now if we run yarn hardhat, you see that we have a bunch of new tasks in here,
现在如果我们运行 "yarn hardhat"，你会看到这里有一堆新的 task
with one of them being this deploy task,
其中之一就是 "deploy" task
this deploy task is going to be the main task that we use to deploy our contracts.
这个 "deploy" task 将是我们部署合约时主要使用的 task
Instead of writing our deploy scripts in the Scripts folder,
这次我们不再在 "scripts" 文件夹中编写我们的部署脚本
we're actually going to create a new folder,
而是创建一个新的文件夹
we can create a new folder by just doing MK dir deploy.
我们可以使用 "mkdir deploy" 来新建文件夹
Or you can always right click and hit New Folder.
或者你也可以右键并点击新建文件夹("New Folder")
This deploy folder is going to be where a lot of hard hat Deploy Module looks to deploy code.
这个 "deploy" 文件夹将是许多 "hardhat-deploy" 模块部署代码的地方
And it's going to be where we are writing our scripts.
同时也是我们编写脚本的地方
To write our scripts, we usually need to add one more thing in here.
为了编写我们的脚本，通常还需要添加一个东西
Since we're going to be using ethers JS in all of our scripts,
因为我们要在所有脚本中使用 "ethers.js"
we want to add Hardhead deploy ethers to our package here.
所以我们要添加 "hardhat-deploy-ethers" 到我们的包里
Now, instead of just doing yarn, add dash dev hard at deploy ethers,
这回我们不再是只运行 "yarn --dev hardhat-deploy-ethers"
we're going to do something a little bit weird.
而是会做一些略显奇怪的事情
We're going to do yarn add or npm install dash dash Dev,
我们要运行 "yarn add" 或是 "npm install --dev"
and we're going to install it like this.
然后按照这样的方式来进行安装
So let me just copy this.
让我来复制一下这个东西
And you can just copy that from the repo.
你也可以直接从代码库里复制
And we'll do yarn, add dash dash Dev, and paste that in here.
然后我们来运行 "yarn add --dev" 并粘贴到这里
What we're doing is we're taking at nomic labs, hard hat ethers, which we've used before,
我们做的就是获取 "@nomiclabs/hardhat-ethers"，这是我们之前用过的
and we're overriding it with hard hat deploy ethers.
然后我们用 "hardhat-deploy-ehters" 把它覆盖掉
Remember how in our last project, we used hard hat ethers.
还记得我们在上个项目中是怎么做的么？我们使用的是 "hardhat-ethers"
So that hard hat could override ethers to use hard hat deploy.
所以 Hardhat 可以覆盖 ethers 使用 "hardhat-deploy"
(译者注：这句中的 hardhat-deploy 很可能应为 hardhat-ethers)
We use hard hat deploy ethers, so that hard hat deploy can override Hardhead,
我们使用了 "hardhat-deploy-ethers" 所以 "hardhat-deploy" 可以覆盖 Hardhat
which overrides ethers, which is kind of funny.
而它又覆盖了 ethers，这还挺有意思的
When you say like that, this will enable ethers to keep track of and remember
这样做的话 ethers 就能够跟踪并记住
all the different deployments that we actually make in our contract.
我们所部署的所有不同合约
So if we look at our
package, JSON, and now we can see our nomic labs dashboard had
ethers. Now the version of it is going to be MPM. Hardhead deploy
ethers. This is our package dot JSON, basically saying the hard
hat ethers package is now overwritten by the hard hat
deploy ethers package, which is what we want. Alright, great. So
now that we have that setup, we can start writing our deploy
scripts, the way that Hart had to play works is all the scripts
that get added to our deploy folder will get run when we run
yarn, hard hat deploy. So a good practice is usually to number
them so that they run in the order that you want them to run
in. So since we only have one contract that we want to deploy
the Funmi contract, we're going to do 01 Deploy Funmi Jas, and
in this script, this is going to be where we define how to deploy
the fundament contract. Alright, so we're in our deploy Funmi
scripts. Now traditionally, what did we do, we did imports, we
did the main function. And then we did calling of main function,
that Hardhead deploy is a little bit different, we're still going
to import our libraries and packages, but we're not going to
have main function. And we're also not going to call the main
function when we run Hardhead deploy Harnett deploy is
actually going to call a function that we specify. In
this script here. What we're going to do is we're gonna
create a function, we'll call it deploy funk.
We're going to export this deploy function as the default
function for Hardhead deploy to look for, so we could say,
module that exports dot default equals deploy funk. To test it
out, we can go ahead and do console dot log, hi. And then in
our terminal, run yarn, hard hat, deploy. Oops, get rid of
the parentheses here. Sorry. Run it again. And we can see it went
and ran our deploy func here. Now if this syntax is easier for
you to understand, go ahead and use this syntax and we're going
to be passing the heart at runtime environment as a
parameter to this function. However, if we go to the heart
hat deploy documentation, and we scroll down to an example
script, the syntax looks a little bit different. And let me
just explain what's going on here and how we're going to be
writing ours. So instead of kind of defining everything like
this, and defining the function name, similar to what we were
doing before, we're actually going to using a nameless, a
synchronous function, we're going to make it an anonymous
function, similar to what we've seen before. So instead, we're
going to say async parameters like this, I'm going to pass our
parameters our heart at runtime environment in here. And it's
going to be an arrow function. And then we're going to wrap
this whole thing in module dot exports. So we're gonna say,
module, dot exports, equals this async function like this. This
syntax here is nearly identical to what's up here, we just don't
have a name for our async function. So this is how we're
going to set it up instead. But if this syntax is a little bit
confusing for you feel free to use this above as the two of
these are going to be the same. Now the next thing that most of
the documentation does is it pulls out the variables and
functions out of the HRV that we're going to use. HRV is the
heart hat runtime environment. Whenever we run a deploy script,
heart hat deploy automatically calls this function and just
passes the hard hat object into it similar to in back in hard
hat simple storage. In our deploy script. We had ethers run
in network come from hard hat, instead of coming from hard hat.
We're coming from HRV, which is basically the same thing as hard
hat. For our script, we're only going to use two variables from
a jury when you use const. Get named accounts. And deployments.
This syntax might look a little bit weird for you. But it's just
a way to pull these exact variables out of a tree. It's
kind of the same thing as just doing a tree dot get named
accounts and HRA dot deployments. But pulling them
out like this means we don't have to add a tree at the
beginning anymore. And then additionally, additionally,
JavaScript has something called syntactic sugar. So instead of
doing this on two lines like this, we can actually do that
whole bit on one line. So instead, we just extrapolate
those two variables, right in the function declaration. So
this line is the exact same thing as doing this line. This
is an asynchronous, nameless function using the arrow
notation, or working with our deploy scripts here. And we're
default, exporting it with module dot exports. I don't know
that was a lot. And another is kind of a lot of syntactic sugar
here. But if that's really confusing for you, just feel
free to use the above. And whenever we refer to get named
accounts, you can also just do a three dot get named accounts, or
a three dot deployments. So hopefully, that's clear that
this top part is gonna be the same as this bottom part right
here, whichever one you feel more comfortable working with.
But alright, now that we've gotten all that out of the way,
let's continue with the script. So we're using this deployments
object, reason this deployments object to get two functions,
those two functions are going to be the deploy function, and the
log function. So we're gonna say const, deploy log equals
deployments. So we're going to pull these two functions out of
deployments. And then we're also going to do const Deployer.
Equals await, get named accounts. So we are grabbing
this new deploy function, this new log function, and we're
grabbing this deployer account from this weird get named
accounts function. What's this get named accounts function,
this get named accounts is a way for us to get named accounts.
When working with ethers we saw when working with ethers, we can
actually get our accounts based off of the number in the Account
section of each network. So for example,
in this list of private keys, private keys zero private key
one private key two, it might get a little confusing to
remember which ones which so instead of working like that, we
can add a section at the bottom called named accounts where we
can name each one of those spots in the accounts array. So we'll
do named accounts. And we'll say one of the accounts that will
name is going to be named Deployer. And we're gonna say by
default, the zero with account is going to be Deployer. We can
also specify which number is going to be the deployer account
across different chains. For example, on Rigby we wanted the
deployer account to be the first position, we could do something
like this or on hard hat, we could do it like this. We can
create multiple users. Like for example, if we wanted to do a
user for some test or something, and we'll just say the default
is one or whatever we wanted in here. So back in our deploy fun
me We're going to say we're going to grab that deployer
account from our named accounts. And then finally, we're going to
grab our chain ID for reasons that will come clear pretty
soon. So we'll do const, chain ID equals network dot config dot
chain ID.