Now, how do we actually deploy this fund me contract?
现在，我们该如何部署这个 "FundMe" 合约呢？
Well, let's think about this for a little bit.
让我们来仔细考虑一下这个问题
When working with remix, it was pretty easy, right?
当我们使用 Remix 的时候，这是件很简单的事，对吧？
We just deployed it to a test net.
我们只要直接把它部署到测试网络上就行了
Ah, that's kind of the issue there, isn't it
啊，但这就是问题所在不是么？
deploying to a rink, the test net is a little bit slow.
部署到 Rinkeby 测试网上实在是有点慢
We don't always want to have to deploy to one of these slow test nets or even a main net
我们不想总是在这些慢速的测试网或主网上进行部署
when tinkering and fiddling with our contracts, do we
从而调试和修改我们的合约，是吧？
know that's gonna be really bad,
是的，那真的很糟糕
we really want to deploy to a test net as a last stop after we've done all our testing locally.
我们想要的是将部署测试网这一步作为本地测试之后的最后一步
Or we can deploy it to a test that to see some very specific code work,
或者我们可以提前将其部署到测试网络以查看某些特定代码如何工作
like for example, with the chain link documentation.
例如与 Chainlink 文档一起使用
So ideally, we deploy this to a local network first. But can we just do that?
理想情况下，我们应当首先部署到本地网络上，但我们真的可以直接这样做么？
Well, if we look in our price converter, dot Seoul,
如果查看一下我们的 "PriceConverter.sol"
we have this hard coded address in here, this 0x address,
我们会发现这里有一处硬编码地址，就是这个 0x 地址
if we go to Doc's dot chain that link EVM chains, contract addresses for Aetherium data feeds.
如果我们前往 "docs.chain.link"-"EVM Chains"-"Contract Address"-"Ethereum Data Feeds"
That address is the eth USD, specifically for Rinkeby.
那个地址是 "ETH USD" 的地址，具体来说是 Rinkeby 的
What if we work on the Hard Hat Network?
如果我们想在 "Hardhat Network" 上运行呢
Example? default network? Hard Hat.
比如说 `defaultNetwork: "Hardhat"`
And then like I said before,
就像我之前说的
if you don't write this in part, it is automatically the default network.
如果你这里不明确指定，那么 "hardhat" 将自动作为默认网络使用
But if we're to point to the Hard Hat Network,
但如果我们就要指向 "Hardhat Network"
harder network is a blank blockchain.
"Hardhat Network" 是一个空白的区块链
And it gets destroyed every time our scripts finish,
每次我们的脚本运行完毕后它都会被销毁
or even if we're working with a local node,
又或者即使我们在本地节点上工作
this price feed contract won't exist,
这个 "priceFeed" 合约将不再存在
one of the code there won't be updated with data. So what do we do?
其中某些代码将无法更新数据，那么我们该怎么办？
How do we test and interact with our code locally? Is there a way we can do this?
我们该如何在本地测试中与我们的代码进行交互？有没有什么方式可以做到这一点？
Well, one of the ways that we can do this that we'll learn a little bit later
嗯，之后我们会学习一种方法
is actually forking a blockchain, where you can keep stuff hard coded.
就是所谓的分叉(fork)一个区块链，你可以在其中保留硬编码内容
But usually, it's still better to figure out how to do everything with something called mocks.
但通常来说，最好的方法还是使用一种被称为 "mocks" 的方法来完成所有的操作
There's a great Stack Overflow question that just says, What is mocking
这里有一个很好的 "Stack Overflow" 问题问的就是，什么是 Mocking？
and mocking is primarily used for unit testing, which we'll talk about in a little bit.
mocking 主要用于单元测试，我们稍后会详细讨论
And object under test may have dependencies on other complex objects.
受测对象可能依赖于其它复杂的对象
To isolate the behavior of the object,
为了隔离某些对象的行为
you want to replace other objects by mocks that simulate the behavior of the real objects.
你需要使用 mocks 对象来替换其它对象，以模拟真实对象的行为
In short, mocking is creating objects that simulate behavior of real objects.
简而言之，mocking 就是创建一个模拟真实对象行为的对象
Now, this might seem like a lot of words.
看起来它说了很多东西
But basically, what we want to do is we want to make a fake price feed contract
但基本来说，我们想要的就是一个虚拟的 "priceFeed" 合约
that we can use and we can control when working locally.
以供我们在本地工作时能够使用并进行控制
So back here, I'm just going to leave a note in here saying,
所以在这里，我会留下一条注释说
When going for local host or Hard Hat Network, we want to use a mock.
当使用本地主机或 "Hardhat Network" 时，我们要使用 mock
Okay, great, well, we can use a mock
OK 好，现在我们要使用 mock 了
and we'll learn how to make one of those in a little bit.
之后我们将学习如何来创建一个 mock
Well, what happens when we want to change chains,
但是当我们想切换链的时候会发生什么呢
for example, back in dots dot chain to link EVM chains, contract addresses,
举个例子，回到 "docs.chain.link"-"EVM Chains"-"Contract Address"
there are a ton of different block chains that have price feeds on them.
这里有很多不同的区块链都有价格数据源
And on each one of these blockchains,
并且在这些区块链的每一个上面
the eth USD price feed is going to be a little bit different.
"ETH/USD" 的价格数据可能会有一点不同
For example, we're looking at ETH USD,
比方说，如果你查看 "ETH/USD"
the address of eth USD for Aetherium main net
以太坊主网的 "ETH/USD" 地址
is different from the address of eth USD for Rigby,
与 Rinkeby 的 "ETH/USD" 地址是不同的
which makes sense, they're totally different contracts on different chains,
这是有道理的，它们是不同链上完全不同的合约
they have very similar functionality. And they do nearly the exact same thing.
它们有非常相似的功能，做的也几乎是完全相同的事
But they're still different.
但它们仍然是不同的
We're also going to need a way for us to modularize or parameterize, this address in here,
我们还需要一种方法来把这里的地址给模块化或参数化
so that no matter what chain we deploy to,
这样无论我们部署到哪个链上
we don't have to change any of our code,
我们都不需要改动任何代码
we can always have our code be exactly the same.
这样我们的代码可以始终保持一致
And we don't have to come in here and like flip values and flip variables and stuff. So
let's keep that all of that in mind as we write the rest of this.
Now in order to parameterize. This,
we actually want to prioritize and do a little refactoring of our fundamental soul.
Refactoring basically means going back and,
and changing the way your code works.
Right now we have this constructor function, right
the constructor function is the function that automatically gets called whenever we deploy our contract.
Right now it's not doing a whole lot
right now it's just updating the owner variable to be whoever sent in the contract.
But we can actually have a do much more than that.
Since this constructor is a function just like every other function,
we can actually have it take parameters,
one of the parameters that we might like for it to have is going to be the address of a price feed.
So let's go ahead and add this and figure out how to refactor all this code.
So we're going to add constructor address,
price feed for the constructor in here.
When we deploy our contract. Now
we're going to pass it the eth USD price feed address depending on what chain we're on.
If we're on rink B, we'll use this address
if one polygon will use a different one b&b, different one, Gnosis hecho, avalanche, etc, you get the picture.
So we're going to marginalize this like so.
Now that our constructor takes a parameter for the price feed,
we can actually save an aggregator v3 interface object as a global variable
in our price converter,
we just create a price feed variable of type aggregator v3 interface,
which again, we're importing from the chainlink repo,
which is an interface object which gets compiled down to the ABI.
If you match an ABI with up with an address, you get a contract that you can interact with.
So we're going to do the same thing here.
We're gonna say, aggregate Tor, v3 interface, public price feed,
ration and call this price feed address
so that these don't have the same name.
And in our constructor, we're going to say price feed equals,
and we're going to do the exact same thing we did with our price converter
equals aggregate tore the three interface of price feed address.
Like so
now, we have this price feed address
that's variable and modularized, depending on whatever chain that we're on.
Now, what we can do is we can grab this price feed address,
and we can use it for our price converter.
So where are we using our price converter?
Well, just a quick reminder, we're using using price converter for you at 256.
We're using this as a library on top of our unit 256 type.
So we're calling message dot value dot get conversion rate.
So we look at our price converter, we have this function get conversion rate,
which takes an FML as its initial parameter,
which again, since this is a library,
it automatically passes the message dot value into this get conversion rate function.
But we could also pass in this price feed,
and therefore we wouldn't need to hard code it in the get price anymore.
So let's go ahead and figure out how to do that.
Well, what we can do is we can do message dot value dot get conversion rate,
we'll stick price feed in here.
And then we'll have to update our get conversion rate
to do a comma so that it takes a second parameter,
because remember, again, the initial parameter is going to be message dot value.
And the second parameter is going to be what we define here.
So we'll do s amount, comma ag reg gate Tor v3 interface.
And we'll call this price feed.
And now, when we call our get price function,
we can pass the price feed to the get price function.
And up here we can have get price.
Take, you guessed it an aggregate or the three interface called price feed.
And now we no longer need to hard code in the price feed.
And we can just delete those lines and have it compile like this, which is awesome.
So quick refresher, we're parameterizing that price feed address
and passing it in with a constructor that gets saved as a global variable to an aggregator v3 interface type,
or passing it to a get conversion rate function,
which passes it to the get price function, which then just calls latest round data.
And we probably could have made this even easier, probably could have just got rid of the get price function
and stuck this code in the get conversion rate.
But we'll leave it there for now.
Now that we've done that refactoring, let's make sure it works.
Yarn Hardhead, compile, invalid value undefined for hardhat dot config dot networks.
Let's go to the let's go to the config real quick.
That's because the default network needs to be outside of networks.
My mistake. Let's try that again. I spelled interface wrong and the price converter.
And a quick note, if gives you an error like this,
oftentimes, you can command click or control click and open that file up right in the editor,
which saves you some time, we're going to have defined the line and find the file.
But yeah, let's spell that correctly.
And let's try this again.
And awesome. It looks like it's compiling correctly.
And we just have some warnings,
it looks like these warnings are just about this git version,
which is because we're shadowing this, we're creating a new price variable down here,
you've no we just created a global price free variable.
Let's just go ahead and delete the get version function altogether
since we're not even going to really need it.
And we only use the Git version to show you how to actually start working with interfaces.
And then we'll compile it one more time for good measure.
Boom compiled successfully. Awesome.
So now we've just refactored our code.
So we can pass a price feed address depending on the network that we're on.
Okay, great. With all that being said, let's come back to our deploy Funmi script,
and let's learn how to actually deploy the rest of it.
In order for us to deploy a contract
we remember from our last sections that we use the contract factories,
with heart hit Deploy, we can just use this deploy function.
And to use the deploy function,
we'll say const Funmi, which is going to be the name of our contract,  equals await.
And we'll call this deploy function, the name of the contract that we're deploying right now,
and then a list of overrides that we want to add here.
So we're gonna say who is actually deploying this by saying from,
we're gonna say it's from the Deployer.
We're gonna pass any arguments to the constructor In this args piece here,
which we just added a single Argh.
So these brackets, we're going to make it a list of arguments, we're going to put the price feed address in here, which we'll show you how to do
in a second, put price feed address. And then we're also
going to do some custom logging here so that we don't have to do
all that console dot log stuff that we've been doing this whole
time. And we need to put something in here. We need to
put an address in here. And you can use this backslash star to
put like a common in between your code.
We can't just do const address equals, you know the address and
stick it in here. Well, I mean, we could but we're not really
prioritizing now. Right? We're kind of back to just hard coding
it here. So what can we do instead? Well, what we can do is
we can actually use the chain ID to do something like if chain ID
is x, use address, Y, or if chain ID is Z use address A. So
we can do something that looks like this. And to enable this
functionality, we actually take a page out of the Ave GitHub. So
Ave is another protocol that's on multiple chains and has to
deploy their code to multiple chains and work with multiple
different addresses. So what they do is they use a number of
different useful tricks. But one of the main ones is using this
helper hardhat config. Now they're using TypeScript with
JavaScript, but it's gonna be the same thing. With this
config, they have different variables, depending on what
network that they're actually on. And depending on the network
that they're on, they use different variables. So they use
this network config almost to do exactly what we're trying to do
here. So what we want to do is we're going to create a new file
at the root directory, so just click down here, new file. And
we're going to call it helper, hard hat config dot j, s. And
this is where we're going to define that network config. And
this is where we're going to say, hey, if you're on network,
a, use this address network, be this use this address, etc. So
we're going to create an object called const. Network config.
equals and we're going to add a bunch of stuff in here. So our
main network that we're working with right now is rinky. dinky
has a chain ID of four. So we'll say chain ID four is going to be
named Rinkeby. And the eth USD price feed address is going to
be the price feed address of rank B of the eth USD price
feed. So we're going to copied from the documentation or from
the GitHub, whatever you want to do, and paste it in here. Now we
have a simple methodology of keeping track of different price
feeds a different contract addresses across different
chains. Let's say for example, we wanted to deploy to Polygon
as well. Well, first, what are we going to need? Well, we're
going to need the chain ID of polygon. So a quick little
Google Search brings us to the polygon documentation. And we
see the chain ID is 137. So I'll do 137. What's a little brackets
here, we'll say name, polygon. Then we'll do a comma eth USD,
price feed. And then we'll add the price feed of eth USD on
polygon. So docstoc, chain link, polygon or Matic and then we'll
look up eth, USD. And boom, we see it right here. We've grabbed
this address, and we paste it in. Well, what about the
Hardhead? Network? We'll get to that in just a second, don't you
worry. And then at the bottom, we need to export this network
config. So our other scripts can actually work with it. So we'll
do module dot exports equals network config. And we're going
to actually export a couple of things from this file, which is
why we're doing it like this instead of that default way that
I showed you before. So back in our script, now, what can we do?
Well, first, we want to go ahead and import that network config.
So we'll say const. Network config equals require, and then
we'll import it, we'll go down and directory to help our
Hardhead config and save. And I just want to mention this one
more time, just so that it doesn't confuse anybody. This
syntax here, constant network config with the little curly
braces around it is the same is if I went const. Helper config
equals this thing, which helper config is now kind of this whole
file. And then const network config equals Hopper config dot
network config. So again, this index is just kind of an easy
way to extrapolate or pull out just the network config from
this file. So that's how that works. And that's why we export
it at the bottom so that we can do this, please use the GitHub
repository to ask questions and discussions especially about
some of this JavaScript stuff. Alright, great. So now that we
have this network configured here, we can now do this part of
where we say if China d z use a if chain ID is x use y. So Since
our helper config is nicely in this kind of dictionary, key
value pair style, what we can do is we can say const. eth USD.
Price feed address equals network config at the chain ID,
because if Francina D, or it'll be this object, French entity
polygon, it'll be this object at the eth USD price feed, we're
going to save this to eth USD price feed address. And now no
matter what chain we're on, whenever we run hard hat deploy,
if I run yarn, hard hat deploy dash dash network Rinkeby. This
chain ID is going to be four. And so it's going to use this
price feed address. If I do dash test network polygon, and I
remember to add both ring P and polygon to my networks, like
here, the channel is going to be 137. It's going to use this
price feed address. So this is awesome. This is exactly what we
want. But is it everything that we want? Those of you who have
been questioning while I have been coding and talking, you
might be thinking, Okay, well, you talked about this marking
thing. You talked about localhost and hard hat. And how
do we test this locally? Like this is how we go to a test net
and a main net. But what about a local network? And that is
exactly what we're going to talk about now. So we've modularized,
our code and parameterize our code so that we're going to use
the address based off of the chain that we're on. But what if
we use a chain that doesn't even have a price feed address on it?
What do we do there? This is where we actually create those
mock contracts. The idea of mock contracts here is if the
contract doesn't exist, we deploy a minimal version of it
for our local testing, or our local testing. And deploying
mocks is technically a deploy script. So what we do actually
is back in our deploy folder is we're going to create a new
file, and we're going to call it 00 Dash deploy mocks dot j s, we
started with 00. Because this is almost like the pre deploy
stuff, we only do this, sometimes we don't always deploy
mocks, right, we don't need to deploy mocks to Rinkeby, or
polygon or or Aetherium main net, because those already have
these price feeds, we're actually going to deploy our own
mock price feed contracts. And in our deploy Funmi script,
we're going to use our own contracts, instead of already
established contracts. If we're on a network that doesn't have
any price, few contracts, like hard hat or locos, for example.
So let's write our deploy mock script. So the setup of this is
going to look nearly identical to our deploy Funmi. And again,
if you want to set it up like this, you absolutely can. But
I'm actually just going to copy this, this part, paste it in
here, because that initial part is going to be exactly the same.
Oh, and over here, I just realized that we're calling this
network thing without being defined, JavaScript will kind of
be smart enough to know where this network thing is coming
from. But it can be a little bit confusing. So it's better to be
really explicit, and say, const. Network equals require hard hat,
this network thing is coming from hard hat. And we're going
to grab this line. And we're also going to use this at the
top of our script here. And then our top section is going to look
exactly the same as well, we're going to grab these three lines,
and paste them in deploy deployer chain ID, boom, it's
all going to be the same here, because we're setting up to
deploy some stuff. Now we want to deploy a new contract. But if
we look at our contracts folder, this is all we have right now.
So we're going to need to add this mock this fake contract to
our contracts folder. Now what we can do is in our contracts
folder, we want to separate this file from the rest of our file
so that we know okay, this isn't part of our project, but it is
part of our testing. So we're going to right click Create New
Folder. And we can either call it mocks, or test I like to call
mine test. And inside of this folder, we can go ahead and
right click create a new file, I'm going to create a new file
and call it mock, v3 aggregate tore that soul. And this is
where we're going to define our mock price feed aggregator
ourselves. So how can we create our own fake price feed
contract, so we can test everything locally? Well, one
thing we could do is we go to the chain link GitHub repo, and
go through the contracts and find one of these price feed
addresses, source eight, or maybe we'll go back to source
we'll maybe we'll check in V six.
Looks like we could find some stuff and look around and we
probably copy paste all this code, but it really seems like
kind of a huge pain in the butt to have to copy all this code.
Now we absolutely could we copy paste the code in here, but
we're gonna do something a little bit more clever. So the
chainlink repo actually comes with some mocks. If we go to
contracts, SRC V 0.6 tests They actually have a mock v3
aggregator dot soul in here that we can use as our mock. So we
can copy paste everything, but we'd have to revamp a little bit
of it because it's doing some dot dot stuff. It's talking to
other contracts that are locally in this file structure that are
not going to be in our file structure. So instead though,
what we can do is we can use this node modules package to our
advantage, we can just say pragma, solidity, carrot zero,
point 6.0, we'll use the same version that that package is
doing. And then just do import at a chain link slash contracts
slash SRC slash v 0.6. Slash tests slash mock, B, three egg,
Reg, gay tore that soul. And then we'll add, and then of
course, we'll add spdx, license identifier, MIT. And boom, this
is actually all we need. If we just import the code like this,
remember, this is exactly the same as copy pasting this
contract into our project, of course, with this path resolve
to where it actually is in our node modules. Now, actually, I
can run yarn hardhat compile, and it will also compile this
contract. Except for of course, we have an issue, hey, compiler
versions don't match. Right? What's What's up with that now,
you're going to get into situations where you will be
working with contracts that are not the same version of solidity
as you why well because contracts keep being deployed
all the time. And there are a ton of contracts that are in
version 0.4, solidity, 0.5 0.678, and probably 910, or
15 billion, or however many solidity versions will come to
be. So in our config, in our hard hat dot config, when you
scroll to the bottom, we can scroll to where we're defining
our solidity version. And we can actually add multiple solidity
versions, so that our compiler can compile multiple versions of
solidity. To do that, we'll say, so Lyd, did T. And we'll turn it
into an object here, we'll make sure to put this comma here. And
inside our solidity object, we'll put compilers and we'll
have a list of compilers. Our first one we'll say is version,
zero, point 8.8. And we'll say our second one is going to be
version 0.6, point six, and then we'll go ahead and save that.
And it looks like mine wanted to format it like this, which is
fine. Now, we can go ahead, rerun, yarn, Hardhead, compile,
and boom, compiled five solidity files successfully. This means
that our Mark V aggregator should also have been compiled.
And if we look in artifacts, at chain link, do indeed see this
at chain link slash contract slash SRC bid, and a v 0.6. In
tests, we see this mock aggregator dot soul, which has
been compiled. Awesome. So now that we have our mock contract
compiled, we now have a contract that we can use to deploy a fake
price feed to a blockchain. So how do we actually do this?
Well, it's going to be the exact same way that we deployed the
Funmi contract. But we're going to add a little if statement in
here, we don't want to deploy this mock contract to a test net
or a network that actually has a price feed on it, we could just
do something like if chain ID does not equal, you know, some
chain ID, then deploy marks, right. And then this is kind of
pseudocode. Obviously, this code won't actually work. But
instead, what I like is I actually like to specify which
chains are going to be my development chains, which chains
are going to be the one that I can deploy these mocks to, in my
helper, hard hat config, I'll define these chains. So I'll say
const, development chains, equals, and then I'll just say
hard hat, and local host. I'll export these. And back in my
deploy mocks, I'll import these with const. Development chains
equals require dot dot slash helper Hardhead config. And now
I'll say if development chains dot includes chain ID. This
includes keyword basically is a function that checks to see if
some variable is inside an array, then we're gonna go ahead
and deploy Max, and which is what we want to do. So we'll do
log, which we're getting from deployments, which is basically
console dot log. And we'll say local network detected,
deploying mocks.
And we'll do a weight ploy, and we'll deploy our new mock v3
aggregator mock v3 aggregator will do a comma. There a little
colons here. If we want to get really specific, we can say
contract v3 aggregator which we're kind of already saying
we'll say from deployer We'll say logging is going to be true.
And then we need to pass some arguments, we need to pass the
constructor parameters for the mock v3 aggregator, which are
what? Well, let's go to docs chain to link to find out. Or
you can also just go to Node modules chainlink, SRC V 06,
tests, and then all the way down to mock V three, aggregated out.
So where you could also find the constructor in here, whatever
one you like better, sometimes I find it easier just to read
GitHub Ctrl plus F or Command plus F for constructor. We see
it takes a decimals and an initial answer. And if we read
through the code, we'll learn that the decimals object is
going to be equivalent to the decimals parameter is going to
be equivalent to this decimals function and the initial answer.
And the initial answer is basically just going to be what
is the price feed starting at, we actually get to pick the
price of the price feed, which works out really well, because
that works out great for testing. I usually like to
define the decimals and the initial answers somewhere
outside of this function so that I can access it later. One good
place you can add it is once again in our helper Hardhead
config.js. So I might do const decimals equals eight. And then
const initial answer. Answer equals, and we'll do 2000. So
since we have a decimals, we'll do 2000 And then 123456788
decimal places, and then we'll export these as well. Export
decimals, and export initial answer. We could of course, just
do you know, const decimals equals eight at the top and then
initial answer and then use them down here. But I like to do it
like that. So Conce. So now we have to import them in here.
const development chains. It's also grabbed decimals. It's also
grabbed initial answer, we'll save it. We'll take a look back
at the constructor looks like it's decimals first, initial
answers second. So in our arguments, we'll do decimals
first, initial answers second, and tada. And then we will be
all done that we'll do a quick log box deployed. And then I
also like to do kind of like a big line at the end of all of my
deploy scripts just to be like, hey, that's the end of this
deploy script. Anything else after this is going to be a
different deploy script. All right, great. Now our deployed
mocks script is actually done. But our deploy Funmi script
isn't quite done. Is there a way that we could run only our
deploy mock script? Well, yes, there is. Great, thanks for
asking. What we can do at the bottom of our deploy mock script
is we can add a module that exports dot tags, equals, and
we'll say all and marks. Now what we can do is if we run
yarn, hard hat deploy, we can add this flag dash dash tags.
And it will only run the deploy scripts that have a special tag.
So we'll run our mocks tag, which means it'll only run our
deploy mock script. And, and oops, actually, in our helper
config development chains is actually hard hat and localhost.
And I said, we're going to try to do with the chain ID, sorry,
we're going to do this, we're gonna do development chains dot
includes network dot name.
Because our helper config is using names and not chain IDs,
so if development chains that includes that network the names,
then we're gonna go ahead and deploy the mocks. So let's go
ahead and run this yarn here and hit Deploy dash dash tags,
mocks. And perfect we do indeed see our mocks getting deployed
here. This log true means that it's going to spit out stuff
like this. It'll say contract, it's deploying, it'll say the
transaction it's doing and it'll say where it was deployed with
how much gas and awesome This means our deployed Mach script
is working perfectly. So now we have our deploy mocks script
working perfectly. So how do we apply that back to our deploy
Funmi script? Well, we're gonna do the exact same thing here.
Instead of making eth USD price feed address constant variable,
we're gonna say let at USD price you'd variable so that we can
actually update it. And we'll say, if development chains dot
includes network dot name, what we can do with hard hat deploy
is we can just get the most recent deployment using a
command called literally get. So we'll say const. eth USD
aggregator equals await deployments dot get. And then
the name of the contract that we deployed Mach v3 aggregator, and
if you wanted to just do get instead of deployments dot get,
we absolutely could, just by doing it like this. Those are
exactly the same. So we'll get the address like this and then
we'll say eth USD price feed address equals that eth USD
aggregator contract dot address. And then if we're not on a
development chain, if we didn't deploy a mock, we're just going
to do exactly what we did before. With using the network
config. Oh, my goodness. Now, now that we've done all of these
steps, let's add a little log thing at the bottom here with
just a bunch of hyphens. Now, we should have a very robust script
to flip between a local development chain, a test net
chain, a main net chain, and allow us to deploy literally
everywhere without changing any of our solidity. And then we
just take this, this eth USD price feed address and stick it
into logs here. And then at the bottom, we can do module dot
exports, dot tags equals and then we'll just do all and then
we'll call this one Funmi. Oh, now moment of truth. If we did
all this, right, we should just be able to run yarn, hard hat
deploy. And it should work on our local chain, our hard hat
chain. And then it should also work on any test net that we
give it. So let's give this a try. Yarn, Hardhead deploy.
Let's see if this works. Awesome. And we got this all to
deploy locally to our Hard Hat Network, we can see that we went
ahead and we deployed mocks, we did our little underline here.
And then we deployed Funmi deployed at this address with
this much gas. Now, what are the other awesome things about hard
hat deploy? When we run our local blockchain, our own
blockchain node, hard hat deploy will automatically run through
all of our deploy scripts and add them to our node. So now if
I run yarn, hard hat node, we're going to spin up a new
blockchain node, but it's already going to have all of our
deployed contracts on it. So every time we spin up a local
node, now it's going to come automatically packed with the
contracts that we want on it.