So we are going to show us doing this on a test net on Rinkeby.
现在我们要展示如何在
But before we actually test it on Rinkeby,
I'm going to add a little bit of the auto verification piece in here as well,
because we did that in the last lesson.
And we wanted to show how to do it in hard hat deploy as well.
So right after we deploy our Funmi, we can do something similar here,
we'll say, if developer chains includes network dot name,
we'll say if developer chains doesn't include network dot name,
because we don't want to verify on a local network.
So we'll say if not development chains dot includes network dot name,
the exclamation mark, aka the bang
means not when we're talking about booleans.
So we're saying, if the name of the network isn't a development chain,
we want to go ahead and verify and same as last time.
And if process dot e NV dot ether scan API key,
then we're going to go ahead and verify.
Now before we had our verify code, right in our deploy code,
we're gonna do something a little bit different here.
Instead of having our verify code in our deploy scripts here,
we're actually going to create a new folder called utils, which stands for utilities.
And this is where we're going to add different scripts that
we can use across different deployments.
Because let's say we have 50 Deploy scripts,
we're not going to make 50 Deploy functions,
we're just going to add them to our utils folder,
and in our utils folder, or create a new file called verify dot j s,
we're going to add that code from our last project in here.
So if you want, you can go ahead copy paste from our last project over to this one,
or you can pause the video to type it out yourself.
Since we're using the run command here, we're gonna do const run equals require RT hat.
And then at the bottom, we're going to do module exports. Exports equals verify.
Now that we have a verify script in our utils folder,
back in our deploy Funmi we're going to say
const. Verify equals require dot dot slash utils. Slash verify.
And since now in our verified Jas, we have a lot of this trycatch stuff in here,
we can just do a wait. Verify
and a verify once again takes a contract address and a list of arguments.
We'll say await verify, fund me dot address and then the list of arguments.
To make the list of arguments easier to put in.
You can go const args, equals and then we'll just stick our eth USD price feed in here
and then replace this with args
and then take this args and pop it on down into the second parameter here.
All right, great.