Now let's go ahead and deploy this to With the Rinkeby test net,
现在让我们把它部署到 Rinkeby 测试网上
and what do we need to deploy this to the Rinkeby test net?
那么部署到 Rinkeby 测试网上需要做哪些事呢？
Well, let's jump into our hard hat config first.
让我们先转到 "hardhat.config"
And let's clean this up, we don't really need this accounts task,
并且清除掉这些内容，我们并不需要这个 "accounts" task
so I'm just going to delete it,
所以我们要把它删掉
I don't really need this comment. So I'm going to delete this too.
我也不需要这个注释了，所以也要删掉
And let's jump into the network section,
现在让我们进入 "network" 部分
we're not going to be working with ropsten. So we're gonna go ahead and dump that.
我们不会使用 "ropsten"，所以我们扔掉它
We are however, going to be working with rink B, the URL is going to be that same Rinkeby RPC URL.
但我们要使用 "Rinkeby"，"url" 还是一样的 `RINKEBY_RPC_URL`
So we're going to define that up here, like we did before.
我们在这里定义它，就和之前的做法一样
And if you want to copy paste from your last project, feel free to do so
你可以选择从上一个项目中直接复制粘贴过来
you can also follow along with me or fastforward me
也可以选择跟着我或者快进
the counts is going to be the same.
`accounts` 是相同的
I'm going to go ahead and just copy paste the gas reporter with what we had from before.
我这里直接复制粘贴了之前使用过的 `gasReporter`
So we're going to add this
所以我们要添加一句
constant corn market cap API key equals process dot EMV dot corn market cap API key.
`const COINMARKETCAP_API_KEY = process.env.COINMARKETCAP_API_KEY`
Do the same thing with the ether scan API key Licious add everything in here. Now.
`ETHERSCAN_API_KEY` 也是一样的，添加到这里来
We have our ether scan section in here already,
we're gonna have our gas reporter be
false, because I don't really feel like using it right now.
And then finally, we're going to add one more thing in here.
Remember how in our last project, before we actually
verified we waited some block confirmations. That way ether
scan could make sure to catch up. Well, we can do the exact
same thing in here in our hard hat dot config, we can add a
section for each test net for how many blocks we want to wait,
I'm going to add block confirmations of six. Now back
on our deploy Funmi. In a new section, I can add wait
confirmations of network dot config. That block on for
motions, or one is or one means if no block confirmations is
given in our Hardhead dot config will just wait for one block.
And again, the reason we want to wait for approximately six block
confirmations is we want to give ether scan a chance to index our
transaction. And I added a chain ID 42 when it should be for my
mistake. And of course, we're going to need our dot env file,
where we add all of our stuff from the last session, the RIP
ERP CRL private key ether scan API and then coin market cap
API. All right moment of truth. Let's try this out. If we run
yarn Hardhead deploy dash dash network Rinkeby. It should not
deploy any marks because we have this if statement in our mock
deployment. But it should deploy our Funmi contract using the
correct price feed address. And then it'll go ahead and verify
it. Since we're waiting for six block confirmations, we can even
be super secure by adding dash dash tags and just running the
funding tag. But we're just going to do yarn hearted deploy
network Rigby. And let's see what happens. All right, and
we're deploying funding. And we can see the transaction that we
have for fun me, this is that logging feature, we have log is
true for deploying Funmi. So it gives us the transaction once it
has a transaction, and it will give us the address once we have
the address. So we're going to wait six block confirmations for
this transaction to finish going through. Now we see we've
deployed this contract address with X amount of gas. And now
we're running the verification process. While the verification
process is running, we can pull up Rinkeby ether scan, paste our
address in here and see that we have indeed created this
contract. And now it looks like we've successfully verified the
contract on ether scan. So if we hit refresh, we can indeed see
that the contract has been verified. Awesome. All right. So
this is fantastic. Our deploy script is looking great, we're
able to deploy to a local chain, we're able to deploy to a test
that and if we wanted to, we could deploy to any network that
we wanted simply by updating our hard hat config, and then
updating our helper config. This is fantastic.
Great work so far.