Alright, so now that we've cleaned this up,
好了，现在我们已经把这里都整理好了
we've got to deploy marks, deploy Funmi.
我们已经有了 "deploy-mocks" 和 "deploy-fund-me"
Let's go ahead and start writing some tests.
让我们开始编写测试吧
And after we write these tests, we're actually going to run that gas estimator
等我们写完这些测试，就要运行 "gas estimator" 了
and using that gas estimator, we're gonna go back, and we're going to update this contract one more time
使用了 "gas estimator" 我们就可以返回去再次更新合约
to make this even cheaper to use and work with.
以使其使用起来更加便宜
And remember, that's going to be one of the advantages of writing these tests
记住，编写这些测试的优势之一
is how we can optimize our contracts to be even faster, more gas efficient, etc,
就是可以通过它们来优化我们的合约，使其更快速，更节省 gas 等等
we want to make sure that we write really good tests,
我们希望确保我们编写的测试非常好
and this is going to be one of our first jumps into these more professional test setups.
这将是我们迈向更专业的测试设置的第一步
So we're going to jump into our test folder,
所以，现在要跳转到我们的 "test" 文件夹
we're going to delete this sample test.js.
我们要删除这个 "sample-test.js"
In our last section, we went over a really minimalistic test, which is great.
在上一节中，我们介绍了一个非常简化的测试，已经很不错了
However, when we get bigger and bigger projects,
然而，当我们的项目越来越大时
we're going to want to start testing more and more different things,
我们就会开始想测试越来越多不同的内容
we're going to get more and more into at least two different types of testing.
我们将至少进行两种不同类型的测试
So if we cd into our test folder,
如果我们进入 ("cd") 到我们的 "test" 文件夹
we're going to make one directory called staging.
我们要创建一个名为 "staging" 的目录
And then we're going to make another directory called unit.
接着我们再创建另一个目录名为 "unit"
And now if we look in our test folder,
现在如果查看我们的 "test" 文件夹
we now have a staging folder, and a unit test folder.
就会有一个 "staging" 文件夹和一个 "unit" 文件夹
Now we're going to talk about two different types of tests.
现在我们要讨论两种不同的测试类型
The first one is going to be something called a unit test.
第一种被称为单元 ("unit") 测试
Now what is a unit test?
那么什么是单元测试?
Unit testing is a software testing method by which individual units of source code are tested.
单元测试是一种软件测试方法，用于测试源代码的各个单元
Basically, what we want to do is in our contracts,
基本上，我们想要在我们的合约中
we want to test minimal portions of our code to make sure that they work correctly.
测试代码的最小部分，以确保它们正常工作。
Then once our small pieces of the test work,
一旦小的测试片段工作正常
we want to do a staging test or maybe an integration test.
我们就要进行暂存 ("staging") 测试或者说集成 ("integration") 测试
This might be where we run our code on a test net or some actual network.
这可能就是我们在测试网络或真实网络上运行代码的地方
You can think of a staging test, it's kind of the last stop before you deploy to a main net.
你可以将暂存测试看作是部署到主网络前的最后一道检查点
They're not always 100% necessary,
它们并不总是百分百必要的
but they can be really, really helpful.
但它们真的非常非常有用
Remember, we do want to be conscientious of how much we use our test nets,
记住，我们确实需要注意我们使用测试网的频次
but we absolutely would 100% want to make sure that everything works locally
但我们必须确保在本地的一切都工作正常
and that we unit test and we run all of our code locally.
并且我们要在本地进行单元测试并运行所有的代码
Then we can use staging tests on an
actual test net to make sure that our code will work with
actual other contracts. Now unit tests can be done with local
Hard Hat Network or a forked Hard Hat Network, we'll talk
about this for tar Hat Network very soon, right, now, let's
build these unit tests, these unit tests are going to be
basically what we saw in our last section. So let's go in and
let's jump in and write some of these unit tests. So let's
create a new test, we'll call it on me dot test dot j, s. And
we'll start making our tests in here. Now, we did test
previously in our last section, but our tests here are going to
look a little bit differently, we're actually going to use
hardhat deploy, to automatically set up our tests as if both of
these deployed functions had been run. So let's go ahead and
get this started. So we're still going to do that same setup that
we're gonna do describe, we're gonna say fund me. And this is
going to have that async function like so. And in here,
we're going to have a before each, and we're going to have
some hits and some describes and everything. Now since we want to
unit test this, we're gonna go a little bit heavier on the test
here, and then with our last project, but in the future,
we'll go a little bit lighter with some of the tests. So let's
get started. If we run yarn Hardhead test right now, we're
gonna get zero passing. Now, if we run yarn hardhat coverage,
we're gonna get something that looks like this, saying, Hey,
you're missing a lot of stuff. So let's try to cover some more
lines with our tests. And one way we can do that is actually
we can group our tests based off of different functions. So let's
have our first set of tests be around our constructor. To do
that inside of our first describe, we can add another
describe, have this describe the just the constructor, this
larger scope will be for the entire Funmi contract. And
everything inside this one will just be for the constructor. So
this will also be an async function. And these tasks will
be just for the constructor. But before we even work on this
describe, we probably want to deploy our Funmi contract. So
let's learn how to do that. So we'll do a before each, which
will be an async function. And we're going to deploy our Funmi
contract using hard hat deploy. Since we use hard hat deploy,
our Funmi contract will come even with our mocks and
everything. So above the before each,
let's do let me HDMI. And then here, we're going to deploy
Funmi, where we're going to deploy our Funmi contract is
first by pulling in our deployments object from Harnett
deploy. So we'll do const deployments equals require
hardhat. And this deployments object has, has a function
called fixture with fixture does is it allows us to basically run
our entire deploy folder with as many tags as we want. You'll
notice I added this alt tag in both of our scripts. This means
that in this deployment stuff fixtures, it's gonna be a wait
deployment of fixtures. If I run away deployments dot fixture,
I'll run through our deploy scripts on our local network and
deploy all of the contracts that we can use them in our scripts
and in our testing, and we can deploy everything in that deploy
folder with just this one line. isn't that helpful. Now, once
all of our contracts have been deployed, we can start getting
them will say fund me equals await ethers, and we'll pull an
ether some hard hat as well. dot and this is where hard hat
deploy is helpful. Again, hard to deploy rapt ether is with a
function called Get contract, this get contract function is
going to get the most recent deployment of whatever contract
we tell it. So we'll say get contract of fun to me. So this
will give us the most recent Lee deployed Funmi contract in just
this one line. And now Funmi will be equal to this line here.
Now we're going to make a bunch of transactions on our Funmi. To
test it. Of course, we can also tell ethers which account we
want connected to fund me. So I can say const deployer equals
goes away get named accounts, exactly like we did in our
deploy scripts. And then we just need to import it from our tap
in our deploy scripts we imported get named accounts
inside of our input parameters for our deploy function.
Remember getting named accounts and deployments was abstracted
from if we look up here, from the hard hat runtime
environment, and like I said, the hard hat runtime environment
is basically the same thing as hard hat. So we can just go
ahead and import it like this, actually like this. Because we
actually need to abstract just the deployer from getting named
accounts. And now what we can do is we can connect our Deployer
to our Fund Me account. So whenever we call a function with
fund me, it'll automatically be from that the player account,
which is great. Another way you can get different accounts
directly from your heart had config. Is you could take const
accounts equals await ethers dot get signers, ethers dot get
signers is going to return whatever is in this account
section of your network. If you're on your default network
hard hat, it's going to give you a list of 10 fake accounts that
we can work with you then of course, can do something like
const. Account one equals accounts. More correctly would
be account zero equals account zero and work like that. We'll
leave that comment that out, just in case you need a
reference to it in the future. Okay, great. So now we have our
Funmi contract. Let's go ahead and write some tests for testing
the constructor. And we're probably going to want to use
this deployer object down here. So we'll do let deployer above.
And we'll do something a little finicky here. But we'll say
deployer equals Wait, get named accounts, dot Deployer. And
we'll just wrap this up so that we can just grab this deployer
object and assign it to declare like so. Now in here, we'll
create our first test, we'll say it will say it sets the Agra
Gator addresses correctly. Comma will have this be an async
function. And we'll say const response equals await fund me
dot, let's get this price feed here, fund me dot price feed.
And then we'll want to make sure this price feed is going to be
the same as our Mk V three aggregator since we're going to
be running these tests locally. So we should get our mark three
V three aggregator up top. Let's do let mock v3 aggregate store.
And we'll grab this address the same way mockbee Three
aggregator equals await ethers dot get contract mockbee Three
aggregator comma, we'll connect this one to the deployer as
well. So we'll want to say cert dot equals cert dot equal
response comma lock v3 aggregator dot address. And of
course we'll want to say const. Assert equals require gy. Import
that from DJI. Okay, cool.
Now, let's go ahead and try this out. Yarn hardhat. Test. Oops, I
spelled response wrong. Let's try that again. Awesome. So this
means that we are indeed assigning the price feed address
correctly to the Mach v3 aggregator. Okay, great.
Awesome. I think for now, that's all we really want to do for our
constructor. Now these two are kind of a nice to have, I showed
them more just to kind of demo what they look like, we're going
to skip writing tests for them for now. And we're actually
going to go ahead and delete them directly from the contract.
If you want to go ahead and write some tests for them and
leave them in your examples for your learnings. You absolutely
can pause the video and write some tests for it if you choose
so, but we're going to skip them. Next though, we are going
to move on to fund and running some tests for fun here. So
let's go ahead and write describe fund. This will be an
async function. And in here, we're going to do a number of
tests. So if we're going to go line by line here, what's the
first thing that we should look at? Well, we should look at this
require line we should write a test to see if this contract
actually does fail? If not enough, eath is sent. So let's
go ahead and we'll say it fails, if you don't send enough eath
have this be an async function? Now, how do we test to see if
something fails? Right now we've done assert equals, but if
something fails, we might run into an issue. So for example,
if I run await fund me dot fund, but I don't pass any value to
this transaction. Let's see what happens. I run yarn Hardhead
test. Well, our test is actually going to break VM exception.
While processing transaction reverted with reason string, you
need to spend more eath. So our tests are going to break which
is good. We want this to break. But we want to tell our test
that this is okay. Right? Want to tell that this is okay. So
the way we can do this, and this is where our waffle testing
comes into play. With waffle and with testing, what we can
actually do is we can use the expect keyword and expect
transactions to be reverted and for transactions to fail. So
instead of using assert here, we're actually going to run a
wait expect fund me dot fun 2.2 dot B, that reverted and we've
actually even be more specific here by saying to be reverted
with and then the exact reverted error, you need to spend more
eath. Now if we run our tests, oops expect is not defined. So
we need to import that from Chai. Which chai is being
overwritten by waffle, we see that it does indeed Pass, which
is perfect. So now we have a way to both assert things and expect
things to fail. Awesome, even with the specific failure codes.
Perfect. Let's write some more tests here. Well, we probably
want it to correctly update this data structure. So we could say,
it updates the amount funded data structure, it's going to be
an async function. In here, we're going to need to call fund
v dot fund. However, we're going to need to actually pass some
value with this transaction. And for now, we'll just hard code
the value that we're going to send, say const. Send value is
going to be 112345 678-910-1234 5678, which
is going to be one eath. Another way we can write this though, is
we can use the ethers utility to make this a little bit easier to
read. Because all those zeros are kind of confusing, and it's
hard to tell at first glance what this actually is. So we're
gonna actually use ethers dot utils dot parse ether, one, this
parse ethers utility converts this one into that one with 18
zeros, which makes life a lot easier. If you go to the ethers
documentation, there's also a parts units function where you
can actually convert any unit, either ethers or Gwei. Or really
whatever you want to do, you could convert any number to any
other Aetherium you type. So this is the set value that we're
going to use for our fund. And, and this is definitely going to
be more than our minimum USD of 50. So after we call this fun
function, we'll say const response is going to be equal to
a weight, fund me dot address to Mt funded address to Mt funded
for the deployer dot address. Because remember, this is a
mapping of each address and how much they've actually funded. So
if we use the deployer address, it should give us the amount
that we actually sent. So now we can run assert dot equal
response.to string, right, because this response is going
to be the big number version of how much has been funded by that
account. And that should be the same as our send value.to
string. Since send value, our one should be the exact same as
the amount that we funded, we can run just this one test, or
running yarn, art hat, test, dash dash grep. And we'll put
this in quotes allow funded for this amount funded line. And it
looks like we ran into an issue here, because we don't need to
do deployed at address, we can just do deploy here. And great,
it looks like we are indeed passing. Now if we even run yarn
Hardhead coverage will now see we've got at least a little bit
more coverage here. It's still not going to be great. But we
have much better coverage. We have some statements, some
branches, and at least some functions covered. So this is
awesome. Let's keep going. Are we all done testing our fun
function? Well, probably not. What else can we do with our fun
function? Well, we're also adding funders to a funders
array. So let's go ahead and test for that. So it adds funder
to array of funders has been an async function. And we'll say
await fund mean that fund value is going to be send value. We'll
say const response equals await fund me dot calling the funders
array at index zero. So this will be funder equals await fund
me dot funders zero. And then we'll say assert dot equal
funder should be the same as the Deployer. So let's go ahead and
run this test. We'll hit up a couple times. And we'll change
the GREP to under to array so that it looks for this line. And
perfect. It looks like that one is also passing. Great. So the
money's coming through, the minimum amount is coming through
and our data structures are being updated. Awesome. Now we
could be a little bit more verbose and do even more testing
with this fun function. But I think for the most part, we've
got the gist, right. So now let's go ahead and move on to
the withdrawal function. So we're going to create a new
describe or withdraw. This is going to be an async function.
And let's see what the withdrawal function does. Only
the owner of the contract is going to be able to get the
balance, get the money back. And we're also going to reset all of
the amounts that each one of these users is done. So let's go
ahead and do some withdrawing. Now in order for us to test
withdraw, we probably first want the contract to actually have
some money and so what we can do actually is we can add another
before each in the describe to automatically fund the contract
before we run any tests. So we can say before each async
function. We can say await, fund me dot fund. Value, send value.
Now for all of our tests in this withdrawal scope, we're first
going to fund it with eath. Let's say it can withdraw,
withdraw eath. From a single founder, this would be an async
function. And this is going to be a little bit longer test. So
I'm going to set it up to be an arrange, act and assert test. So
arrange act assert is just sort of a way to think about writing
tests, you want to arrange the test, then you want to act. And
then you want to run the asserts, and you'll see what I
mean in just a second. So we're going to arrange this test,
we're going to set this test up, we want to actually check that
we're correctly withdrawing the ether from a single founder. So
first, we're going to get the starting balance of the
fundraising contract and the starting balance of the
Deployer. So we'll say const. Starting under me, balance,
equals await, fund me dot provider, dot get balance, fund
me dot address. So we're gonna start with the balance of the
fund V contract after it's been funded with some eath. And we're
also gonna get costs start starting, deploy your balance
goes await, fund me dot provider, dot get balance of
deployed employer.
So we're getting the starting balance of the Funmi, we're
getting to the starting balance of the employer so that we can
test later on how much these numbers have changed based off
of what happens when we call the withdrawal function. Now that
we've done a little bit of setup, we can actually run this
withdrawal function, we can do the act here. So we're gonna say
const, trans action response equals await, fund me dot
withdraw. And then we can say const, transaction receipt
equals await transaction response. That Wait, one, and
now we should be able to check to see that the entire fund
rebalance has been added to the deployer balance. So now we can
say const ending fund me balance equals a weight on me that
provider dot get balance of Unreal dot address. Then we can
say const ending deployer balance equals await, fund me
dot provider dot get balance
of Deployer. And now we can just check to see if the numbers work
out here.
So we can say assert dot equal ending fund me balance is going
to be zero, right, because we just withdrew all of the money.
So ending funding balance should be zero. And we'll say assert
dot equal starting fund me balance plus starting deployer
balance. So the starting funds the balance plus the starting
employer balance should equal the ending employer balance.
Since we're grabbing whatever the starting deployer balance
started with plus the starting fund to be balanced, because we
just withdrew all of the starting fund, we balance that
should equal the ending deployer bots. Now a couple of notes
here, since starting Funmi balance is calling from the
blockchain, it's going to be of type a big number, we want to
use big number dot add actually, instead of the plus sign here,
just because it'll it'll make working with our big numbers a
little bit easier. So instead of starting Funmi balance, plus
we're gonna be starting from the balance dot add. Like that. And
that should be good. One other thing about this, though, is
that when we called withdraw our Deployer did what our Deployer
spent a little bit of gas. So this actually isn't accurate. We
actually also need to calculate in the gas cost, so we wouldn't
need to do dot add gas cost. We'd also have to do.to string
because big numbers are objects and so identities a little bit
weird. So to test to see if they're equal, we'll just make
them both strings.