Now we're about to jump in and level up our tests.
现在我们要开始升级我们的测试了
But before we do that,
但在此之前
we're going to clean up our Funmi contract a little bit to make it look a little bit more professional.
我们将稍微整理一下 "FundMe" 合约以让它看起来更加专业
And I'm going to talk about some of the syntax and some of the reasons why some conventions exist.
我会讲解一些语法以及一些惯例之所以存在的原因
We're not going to do this full force on all the projects moving forward.
我们不会在之后的项目中往这方面投入很大的力气
But they are good to know and they are good to keep in mind
但了解并记住它们是很有益的
when moving forward and working with our contracts.
尤其是在处理我们的合约的时候
While we go through this we're going to learn why some of these conventions exist
在这个过程中，我们将了解这些惯例为什么会存在
including learning a little bit of low level solidity.
而且会学习一些 Solidity 更底层的知识
So don't skip this part.
因此，请不要跳过这部分
When we get to later sections.
当我们抵达更靠后的章节时
We're going to be a little bit looser and not be as strict with the code style guides
我们会变得稍微宽松一些，不会像代码风格指南那样严格
but That's basically what we're gonna go over now.
但基本上，这就是我们现在要讨论的内容
And for now, you might see this event funded thing here,
现在，你可能会看到这里有个 `event Funded`
please just ignore that for now,
请暂时先忽略它
in an earlier take, I'd introduced the events much earlier.
在较早版本的课程中，我比较早地介绍了 "event"
And now we're actually going to learn about events a little bit later in the course.
但现在我们会在更靠后的课程中学习 "event"
So please ignore that event funded for now.
所以请暂时忽略掉 `event Funded`
So let's go ahead and tweak a little bit of our contracts here.
让我们继续，来稍微修改一下我们的合约
Now what I'm talking about tweaking this to make it look professional, a little bit more professional,
我所说的优化我们的合约以让它看起来更专业的意思
I'm talking about the solidity style guide,
指的就是 Solidity 的风格指南("Style Guide")
there are some conventions for naming and ordering
有一些关于命名和排序的惯例
that we can follow to make our code look a little bit better.
可以通过遵循它们以使我们的代码看起来更好
Now, like I said, this is going to be a little bit more optional,
就像我说的，这是一个可选步骤
because it can be a little bit verbose.
因为它可能会有些冗长
And it doesn't really make that big of a difference.
But it can increase readability of your contracts by a lot and make your code look a lot nicer.
So if you want, you can go through this style guide to learn more about
what kind of makes solidity look nice, and what makes it not look nice.
But well, that's some of these style guides in here,
we're not going to follow the style guide exactly to a tee.
But we are going to make some best efforts to make our code follow the style guide,
we've got a link to the style guide in the GitHub repository for this section,
we can read some more about the layout.
But the main thing we want to look at is this order of the layout,
we want to start with our imports
with our pragma statement, our imports, interfaces, libraries, and then contracts.
And then inside each contract type declarations, state variables, events, modifiers, and functions.
So let's go back here and make sure that we're up to speed,
we want our pragma first.
Alright, awesome, we did exactly that,
then we want our imports. Okay, awesome, we have those too.
Something that's not in the style guide is going to be error codes,
which we definitely want next.
So next is going to be error codes.
Now this is where we're going to bump into one of our first updates here.
As of recent, it's sort of becoming a best practice to
add the name of your contract, some underscores, and then the name of your error.
Whenever you're running into an error.
This makes it a lot easier to understand which contract is throwing the error.
So for this, we're going to say error Funmi, two underscores not owner,
then we're going to scroll down to the our revert and set it like this.
This way, when if we ever run into this error,
we know that the error is coming from the Funmi contract,
not from the aggregator v3 interface,
or the price converter or some other contract.
So that's how we want to write our error codes here.
If we had any interfaces or libraries not imported, we would add them here.
But then finally, we add our contracts.
In this file, we only have one contract here.
It's our Funmi contract. Awesome.
Now the next thing we want to learn about as far as style guides go is this thing scalled natspec.
natspec stands for Etherium natural language specification format.
And it's basically a way of documenting our code inspired by Doxygen
uses Doxygen style comments and tags to help document our code,
you can click the link here in the solidity documentation to learn more about Doxygen.
If we scroll down in the documentation, here,
we can see an example of using natspec.
Whenever we have a contract or a function that needs documentation,
we can add some syntax that looks like this to it.
So for example, if we wanted to add this to our code,
we could add a comment explaining this funding contract
to start a piece of natspec, you can do three backslashes,
or one backslash, two stars, and then another ending star here. x
or one backslash, two stars, and then comment section basically gets turned into a comment.
For the start of our contract, we'll do the Add sign title
to explain basically, what this contract is,
it's fun, we contract is going to be a contract for crowdfunding,
we'll add another star. And we can add the author of it,
which is going to be your name, I'm going to put Patrick Collins, of course,
then we'll add a notice, which is just kind of a note to people
we can say this contract is is to demo a sample funding contract.
And we can also add apt Dev,
which is a note specifically to developers.
And we can say this implements price feeds as our library.
The reason that we want to add these tags here
is actually because we can use the natspec to automatically create documentation for us
if we download so we can actually run solc dash s user doc dash dash dev doc,
and the name of our file to automatically generate documentation.
So this is also really helpful for
automatically creating documentation for other developers who interact with the protocol later on.
You can use this natspec For as many or as few functions as you'd like.
Most of us probably aren't going to be making documentation.
So we really just want to follow those guidelines
if we think some function or some section of our code
is a little bit tricky for other developers.
Now that we're inside of contract, we can follow the order of our contract.
We're first going to start with type declarations
which we don't really have any except for the fact
that we're using our price converter for the UN 256 type.
Okay, great. You Next, after our type declarations,
we're going to do state variables.
And in this state variables section,
this is where we're actually going to change the name of some of our state variables.
So we'll do a little common here state variables.
Now in the solidity style guide, kind of adhere to the naming styles,
we use upper and lowercase, we use total caps with underscores here.
However, these naming variables are going to change in the future in this section.
And if you're following along with the GitHub repo associated with this course,
these are going to be actually a little bit different than what you see.
However, for now, we're going to leave them as they are,
because the reason why we're going to change them isn't going to be quite clear yet.
Don't worry. So these names are going to change soon, but not yet.
Alright, after state variables comes events, and modifiers.
We don't have any events, but we do have a modifier.
So we'll copy this. And actually, we'll delete this comment here.
And we'll paste our modifier here.
Oh, and it looks like looks like we're not auto formatting here.
So we're going to uncomment immutable actually,
so that it automatically auto formats.
Okay, great. We're out of formatting now. And Cool.
Alright, so now we have our modifiers. Next,
we have right here, and then we have all of our functions. Great.
We actually want to group our functions in this order that I just print here.
So we want the constructor which we have received and fall back,
we do have fall back and receive.
So we're going to actually copy those and delete this comment.
We're gonna stick those veterans Heath here looks like receive goes first.
So we'll put that here. Then external functions, then public, internal, private.
So we have public public. And that's it. And then we can delete this part down here. Okay.
Cool. And if we want, we can do that syntax up here from the net spec for our functions.
For example, for fund it, we could even just copy paste,
we would remove title, we would remove author,
and we just say add, notice, this function, funds this contract.
And we can even leave a little dev thing here to talk about it.
Now if we have parameters, you can do apt puram.
And say like what the parameter is.
And then if we have returns, we can say returns,
or returns and then what it returns for the documentation.
Since this doesn't have any parameters in here,
and doesn't return anything, we can just leave it like this.
And great, we've just revamped our contract here
to make it a little bit more nicely formatted. Great job.
Now, like I said, we actually are going to change the names of our state variables,
and we're going to add some functions in here and a little bit.
So if we're following with the GitHub repo,
the state of the contract right now is going to look a little bit different.
But it'll make sense why change this up in a little bit.