Now
another incredibly powerful debugging tool that we're not
really going to go over here. But it's important to know about
because it can be really helpful is that you can actually use
console dot log in your solidity with hard hat. If you're inside
of a heart hat project, you just import hard hat slash console
dot soul. And then right in your solidity, you can do console dot
log, and then type pretty much whatever you want. When you
execute these functions, similar to how we do a console dot log
in JavaScript, those will actually console dot log out to
your terminal. Here's an example of if you run yarn, hard hat
test and you have those console dot logs, you'll see stuff like
this get printed out. So in addition to the Visual Studio
Code debugger, importing hard hat slash console dot Sol, and
using console dot logs in your solidity can also be an
effective debugging strategy. Feel free to give this video a
pause, implement this in some of our contracts and try it out in
our tests.