Okay, great. We have some basic unit tests here.
很好，我们在这已经有了一些基础的 Unit 测试了
And we're going to write some staging tests pretty soon.
我们很快就会编写一些 Staging 测试
But before we actually do that, let's go ahead and add the gas estimator.
但在此之前，让我们来先添加一下 "gas estimator"
And we'll see how much gas these contracts in these functions are taking.
我们要看一下这些合约和函数用掉了多少 gas
It looks like the Hardhead gas reporter is already here.
看起来 "hardhat-gas-reporter" 已经准备好了
So let's scroll down. We'll do gas reporter true.
所以让我们往下拉，把 "gasReporter" 修改为 `true`
And we won't do coin market cap here. And we'll just look purely at the GUI.
这里我们就不使用 "coinmarketcap" 了，只看用了多少 gwei
So you can just comment it out like that.
你可以像这样直接注释掉它
Now rerun all of our tests. So we'll say yarn, our test.
现在重新运行我们所有的测试 `yarn hardhat test`
And in doing so we're gonna get that that gas output in that gas report dash text here.
这样我们就会在 "gas-report.txt" 中得到相应的 gas 输出
So looks like all of our tests are passing, which is perfect.
看起来我们所有的测试都通过了，非常完美
Now we can look into our gas report and see what's going on here.
现在我们可以查看一下 "gas-report"，看看都发生了些什么。
i Well, it looks like the fundraising function is taking a decent chunk of gas,
好吧，看起来 "fund" 函数消耗了相当多的 gas
the withdrawal function, take it some guests to
"withdraw" 函数同样消耗了不少 gas
we'd see the min, the max and the average.
我们可以看到最小值("Min")，最大值("Max")以及平均值("Avg")
Of course, we can see how much each one of these contracts cost to actually output.
当然还可以看到每个合约消耗量的输出
We don't really care about the MOQ aggregator of course,
我们倒是不关心 "MockV3Aggregator"
because we're never actually going to use that.
因为我们永远都不会真的用上它
Let's say we look at the average gas for these and we go hmm,
我们就来看看它们平均消耗了多少 gas
this looks like it's actually a lot more than what we originally expected.
看起来大大超出了我们最初的预期
Is there a way for us to make this a little bit cheap.
有没有办法能让这个便宜一点呢
If we go back to our funding contract, we look at our withdrawal function.
回到我们的 "FundMe" 合约，看一下我们的 "withdraw" 函数
And we noticed something,
我们注意到了某些东西
oh, there is actually a way to make this a lot cheaper.
哦，确实有个方法可以让它便宜不少
And it has to do with something called storage variables, or these global variables that we've been working with this whole time.
这与我们一直使用的 storage 变量或者说全局变量有关
Let me let me paint you a little picture here,
让我来给你们描述一下
we're gonna look at one of the first gas optimization techniques you can take to drop these down.
我们要通过一种早期的 gas 优化技巧来把成本降下来
And it has to do with an R Funmi. Contract
它要在我们的 "FundMe" 合约中进行操作
these state variables and how they're actually stored
这些状态变量以及它们实际如何存储
and how this contract actually keeps track of all this stuff,
还有这些合约如何跟踪它们，我们要把这些东西搞清楚
this section is going to be a little bit more advanced.
这个部分略微会有点进阶
So we'll have a note here saying that this is an advanced section,
所以我们这里先说明一下，这是一个进阶部分
if you want to skip over it, you can,
如果你想跳过的话，完全可以
because now
we're getting into gas optimizations here, this
information still is really good to know. So if you want to skip
it for now, and then come back later, you absolutely can. But
let's talk about what happens when we actually save or store
these global variables. Okay, these storage variables. Now,
everything I'm about to go through is in the documentation.
And there is a link to this, of course, in the GitHub repo
associated with this course, whenever we have one of these
global variables, or these variables that stay permanently,
they're stuck in something called storage, you can think of
storage as a big giant array, or a giant list of all the
variables that we actually create. So when we say we have
some contract called Son of storage, and we have a variable
called favorite number, we're basically saying we want this
favorite number variable to persist, right, we saw in a lot
of our examples, we had a favorite number variable that we
can always call to see what this contracts favorite number was,
well, the way it persists, is it gets stored in this place called
storage. A storage box is this giant list associated with this
contract where every single variable and every single value
in the storage section is slotted into a 32 byte long slot
in this storage array. So for example, the number 25 in its
bytes implementation is 000 with a ton of zeros 19. This is the
hex version of the yuan 256. This is why we do so much hex
translation, the bytes implementation of a yuan 256.
And each store saw increments just like an array starting from
zero. So for example, our next global variable or next storage
variable just gets slotted at the next slot that's available.
So bullions, for example, get transformed from their bull
version two, their hex and we modified our some bool variable
to be true and X edition of the true Boolean 0x 001. Every time
you save an additional global variable, or more correctly, one
of these storage variables, it takes up an additional storage
slot. And what about variables that are dynamic in length, or
that can change length? What about something that's dynamic?
Well, for dynamic values, like a dynamic array, or a mapping
elements inside the array or inside the mapping are actually
stored using some type of hashing function. And you can
see those specific functions in the documentation, the object
itself does take up a storage slot, but it's not going to be
the entire array. For example, my array variable here at
storage, slot two doesn't have the entire array in storage slot
two, what has actually is just the array length, the length of
the array is stored at storage slot two. But for example, if we
do my array dot push 222, we do some hashing function, which
again, you can see in the documentation what that is, and
we'll store the number 222. At that location in storage, the
hex of 222 is 0x 0000 D, so it gets stored in this crazy spot.
And this is good, this is intentional, because 32 Bytes
may not be nearly big enough to store my array if our array gets
massive. And it wouldn't make sense for to put the elements
inside the array at subsequent numbers because again, the size
of the array can change and you're never going to be sure
how many subsequence that you need. So for my array, it does
have a storage slot for the length for mappings. It does
have a storage spot as well similar to array, but it's just
blank. But it's blank intentionally so that solidity
knows, okay, there is a mapping here, and it needs a storage
slot for attaching functional work correctly. Now
interestingly, constant variables and immutable
variables do not take up spots in storage. The reason for this
is because constant variables are actually part of the
contracts byte code itself, which sounds a little bit weird.
But you can imagine what solidity does is anytime it sees
constant variables name is it just automatically swaps it out
with whatever number it actually is. So you can kind of think of
not in storage is just a pointer to 123 and it doesn't take up a
storage slot. Well when we have variables inside of a function,
those variables only exist for the duration of the function.
They don't stay inside the contract. They don't persist
they're not permanent. So variables inside these functions
like new var and other var do not get added to storage. They
get added in their own memory data structure. Which gets
deleted after the function has finished running. Now you might
be asking, Okay, well, why do we need this memory keyword,
especially when it comes to strings, we saw before that we
had to say String memory. The reason we need it for strings is
because strings are technically this dynamically sized array.
And we need to tell solidity, hey, we're going to do this on
the storage location, or we're going to do it into the memory
location where we can just wipe it. arrays and mappings can take
up a lot more space. So slowly, just wants to make sure Okay,
where are we working with this is it storage is a memory, you
have to tell me, I need to know if I need to allocate space for
it in our storage data structure. And again, everything
here you can read in the solidity documentation. Now, in
the GitHub repo associated with this course, if you go to
contracts, we've actually got an example contract section called
Fun with storage, where you can play with and look at a lot of
this stuff. And we even wrote a little script called deploy
storage fun, where it'll print out the storage location of some
of the different variables, feel free to give it a run, if you
want to try a challenge anybody to write some functions that
find the storage slots of the elements of the arrays, and the
mappings, and then find the data inside of those as well. We use
a function here called Get storage app, which allows us to
get the storage at any one of these slots. And this is to
reinforce that even if you have a function as private or
internal. Anybody can still read it. Anybody can read anything
off the blockchain. And you can test it exactly what this if you
go ahead and get clone that or copy paste the code yourself.
You can then run yarn part at deploy dash test tags, storage.
And you'll run the deploy script for that storage.
And you'll see printing out the location of storage in each
storage slot with a fun contract that we made as an example.