Now, there's a couple other tasks that are really helpful.
You'll see before I went ahead and just
deleted artifacts and deleted the cache manually. Well, to do
that yourself, you can also just run yarn Hardhead, clean. And
that'll delete the artifacts folder and clear out your cache.
We already know what compiled does. But one of the biggest
things that Hardhead is fantastic for especially is
running tests. Now we haven't run tests yet so far. However,
running tests is absolutely critical to your smart contract
development journey. And we're going to spend a lot of time in
the future writing really good tests. The reason that writing
tests are so important is because we want to make sure our
code does exactly what we want it to do, especially in the
defy, and the decentralized, smart contract world, all of our
code is going to be open source for anybody to interact with,
and potentially exploit. There's sites like req dot news, which
go through a ton of previous hacks and how they actually got
hacked and what happened in the smart contract to enable these
hacks to occur. So testing, so writing really strong tests is
always going to be our first line of defense. And we have
this sample test.js, that comes default with the basic package
of hardhat. But as you probably already know, we're going to
rename this and change it. So we're going to rename this to
test deploy dot j s. And we're going to delete everything in
here and start from scratch. We want to be able to test all of
our solidity code locally, so that we know exactly what it's
doing. And we can have a programmatic way to make sure
that our code does what we want it to do. So let's write a basic
test for our simple storage contract. So that we can be sure
that it's doing exactly what we want it to be doing. Hard Hat
testing works with the Mocha framework, which is a JavaScript
based framework for running our tests, you actually can write
tests directly in solidity, if you'd like to, there's a bit of
back and forth on whether testing with pure solidity is
better or testing with a modern programming language. The
argument goes that testing with a modern programming language,
you have more flexibility to do more stuff to interact and test
your smart contracts. But the argument for testing with us
with solidity is that we want to be as close to the code as
possible. At the time of recording, most projects do the
vast majority of their testing in a modern programming language
like JavaScript. So that's what we're going to be using here. So
to get started with our mocha tests, we do, we're going to
write a describe function. Describe is a keyword that
hardheaded mocha will recognize, and it takes two parameters, it
takes a string, which we're going to just write simple
storage for now. And then also takes a function, we could make
function, test func and then write some stuff in here, and
then pass it to our describe here. But the common convention
is going to be to do is to make it as an anonymous function,
which we can create by typing function, putting an empty
parameter here, and then some brackets like that. So our
describe function takes a name, a string, and a function.
Another way that you'll often see functions in describe is
using that anonymous function syntax. So you might see just
these parentheses, an arrow, and then some brackets, the two of
these are going to be basically the same, there are some
differences. And this second one is actually best practice, but
just know that you might see this arrow syntax in other tests
as well. We have described a sample storage and then our
function here, which is going to have all of our tests in it.
Inside each one of our describe blocks. We're gonna have
something called a before each, and a bunch of It's Our before
each function is going to tell us what to do before each of our
hits. So we're going to have a ton of it and then we're going
to have a before each. All of our IDs are going to be where we
actually write the code for running our tests. And before
each is going to be some code that tells us what to do before
each one of these hits, we can also actually have describes,
inside of describes, which again have more before each and more
before it's having these nested describes can be really helpful
for separating and modularizing our tests. But for this one,
we're just going to have a setup that looks like this. And for
this demo, we're only going to have one it. So in order to test
our smart contracts, before we actually run our tests, we're
probably going to need to deploy the smart contracts first. So
inside of our before each, we're going to pass the our before
each a function, that's going to tell our testing framework what
to do before each test. So we're going to pass it an async
function like this. And in here, we want to deploy our simple
storage contract. So to do that, we're going to need to get the
ethers framework and do exactly what we did in our deploy
script. So in here, we're at the top we're gonna say const.
Ethers, equals require art have an import ethers from hard hat.
Then in our before each function, we'll say await ethers
dot get contract factory of simple storage. And we'll assign
this to a const. Simple Storage factory. And then we'll run
away, simple storage factory dot deploy. Cool. And let's also
assign this to a variable cost simple. Now, since right now,
our simple storage and simple storage factory are scoped just
to inside the before each, we actually need to stick these
variables outside of the before each, so all of our events can
interact with them. So instead of having simple storage,
factory, and simple storage, be constant variables, we're going
to define them outside of them for each with the let keyword.
And we're gonna say let simple storage factory and we're going
to initialize it to nothing. And then we'll say led simple
storage. Now, if you have a whole bunch of let's just
initializing another way, you can write them in JavaScript,
just let simple storage factory comma, simple storage. And that
works exactly the same. And then we can get rid of this const
keyword. Because it's not a constant since we are assigning
it. And now we have simple storage, factory and simple
storage that we can use inside of our init function. Now we
have a before each section. So before each one of our tests,
we're going to deploy our simple storage contract. So we have a
brand new contract to interact with for each one of our tests.
Now, inside of the ID, this is where we're going to say what we
want this specific test to do, and then describe the code
that's going to actually do that. So we're going to say it
should start with a favorite number of zero. So this is
saying what this test should do. And then we're going to add our
async function to actually do that. So we'll say async
function. And in here, this is where we'll actually write the
code to make sure that our contract does exactly this.
We're say const. Current Value, equals await, simple storage.re
retrieve. And now in this test, we want to say okay, now check
to see that this current value is indeed zero. So how do we do
that? Well, we can say const, expected value is going to equal
zero. And what we can do is we can do either we can use either
the assert keyword, or the expect keyword, which we're
going to import both of these from a package called Chai. We
actually installed Chai automatically when we downloaded
the basic parameters when we downloaded the basic packages
for hardhats. So at the top, we're gonna say const. Expect
and assert
equals require Chai, I'm a big fan of using assert as much as
possible, because I think the syntax makes a little bit more
sense. But there will be scenarios where we need to use
expect instead. Now, assert has a ton of functions that are
built in that help us make sure this is what we expect it to be.
So I can do assert dot equal current value.to string, because
remember, this is actually going to be a big number, comma,
expected value. So I'm saying I'm asserting this retrieve to
return zero, which is going to be our expected value. Now to
actually run this, we're going to run yarn, art hat test. And
we see we get an output that looks like this should start
with favorite number of zero, and it's indeed passing. You'll
notice that if I were to change this to one, and this wasn't
correct, it would break and it would say art Pass or not
passing assertion error expected zero to equal one. It expected
zero to equal one, which is not what we want. We want zero to
equal zero. So let's run this again. Tada should start with
favorite number zero, and it's passing. Alright, fantastic. So
that's how we wrote one of our tests, let's write one more test
just to make sure that things are good. So let's say it should
update when we call store, because when we call the store
function, we want our favorite number to update. And we'll make
this an async function as well. And let's add our stuff in here.
So we'll say const. Expected Value equals seven, we're
expecting that when we call store it updates to seven. Now
we can say const. Transaction response equals await simple
storage dot store. And we can even just pass it the expected
value here. And then we'll do a weight transaction response that
weight one. Now let's get the current value. So we'll say
const. Current Value equals weight, simple storage,
retrieve. And now we're going to assert dot equal current
value.to string, comma expected value. And now we can run all
these tests by running yarn Hardhead test. And you'll see we
ran both of these tests. And now if I have 10,000 tests, and I'm
only finagling with one test, I can actually just run one test
by running yarn, art app, test, dash dash grep. And I can search
for any keywords in any of the text here. So I'm going to grep
for the store function. Because the store keyword isn't in this
tax for this, it, it's only in the text for this it. So if I do
grep store, it should only run our second test, which does
indeed, one other way we can run only specific tests is with the
only keyword. So we can type it dot only like that. And then we
can run yarn, art hat test. And it should only run, this should
update when we call store. And it does indeed, then we'll go
ahead and delete this save, run again, and it should run all
too. Fantastic. Now the other way you'll see these tests
written is with instead of assert, it'll use the expect
keyword. So you'll see something like expect current
value.to string.to dot equal expected value, the two of these
lines do exactly the same thing. And it's sort of up to you on
which one you want to use. And that's all we're going to do for
our testing. Now. This is fantastic, great job.